<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Valley of the Sun's Best Real Estate Training</title>
    <description>Nate Martinez, a top Real Estate Agent in The Valley of the Sun, shares his own internal real estate agent training for free. His Real Estate Training, Tips and Advice will help you sell more homes in less time.</description>
    <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 14:07:44 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 14:07:44 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message Volume 968</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/nates-monday-morning-message-volume-968.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-messagebrvolume-968&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;br /&gt;Volume 968&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Nate’s Monday Morning Message! The beginning of August marks the official start of our fundraising efforts for the Month of Miracles, to benefit our local Phoenix Children’s Hospital. And today I’d like to share a little bit about why we participate in this worthy cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Children’s Miracle Network Hospitals® raises funds and awareness for 170 member hospitals that provide 32 million treatments each year to kids across the U.S. and Canada. Donations stay local to fund critical treatments and healthcare services, pediatric medical equipment and charitable care. Since 1983, Children’s Miracle Network Hospitals has raised more than $5 billion, most of it $1 at a time through the charity’s Miracle Balloon icon. Its various fundraising partners and programs support the nonprofit’s mission to save and improve the lives of as many children as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year our Month of Miracles events surpassed our goal of one million pennies and raised more than $18,000 to benefit our local Phoenix Children’s Hospital – additionally throughout the year in 2018 our agents contributed $47,000 in donations! We could not do it without our generous agents, our family, friends and of course our loyal clients who continue to trust us with their real estate needs. I hope we can depend on your support again this year. You can stop by any one of our three Valley office locations, or made a donation online: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rem.ax/2yvmXTo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://rem.ax/2yvmXTo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to thank you in advance for your donations! Let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To me there is no picture so beautiful as smiling, bright-eyed, happy children; no music so sweet as their clear and ringing laughter.” - P. T. Barnum&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There are only two lasting bequests we can hope to give our children. One of these is roots, the other, wings.” - Johann Wolfgang von Goethe&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mother is the name for God in the lips and hearts of little children.” - William Makepeace Thackeray&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright © 2019 Nate Martinez. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-volume-968.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-volume-968.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Latest Numbers From the 2018 Characteristics of New Housing Report</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7zBCUvOtNEI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The 2018 Characteristics of New Housing Report is here, and I have all the key statistics to share with you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does the 2018 Characteristics of New Housing Report say about last year’s national housing market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, it said that &lt;strong&gt;840,000 single-family homes were built, and they had the following characteristics: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10% had two bedrooms or less&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;45% had three bedrooms&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;45% had four bedrooms or more &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;36% of homes had three or more bathrooms (when I first got into real estate 33 years ago, a home with more than two bathrooms outside of the luxury market was unheard of)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The median size was 2,386 square feet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Of the 617,000 single-family homes sold in 2018, the following numbers were reported:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;75% were purchased using conventional financing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6% were purchased using cash&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The median sale price was $326,400&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The average sale price was $385,000&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The median size was 2,435 square feet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=All in all, our market is fairly strong.%20https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/the-latest-numbers-from-the-2018-characteristics-of-new-housing-report.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“All in all, our market is fairly strong.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we look at the NAR statistics for all residential sales, there were 5,340,000 in total. The average days on market for those homes was 120 days. &lt;strong&gt;Here are the year-over-year statistics so far for 2019:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Home sales are up 2.7%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Supply is up 2.4%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The average days on market has risen to 130 days&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s what was recorded for the Phoenix area, in particular:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resale home sales are up 4.3%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New inventory is up 4.1%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The average sale price is $347,500&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The median price is $278,000&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The average days on market is 65 days &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, our market is fairly strong, and I hope this information helps you with your buying and selling plans moving forward in 2019. If you have any other questions about our market, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 11:58:26 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/the-latest-numbers-from-the-2018-characteristics-of-new-housing-report.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/the-latest-numbers-from-the-2018-characteristics-of-new-housing-report.html</guid>
        
        <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message Volume 967</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/181219-natemondaymessage-v1-9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-messagebrvolume-967&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;br /&gt;Volume 967&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Nate’s Monday Morning Message! Every day we have an opportunity to work on ourselves and improve who we are. One of the most important things you can do is improve your skills or knowledge. What areas of your life need improvement? I would like to challenge you to create some time this week to work on bettering yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need help, seek out the information or the people who can help you. The only things that make you different from one day to the next is the people you meet and the things you learn. Make learning and therefore growing a part of your daily life. Let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20 Tips on Time Management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a daily plan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peg a time limit to each task.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a calendar.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use an organizer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Know your deadlines.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn to say “No”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Target to be early.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time box your activities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have a clock visibly placed before you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set reminders 15 minutes before.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focus.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Block out distractions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Track your time spent.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t fuss about unimportant details&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prioritize.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delegate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Batch similar tasks together.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eliminate your time wasters.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cut off when you need to.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leave buffer time in-between.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do not wait; the time will never be ‘just right.’ Start where you stand, and work with whatever tools you may have at your command, and better tools will be found as you go along.” - George Herbert&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Your time is limited, so don’t waste it living someone else’s life. Don’t be trapped by dogma - which is living with the results of other people’s thinking. Don’t let the noise of others’ opinions drown out your own inner voice. And most important, have the courage to follow your heart and intuition.” - Steve Jobs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do the one thing you think you cannot do. Fail at it. Try again. Do better the second time. The only people who never tumble are those who never mount the high wire. This is your moment. Own it.” - Oprah Winfrey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-volume-967.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-volume-967.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to RE/MAX Professionals Jody Snyder</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Please help us welcome Jody to the RE/MAX Professionals’ family!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/jody-snyder.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;626&quot; height=&quot;1100&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/welcome-to-remax-professionals-jody-snyder.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/welcome-to-remax-professionals-jody-snyder.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message Volume 966</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/181219-natemondaymessage-v1-9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-messagebrvolume-966&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;br /&gt;Volume 966&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Nate’s Monday Morning Message! Today I would like to focus on failure, or better yet the courage it takes to keep going in the face of adversity. We have all faced a difficult time or two in our lives, but what made us get back up and continue moving forward? What pushed us to keep trying? I want to remind you about a few important people in history who didn’t give up, even when the odds were stacked again them…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thomas Edison&lt;/strong&gt;: was considered one of the most prolific inventors in history, was told as a boy he was too stupid to learn anything. He tried more than 9,000 experiments before he was successful in creating the first light bulb. There are now 1,093 U.S. patents in his name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michael Jordon&lt;/strong&gt;: was known today as one of the greatest basketball players of all times, was removed from his high school basketball team because of his “lack of skill.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steven Spielberg&lt;/strong&gt;: American film director who has won multiple Academy Awards and considered one of the most successful filmmakers ever, dropped out of junior high school. He later came back and was placed in a learning-disabled class. He dropped out of school for good just one month later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just a few of the countless stories of highly successful people who have failed or who have been told they couldn’t do it, and yet surprised the world because they had a dream. Don’t give up on your dreams, whatever they are…don’t give up! Let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Character cannot be developed in ease and quiet. Only through experience of trial and suffering can the soul be strengthened, ambition inspired, and success achieved.” - Helen Keller&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Stand up to your obstacles and do something about them. You will find that they haven’t half the strength you think they have.” – Norman Vincente Peale&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Every great dream begins with a dreamer. Always remember, you have within you the strength, the patience, and the passion to reach for the stars to change the world.” - Harriet Tubman&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Be faithful in small things because it is in them that your strength lies.” - Mother Teresa&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-volume-966.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-volume-966.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message July 15, 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/181219-natemondaymessage-v1-9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-message&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Nate’s Monday Morning Message! We all face similar challenges in our lives, and we all handle those challenges differently. There a few things that we all could do better to make the challenges that will come a little easier to handle. First, keep in mind that there will always be challenges and disruptions that throw us off course; that is life and we all go through it. Second, your reaction to what happens to you is 100 percent within your control. You may not control what happens, but you control what you do about it. Third, pointing fingers or placing blame on others never solves the problem at hand. The goal is to understand what happened why and what you learned from it. Then move on. Fourth, love more and argue less. Spend your time loving rather than arguing with many. Fifth, realize your time here is limited and the clock is ticking. Don’t waste time because once it’s gone, you can’t get it back. Let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the Journey That’s Important by John McLeod&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life, sometimes so wearying&lt;br /&gt;Is worth its weight in gold&lt;br /&gt;The experience of traveling&lt;br /&gt;Lends a wisdom that is old&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond our ‘living memory’&lt;br /&gt;A softly spoken prayer:”&lt;br /&gt;It’s the journey that’s important,&lt;br /&gt;Not the getting there!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ins and outs and ups and downs&lt;br /&gt;Life’s road meanders aimlessly?&lt;br /&gt;Or so it seems, but somehow&lt;br /&gt;Leads us where we need to be,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And being simply human&lt;br /&gt;We oft question and compare…&lt;br /&gt;“Is the journey so important&lt;br /&gt;Or the getting there?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And thus it’s always been&lt;br /&gt;That question pondered down the ages&lt;br /&gt;By simple people with simple ways&lt;br /&gt;To wise and ancient sages…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How sweet then, quietly knowing&lt;br /&gt;Reaching destination fair:&lt;br /&gt;“It’s the journey that’s important,&lt;br /&gt;Not the getting there!“ &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I will love the light for it shows me the way, yet I will endure the darkness because it shows me the stars.” - Og Mandino&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If a man does not keep pace with his companions, perhaps it is because he hears a different drummer. Let him step to the music which he hears, however measured or far away.” - Henry David Thoreau&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I can’t change the direction of the wind, but I can adjust my sails to always reach my destination.” - Jimmy Dean&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PS…You are invited to my &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyurl.com/yyfdw6sa&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Business Planning Workshop&lt;/a&gt; - including happy hour! We’re doing it again! Come grab some FREE tacos, margaritas and advice on how to turn your real estate business into a 7-figure success. This event will be held at Urban Margarita on 67th Ave and the 101 Loop starting at 3:30pm. I hope to see you there!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-july-15-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-july-15-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You Are Invited! Happy Hour Included!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You Are Invited - Happy Hour Included!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please join us next Thursday for a 3 hour business planning workshop with happy hour included! More details below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/190711-businessplanningworkshop-v1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;626&quot; height=&quot;1100&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Space is limited - to secure your seat today, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyurl.com/yyfdw6sa&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;. We look forward to seeing you on July 18th! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/you-are-invited-happy-hour-included.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/you-are-invited-happy-hour-included.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Top 10 Sales Associates &amp; Team for June 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to our top ten agents and teams for the month of June - keep up the hard work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/190705-top10-jun19-ig-assoc-teams-v1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/top-10-sales-associates-team-for-june-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/top-10-sales-associates-team-for-june-2019.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message July 8, 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/181219-natemondaymessage-v1-9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-message&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Nate’s Monday Morning Message! I hope that each of you reading this are enjoying the summer so far and prepared for the monsoon season that is quickly approaching! This time of year, in the Valley of the Sun provides much needed water for the desert and the monsoons give us some pretty amazing sunsets. I hope that you will take some time during the evenings this summer to enjoy the awe-inspiring clouds and vivid colors that fill our sky; it truly is magnificent and a perfect reminder of the simple blessings that surround us every day. We often stare at a door that has closed for too long and in the process miss the one that has opened. Don’t take for granted the simple beauties in life, as they pave the way to finding a deeper meaning to happiness. Take time to appreciate all the good in your life and make each moment count! Let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Fish Stranded in a Drying Puddle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once there was a fellow walking along a road. Suddenly he heard a faint cry. He looked around but saw nothing. Thinking he heard nothing, he continued to walk. Again he heard the faint cry. This time the call was nearby. He searched high and low, and found the sound was coming out of a little fish lying in a drying pond. His mouth gurgling. That person looked at the fish strangely and asked,”Was that you who was just calling me? Was it you needing my help?”The small fish looking pleading at the man gasping and breathless said, “Please save me quickly, I am dying, I need water. I am not a normal fish, rather I am the eastern sea dragon’s official. Please give me a little water.” That person hearing this hurriedly nodded his head and said, “I understand, I will immediately go to the south and let the southern king redirect a river to here so that you can swim and return to the eastern sea.” The fish angrily cried out, “Can a fish live out of water? I am only in need of a little water. Your idea is pointless. I think that the next time you see me will be in a shop that sells dried fish. “The story tells us to reconsider solutions that we usually propose to solve real life problems. Sometimes we take our time too much to find the most ideal solution, while what the problem really needs is time critical solution.We must always aware that many times in our lives we don’t need the best solution but some quick fixes for the current situation to prevent it of becoming worse. Only until then, we have much more time to think and find the ideal solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://chinese-tales.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;http://chinese-tales.blogspot.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Gratitude unlocks the fullness of life. It turns what we have into enough, and more. It turns denial into acceptance, chaos to order, confusion to clarity. It can turn a meal into a feast, a house into a home, a stranger into a friend.” - Melody Beattie&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To succeed in life, you need three things: a wishbone, a backbone and a funny bone.” - Reba McEntire&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Find joy in everything you choose to do. Every job, relationship, home… it’s your responsibility to love it, or change it.” - Chuck Palahniuk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-july-8-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-july-8-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to RE/MAX Professionals Austin Jones</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Please help us welcome Austin to the RE/MAX Professionals’ family!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/austin-jones-welcome.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;626&quot; height=&quot;1050&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/welcome-to-remax-professionals-austin-jones.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/welcome-to-remax-professionals-austin-jones.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
