<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Valley of the Sun's Best Real Estate Training</title>
    <description>Nate Martinez, a top Real Estate Agent in The Valley of the Sun, shares his own internal real estate agent training for free. His Real Estate Training, Tips and Advice will help you sell more homes in less time.</description>
    <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 11:52:16 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 11:52:16 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Realtors Must Know About Zillow’s Instant Offer Program</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gvKlD23K2BM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;What does Zillow&amp;rsquo;s new Instant Offer program mean for Realtors? Today I will discuss how this change may impact you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zillow has undergone some changes recently, so today I would like to talk about what is new with the site. If you visit Zillow’s website right now, you’ll probably notice that Realtors have been removed from every listing on the site. Now, instead of the name of an agent, the site is advertising their new Instant Offer program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This program shows what Zillow will pay a homeowner for their property. Before, Zillow gave homeowners the opportunity to reach out to agents directly. Now, they are moving past that. This isn’t to say Zillow may not sell leads back to Realtors, but for now, &lt;strong&gt;the Instant Offer program has taken the place of agents on the site.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how is this affecting today’s Realtors? For one thing, it means that people who advertise heavily through Zillow, myself included, will no longer have the option to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it is actually investors who will be most affected by this change. This is because Zillow will be getting the first crack at properties investors may have previously been the first to capture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also believe that this change will place Zillow in more direct competition with other platforms like Opendoor and OfferPad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Zillow will be getting the first crack at properties investors may have previously been the first to capture.%20https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/what-realtors-must-know-about-zillows-instant-offer-program.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Zillow will be getting the first crack at properties investors may have previously been the first to capture.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important for Realtors to be aware of this change and how it may affect them. Staying informed is a critical aspect of any agent’s career. &lt;strong&gt;If you are concerned about this change, my recommendation is to focus on your past client database.&lt;/strong&gt; Build deeper connections with people you have already formed relationships with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 08:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/what-realtors-must-know-about-zillows-instant-offer-program.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/what-realtors-must-know-about-zillows-instant-offer-program.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How’s the Phoenix Market Doing Right Now?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/B0KJGngf8P4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phoenix real estate is doing extremely well right now. Here’s what the latest numbers are telling us.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest numbers are in and I’m excited to share them with you today. Let’s get right to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In March of this year, 9,402 homes closed escrow. In January, we only had 6,000 closed sales, which is still a strong number. &lt;strong&gt;This is one of the strongest first quarters we’ve seen in a while.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The market is up 36%, but inventory has dropped almost 12% at the same time. There are currently 21,703 homes active on the MLS today. The average list price is up 8.8% to $381,000 and the average sale price is up 9.5% to $316,400.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the most fascinating things I found was when looking at this year’s numbers compared to the numbers from the past 18 years.&lt;/strong&gt; Back in 2001, the average price in the valley was $175,900. In 2007, the market roared to a peak of $345,900 before crashing and bottoming out in 2009 at $159,080. We’ve made a significant rebound since. Today, the average price is $316,365.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People who bought at the peak are close to being back where they were. People who bought 17 years ago have more than doubled their money, as have the people who bought at the bottom of the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=People who bought at the peak are seeing values rise back to where they were before.%20https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/hows-the-phoenix-market-doing-right-now.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“People who bought at the peak are seeing values rise back to where they were before.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an added note, I’ve seen more cranes in the sky in the Phoenix than I have in the last 10 years. &lt;strong&gt;High-rises, hotels, and more are being built all around the Valley, which is great news for our economy and ultimately, our market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope your market is doing well. If you have any questions for me at all about the latest numbers or about the business in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/hows-the-phoenix-market-doing-right-now.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/hows-the-phoenix-market-doing-right-now.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Phoenix Real Estate Market Is Hot</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EdB-SAGINJo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s going on in the Phoenix real estate market? Here&amp;rsquo;s what you need to know.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about the hot, robust real estate market in Phoenix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month alone, almost &lt;strong&gt;17% of all homes that closed did so above list price.&lt;/strong&gt; When it comes to buyers making offers on houses, you’ve got to make sure that you’re writing your offers very aggressively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only 3% of the upper-end homes actually got any type of seller concessions. When you get below $250,000, that’s still a pretty high percentage of sellers that will offer concessions. In that same price point, homes are selling way above list price as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve experienced multiple offers on almost every home listed above $250,000. In preparing an offer, you want to &lt;strong&gt;come in with a higher earnest money deposit, short inspection time, few contingencies, and don’t ask for concessions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=In this market, you need to come forward with your highest and best offer.%20https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/the-phoenix-real-estate-market-is-hot.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“In this market, you need to come forward with your highest and best offer.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re representing the seller in today’s market, make sure that you’re studying the different buyers and talking to their lenders so that you can select the absolute best buyer possible. Again, in a hot market like today’s, when houses are selling above list price, you need to come forward with your highest and best offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Houses aren’t staying on the market very long. In fact, we have less than three months of inventory available, which is &lt;strong&gt;almost 18% lower than this time last year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please feel free to reach out to me. If there is a topic you’d like me to discuss in a future video, send them my way; if I select yours, I’ll send you a $50 gift card to a restaurant of your choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 10:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/the-phoenix-real-estate-market-is-hot.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/the-phoenix-real-estate-market-is-hot.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Level Up Your Real Estate Business</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ukd-NMGTiJE?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m joined by Sarah Michelle Bliss, who has been by my side for the last 20 years of my real estate career. She’s a great success coach, author, and real estate trainer. &lt;strong&gt;We’ve put together a great class on Thursday, July 26th from 3:00 p.m. to 6:00 p.m. that we want to tell you about.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joinrmxprofessionals.com/Registration&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“10 Ways to Level Up Your Real Estate Business”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;we will be walking you through a ton of information to help you become more proficient and get the most out of the hours that you are working.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The class is around three hours long, but it’s filled with content that will help you be more present at work and have more time off to enjoy life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We can’t wait for you to join us.%20https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-to-level-up-your-real-estate-business.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We can’t wait for you to join us.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As a bonus for being there, we’re also going to be giving you a copy of our 2018 business plan.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s a complete business plan that takes you all the way through the steps it takes to build a successful real estate company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two of the buzzwords we use in our complete agent development are proactive and intentional. That’s where most agents struggle. They aren’t being consistent and proactive and completing the necessary activities to generate the results you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Space is limited so make sure you get signed up soon. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joinrmxprofessionals.com/Registration&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can register here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the class or the real estate business in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 15:19:14 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-to-level-up-your-real-estate-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-to-level-up-your-real-estate-business.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Beat the Competition in This Scorching Hot Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2OiY4IqcanI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I have some advice on how you can handle multiple offer situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Phoenix real estate market is absolutely on fire, and December 2017 was one of the busiest months of my career. Now that we’re in January of 2018, &lt;strong&gt;we’re getting multiple offers on just about every property&lt;/strong&gt; that we place on the market. This affects the buyers possibly even more than the sellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=An escalation clause is a technique that may be necessary to get the house you want in this hot market.%20https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-can-you-beat-the-competition-in-this-scorching-hot-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“An escalation clause is a technique that may be necessary to get the house you want in this hot market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a buyer or representing a buyer in today’s marketplace, an &lt;strong&gt;escalation clause&lt;/strong&gt; will help you beat out the current highest offer by offering a certain amount more. Essentially, it is &lt;strong&gt;a clause in the contract that says that the buyer is willing to pay X amount more than the highest offer received by the seller.  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For example, let’s say you’re making an offer on a house priced at $400,000. You can put in an escalation clause that says you’ll outbid any other buyer by, say, $1,000. This might be a technique that is necessary to get the house that you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inventory is still very low in the valley, but the demand is very high, so hopefully an escalation clause will help give you the edge you need to get the home of your dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about escalation clauses or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home in our market, give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 14:36:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-can-you-beat-the-competition-in-this-scorching-hot-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-can-you-beat-the-competition-in-this-scorching-hot-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Valuable Presentation on Building Wealth in Your Life</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-X0Qdkvx7Kw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may remember, I did a video a couple of months ago on the book “Wealth Can’t Wait” by David Osborn and Paul Morris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around that same time, &lt;strong&gt;I had the pleasure of flying David in to give an hour-long talk on his book and how to build wealth.&lt;/strong&gt; The information he shared was truly valuable and is sure to help you build wealth in your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=In his talk, David provides a lot of insight into how to build wealth.%20https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/a-valuable-presentation-on-building-wealth-in-your-life.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“In his talk, David provides a lot of insight into how to build wealth.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next time you have an hour of free time, I’d like you to sit down and watch David’s presentation. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SjvbStIUzx0&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can find the video from that seminar here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 09:57:55 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/a-valuable-presentation-on-building-wealth-in-your-life.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/a-valuable-presentation-on-building-wealth-in-your-life.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What You Need to Know About Radon Gas</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5k7lwWDdV8M?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last couple of months, I’ve heard the word “radon” too many times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s interesting because whenever I talk to other real estate professionals, I ask them how many of the homes they’ve dealt with have had radon in them, and they always say, “None.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some buyers from the East Coast have some knowledge about radon, as do a few homeowners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Radon came to my attention when I was representing a buyer during a transaction on a house in Scottsdale. This house had fallen out of escrow because the radon test came back two points higher than the national standard of 4%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If the house has a basement or underground air units, order a radon test.%20https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-radon-gas.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If the house has a basement or underground air units, order a radon test.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Radon is an odorless, poisonous gas that can cause lung cancer over long periods of exposure. As I’ve learned more about radon, I’ve found that &lt;strong&gt;the reason most people don’t find it in our area is that hardly anyone looks for it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was always taught that radon tests are necessary in mountainous regions because radon comes from granite in the ground. However, this Scottsdale house was on a flat piece of dirt and ended up having a high radon content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made the offer contingent on the seller getting radon levels down. At first, the seller paid $5,000 to fix the problem. The radon levels did not go down. The seller then spent another $5,000. After all the work they did and money they spent, the radon levels actually went higher, which was no good, and the buyer walked away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just want to make sure that people are aware that radon is out there. If you are buying a home, ask for a radon test. They only cost $300 to $350. &lt;strong&gt;If the house has a basement or underground air units, then you definitely need to order a radon test.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about radon or buying a home, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 07:27:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-radon-gas.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-radon-gas.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>14 Activities Every Real Estate Agent Should Master: Part Two</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tuEfQAN78HQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 14 vital activities that every real estate agent should do. Last time, we focused on the seven things you need to do to help sellers. Today, we’ll focus on what you need to do to master representing buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Lead generation.&lt;/strong&gt; Again, you need to be constantly generating new leads through open houses, Zillow, yard signs, and referrals from past clients, family, and friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Have a conversion process.&lt;/strong&gt; What do you do to convert this person from a name and number into a buyer and broker contract?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Paperwork.&lt;/strong&gt; Get that agreement signed and take care of agency disclosures and buyer advisories while you are in the beginning stages of working with the buyer.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Finding and showing the perfect home.&lt;/strong&gt; This is the fun part. You get to guide the buyer through their home search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You need to be able to write an offer that will get accepted.%20https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/14-activities-every-real-estate-agent-should-master-part-two.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You need to be able to write an offer that will get accepted.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Writing and negotiating the best purchase agreement.&lt;/strong&gt; You need to be proficient in making sure that your offers protect the buyer’s best interests. You also need to make sure that the buyer understands all of the inspections and finance contingencies. The bottom line is that you need to be able to write an offer that will be accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Closing.&lt;/strong&gt; Again, it’s important to make sure that the closing process goes smoothly. Be there with your buyer at the closing table in case they have any questions or concerns. You are there to be their advocate. Let them know that you care by showing up to closing. Then, when everything has been done, you can ask if there is anyone they can refer you to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Post-closing activities.&lt;/strong&gt; In my 31 years of real estate, I’ve noticed that this step gets skipped the most. What are you doing to develop a deep relationship with this client after you close escrow? After all, they may be a client who will bring you business for the rest of your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to have detailed plans in place to make sure that you are relevant in their mind. Call them up every now and then, invite them to sporting events, or host annual client appreciation events. You can also check to see how they like the house. If they have any challenges or need a repairman, you can put them in touch with one. You will position yourself as a great real estate resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope these 14 activities will help you grow your business. If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 07:45:55 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/14-activities-every-real-estate-agent-should-master-part-two.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/14-activities-every-real-estate-agent-should-master-part-two.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Skip These 14 Activities Every Real Estate Agent Should Master</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QRtdlZqHK4A?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 14 vital activities that each Realtor should do. I’ll go over the first seven for you today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Lead generation.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s so important to constantly generate leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Converting leads.&lt;/strong&gt; Turn those leads into appointments and then into contracts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Administrative work.&lt;/strong&gt; Most Realtors don’t like paperwork, which is why we have transaction coordinators to help us out. Administrative paperwork is a vital activity that we must do ourselves or delegate to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Have good presentation.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s important to present at listing appointments, in front of buyers, and in the negotiation of contracts. Whether you are representing the buyer or seller, you have to be able to negotiate on their behalf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Marketing.&lt;/strong&gt; You need to have a strategic marketing plan in place. Whether you are trying to connect with people through farming, Zillow, or wherever it may be that you are spending money to generate leads, marketing is a highly important function of being a Realtor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There are many components that you need to master, but the closing component is extremely important.%20https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/dont-skip-these-14-activities-every-real-estate-agent-should-master.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There are many components that you need to master, but the closing component is extremely important.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Closing.&lt;/strong&gt; All of your hard work goes into the closing day. You want to make sure that you are able to get the closing done right. There are many components that you need to master, but the closing component is extremely important. Make sure you go to closings so that you can represent your client. By going to the closing, you will also be present in your client’s mindset and they will be more likely to send your information to their friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Post-closing activities.&lt;/strong&gt; What do you do once the house is closed? Do you just cash the check and never talk to those people again? Or do you want these people to become part of the fabric of your life? It’s very important to have an ongoing follow-up plan for everyone you represent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, if you had a good transaction, then they know, like, and trust you. They also know what to expect by working with you. Now it’s up to you to stay in constant contact with them. If they need help with the house, finding contractors, or dealing with home warranty issues, you should be their advocate. Invite them to dinner, call on them cordially after closing, or invite them to client events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for the next seven tasks that every real estate agent should do. In the meantime, if you have any questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 06:08:55 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/dont-skip-these-14-activities-every-real-estate-agent-should-master.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/dont-skip-these-14-activities-every-real-estate-agent-should-master.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Want to Teach You How to Build Your Wealth</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5ebEUOMEZbo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you a real estate agent who wants to build wealth? I want to let you know that you’re invited to our next training session, where you’ll learn how to do exactly that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joinrmxprofessionals.com/Join-Today&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Join RE/MAX Professionals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you a real estate agent who wants to build wealth? I want to let you know that you’re invited to our next training session, where you’ll learn how to do exactly that. You’ll learn how to embrace the habits and mindsets of the wealthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You’ll also learn the seven pillars of wealth-building from none other than the guy who wrote the book—literally.&lt;/strong&gt; We’re flying in “Wealth Can’t Wait” author David Osborn. We’re going to give away all of our strategies and systems so you can build a profitable business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the event is over, you’ll leave with not only the knowledge to build wealth, but also a copy of David’s book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=WE’RE GIVING AWAY ALL OF OUR STRATEGIES AND SYSTEMS SO YOU CAN BUILD A PROFITABLE BUSINESS.%20https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/we-want-to-teach-you-how-to-build-your.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“WE’RE GIVING AWAY ALL OF OUR STRATEGIES AND SYSTEMS SO YOU CAN BUILD A PROFITABLE BUSINESS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, space is limited so only the first 200 in attendance will receive this free copy. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joinrmxprofessionals.com/Registration&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;To RSVP for this free event, click here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is one catch after you register: you have to show up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We hope to see you there on Thursday, November 2nd starting at 8:30 a.m.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 12:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/we-want-to-teach-you-how-to-build-your.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/we-want-to-teach-you-how-to-build-your.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate Coaching</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
