<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Valley of the Sun's Best Real Estate Training</title>
    <description>Nate Martinez, a top Real Estate Agent in The Valley of the Sun, shares his own internal real estate agent training for free. His Real Estate Training, Tips and Advice will help you sell more homes in less time.</description>
    <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 15:21:45 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 15:21:45 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message July 15, 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/181219-natemondaymessage-v1-9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-message&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Nate’s Monday Morning Message! We all face similar challenges in our lives, and we all handle those challenges differently. There a few things that we all could do better to make the challenges that will come a little easier to handle. First, keep in mind that there will always be challenges and disruptions that throw us off course; that is life and we all go through it. Second, your reaction to what happens to you is 100 percent within your control. You may not control what happens, but you control what you do about it. Third, pointing fingers or placing blame on others never solves the problem at hand. The goal is to understand what happened why and what you learned from it. Then move on. Fourth, love more and argue less. Spend your time loving rather than arguing with many. Fifth, realize your time here is limited and the clock is ticking. Don’t waste time because once it’s gone, you can’t get it back. Let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the Journey That’s Important by John McLeod&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life, sometimes so wearying&lt;br /&gt;Is worth its weight in gold&lt;br /&gt;The experience of traveling&lt;br /&gt;Lends a wisdom that is old&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond our ‘living memory’&lt;br /&gt;A softly spoken prayer:”&lt;br /&gt;It’s the journey that’s important,&lt;br /&gt;Not the getting there!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ins and outs and ups and downs&lt;br /&gt;Life’s road meanders aimlessly?&lt;br /&gt;Or so it seems, but somehow&lt;br /&gt;Leads us where we need to be,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And being simply human&lt;br /&gt;We oft question and compare…&lt;br /&gt;“Is the journey so important&lt;br /&gt;Or the getting there?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And thus it’s always been&lt;br /&gt;That question pondered down the ages&lt;br /&gt;By simple people with simple ways&lt;br /&gt;To wise and ancient sages…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How sweet then, quietly knowing&lt;br /&gt;Reaching destination fair:&lt;br /&gt;“It’s the journey that’s important,&lt;br /&gt;Not the getting there!“ &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I will love the light for it shows me the way, yet I will endure the darkness because it shows me the stars.” - Og Mandino&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If a man does not keep pace with his companions, perhaps it is because he hears a different drummer. Let him step to the music which he hears, however measured or far away.” - Henry David Thoreau&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I can’t change the direction of the wind, but I can adjust my sails to always reach my destination.” - Jimmy Dean&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PS…You are invited to my &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyurl.com/yyfdw6sa&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Business Planning Workshop&lt;/a&gt; - including happy hour! We’re doing it again! Come grab some FREE tacos, margaritas and advice on how to turn your real estate business into a 7-figure success. This event will be held at Urban Margarita on 67th Ave and the 101 Loop starting at 3:30pm. I hope to see you there!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-july-15-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-july-15-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You Are Invited! Happy Hour Included!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You Are Invited - Happy Hour Included!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please join us next Thursday for a 3 hour business planning workshop with happy hour included! More details below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/190711-businessplanningworkshop-v1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;626&quot; height=&quot;1100&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Space is limited - to secure your seat today, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyurl.com/yyfdw6sa&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;. We look forward to seeing you on July 18th! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/you-are-invited-happy-hour-included.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/you-are-invited-happy-hour-included.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Top 10 Sales Associates &amp; Team for June 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to our top ten agents and teams for the month of June - keep up the hard work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/190705-top10-jun19-ig-assoc-teams-v1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/top-10-sales-associates-team-for-june-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/top-10-sales-associates-team-for-june-2019.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message July 8, 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/181219-natemondaymessage-v1-9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-message&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Nate’s Monday Morning Message! I hope that each of you reading this are enjoying the summer so far and prepared for the monsoon season that is quickly approaching! This time of year, in the Valley of the Sun provides much needed water for the desert and the monsoons give us some pretty amazing sunsets. I hope that you will take some time during the evenings this summer to enjoy the awe-inspiring clouds and vivid colors that fill our sky; it truly is magnificent and a perfect reminder of the simple blessings that surround us every day. We often stare at a door that has closed for too long and in the process miss the one that has opened. Don’t take for granted the simple beauties in life, as they pave the way to finding a deeper meaning to happiness. Take time to appreciate all the good in your life and make each moment count! Let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Fish Stranded in a Drying Puddle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once there was a fellow walking along a road. Suddenly he heard a faint cry. He looked around but saw nothing. Thinking he heard nothing, he continued to walk. Again he heard the faint cry. This time the call was nearby. He searched high and low, and found the sound was coming out of a little fish lying in a drying pond. His mouth gurgling. That person looked at the fish strangely and asked,”Was that you who was just calling me? Was it you needing my help?”The small fish looking pleading at the man gasping and breathless said, “Please save me quickly, I am dying, I need water. I am not a normal fish, rather I am the eastern sea dragon’s official. Please give me a little water.” That person hearing this hurriedly nodded his head and said, “I understand, I will immediately go to the south and let the southern king redirect a river to here so that you can swim and return to the eastern sea.” The fish angrily cried out, “Can a fish live out of water? I am only in need of a little water. Your idea is pointless. I think that the next time you see me will be in a shop that sells dried fish. “The story tells us to reconsider solutions that we usually propose to solve real life problems. Sometimes we take our time too much to find the most ideal solution, while what the problem really needs is time critical solution.We must always aware that many times in our lives we don’t need the best solution but some quick fixes for the current situation to prevent it of becoming worse. Only until then, we have much more time to think and find the ideal solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://chinese-tales.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;http://chinese-tales.blogspot.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Gratitude unlocks the fullness of life. It turns what we have into enough, and more. It turns denial into acceptance, chaos to order, confusion to clarity. It can turn a meal into a feast, a house into a home, a stranger into a friend.” - Melody Beattie&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To succeed in life, you need three things: a wishbone, a backbone and a funny bone.” - Reba McEntire&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Find joy in everything you choose to do. Every job, relationship, home… it’s your responsibility to love it, or change it.” - Chuck Palahniuk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-july-8-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-july-8-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to RE/MAX Professionals Austin Jones</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Please help us welcome Austin to the RE/MAX Professionals’ family!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/austin-jones-welcome.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;626&quot; height=&quot;1050&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/welcome-to-remax-professionals-austin-jones.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/welcome-to-remax-professionals-austin-jones.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message July 1, 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/nates-monday-morning-message---happy-4th-of-july-2019.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;980&quot; height=&quot;1470&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-message&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Nate’s Monday Morning Message! In honor of the upcoming Fourth of July holiday, I want to take the opportunity to say thank you to the countless men and women who have dedicated their lives so we can celebrate the freedoms we enjoy and celebrate this week. I hope you will take a moment to express your gratitude for what it means to be an American. From all of us on my team, we want to wish each of you a very happy, healthy and safe Fourth of July holiday! Let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“One flag, one land, one heart, one hand, one nation evermore!” - Oliver Wendell Holmes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“America was not built on fear. America was built on courage, on imagination, and an unbeatable determination to do the job at hand.” – Harry S. Truman&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We will stand by the right, we will stand by the true, we will live, we will die for the red, white, and blue.” - Unknown&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-july-1-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-july-1-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Not to Lose Clients to iBuyers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ftkTDUKTwUc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Telling the right stories can help you secure more clients, and today I’ll explain how.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently read an article that explained how &lt;strong&gt;sellers lost $14 billion in equity last year because of the increasing number of iBuyers entering our market.&lt;/strong&gt; Selling to these companies is usually advertised as a convenient deal, but is actually a very ineffective move for today’s sellers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what can you do to dissuade sellers from going that route? One of the simplest ways is by doing what you do best: offering expert real estate advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You can use personal success stories of the clients you’ve helped to secure future clients.%20https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-not-to-lose-clients-to-ibuyers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You can use personal success stories of the clients you’ve helped to secure future clients.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Given that 71% of buyers are afraid to buy a home that needs work, some of the best advice you can offer sellers is to make strategic repairs.&lt;/strong&gt; The right repairs and upgrades will not only bring a high return, but they’ll also help sellers to close quickly and for top dollar. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve guided a seller to closing using this (or any other tips), you can use the success stories that come out of these experiences to help you secure future clients who might have otherwise considered selling to an iBuyer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 12:43:22 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-not-to-lose-clients-to-ibuyers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-not-to-lose-clients-to-ibuyers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Prospects</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message June 24, 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/181219-natemondaymessage-v1-9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-message&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to another edition of Nate’s Monday Morning Message! As we are constantly working on improving ourselves and our situations, we try to make things better each day, in big and small ways. The challenge becomes the consistency of doing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many things in life they get harder to do over time and we need to dig deeper and deeper to find the strength and determination to succeed. What it comes down to is passion. Do you have the passion to achieve the goal that you are working towards? Do you have the passion to put up with the bad with the hope that the good will be so very worth it? You must find your passion in everything you do. It is a mindset and it can be created over and over and over if you desire the end result bad enough. Passion is the gas that runs your engine. Find yours and put it to work! Let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;L- Love: your passion is something you love to do.&lt;br /&gt;I- Interest: your passion is something that interests you.&lt;br /&gt;F- Fulfilling: your passion gives you a sense of fulfillment.&lt;br /&gt;E- Empowering: your passion usually empowers and energizes you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P- Personal: your passion has personal significance to you and you alone.&lt;br /&gt;A- Abilities: your passion capitalizes on your assets, attributes and abilities.&lt;br /&gt;S- Service: your passion will usually provide a service or fulfill a need.&lt;br /&gt;S- Spiritual: your passion and its pursuit represent an area of spiritual growth.&lt;br /&gt;I- Inspiring: your passion is inspiring to you and therefore will inspire others too.&lt;br /&gt;O- Obvious: your passion, once found, is usually something obvious to you.&lt;br /&gt;N- Natural: your passion is often unstudied and comes naturally to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Every great dream begins with a dreamer. Always remember, you have within you the strength, the patience, and the passion to reach for the stars to change the world.” - Harriet Tubman&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Follow your passion, be prepared to work hard and sacrifice, and, above all, don’t let anyone limit your dreams.” - Donovan Bailey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is no passion to be found playing small - in settling for a life that is less than the one you are capable of living.”- Nelson Mandela&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-june-24-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-june-24-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message June 17, 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/181219-natemondaymessage-v1-9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-message&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Nate’s Monday Morning Message! This morning, I wanted to remind all of you of the 5 P’s of Life: Prior - Planning - Prevents - Poor - Performance. To be truly successful in all we do both personally and professionally, planning is a must! We must plan for what we need to do and also plan for the different roadblocks that may and most likely will get in our way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When these roadblocks pop-up we will be prepared and able to act quickly. Once we have our plans, we can go after our goals with the passion, determination, and focus to be successful. Spending a small amount of time in the beginning can save you a bunch of time in the end. Remember that you must also take action! Taking action is honestly the single biggest differentiator to success. Follow the 5 P’s and take action EVERYDAY! Let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Principles of Life:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winning isn’t everything but wanting to win is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You would achieve more, if you don’t mind who gets the credit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When everything else is lost, the future still remains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t fight too much or the enemy will know your art of war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only job you start at the top is when you dig a grave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t stand for something, you’ll fall for everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do little things well, you’ll do big ones better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only thing that comes to you without effort is old age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You won’t get a second chance to make a first impression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only those who do nothing do not make mistakes.If you are not failing, you’re not taking enough risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t try to get rid of your bad temper by losing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If at first you don’t succeed, skydiving is not for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who don’t make mistakes usually don’t make anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two kinds of failures: Those who think and never do, and those who do and never think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pick battles big enough to matter, small enough to win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All progress has resulted from unpopular decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change your thoughts and you change your world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding proves intelligence, not the speed of the learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two kinds of fools in this world: Those who give advice and those who don’t take it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Management is doing things right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leadership is doing the right things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friendship founded on business is always better than business founded on friendship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When it is obvious that the goals cannot be reached, don’t adjust the goals, adjust the action steps.” – Confucius&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Successful people maintain a positive focus in life no matter what is going on around them. They stay focused on their past successes rather than their past failures, and on the next action steps they need to take to get them closer to the fulfillment of their goals rather than all the other distractions that life presents to them.” - Jack Canfield&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Vision without action is merely a dream. Action without vision just passes the time. Vision with action can change the world.” - Joel A. Barker&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-june-17-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-june-17-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message June 10, 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/181219-natemondaymessage-v1-9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-message&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Nate’s Monday Morning Message! Over time we accumulate things that are a result of our hard work and determination. However, let us keep in mind that the tangible possessions around us are not the reason for living, but rather the result of a life lived properly. The people and the experiences we have are so much more valuable than any item we may acquire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let this week’s message be a reminder to be present in all that you do. Slow down and concentrate on the conversations you are having with your children, spouse, or other loved ones. Slow down and enjoy the thoughts that you may have about experiences of the past. Slow down and think about all the great people and opportunities that are surrounding you each day. Commit to living a life you truly enjoy…and let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Coffee&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A group of alumni, highly established in their careers, got together to visit their old university professor. Conversation soon turned into complaints about stress in work and life. Offering his guests coffee, the professor went to the kitchen and returned with a large pot of coffee and an assortment of cups - porcelain, plastic, glass, crystal, some plain looking, some expensive, some exquisite - telling them to help themselves to the coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When all the students had a cup of coffee in hand, the professor said: “If you noticed, all the nice looking expensive cups were taken up, leaving behind the plain and cheap ones. While it is normal for you to want only the best for yourselves, that is the source of your problems and stress. Be assured that the cup itself adds no quality to the coffee in most cases, it’s just more expensive and in some cases even hides what we drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What all of you really wanted was coffee, not the cup, but you consciously went for the best cups… and then began eyeing each other’s cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now consider this: Life is the coffee, and the jobs, money and position in society are the cups. They are just tools to hold and contain Life, and the type of cup we have does not define, nor change the quality of Life we live. Sometimes, by concentrating only on the cup, we fail to enjoy the coffee.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My mission in life is not merely to survive, but to thrive; and to do so with some passion, some compassion, some humor, and some style.” - Maya Angelou&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Only I can change my life. No one can do it for me.” - Carol Burnett&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Learn to enjoy every minute of your life. Be happy now. Don’t wait for something outside of yourself to make you happy in the future. Think how really precious is the time you have to spend, whether it’s at work or with your family. Every minute should be enjoyed and savored.” - Earl Nightingale&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-june-10-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-june-10-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
