<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Valley of the Sun's Best Real Estate Training</title>
    <description>Nate Martinez, a top Real Estate Agent in The Valley of the Sun, shares his own internal real estate agent training for free. His Real Estate Training, Tips and Advice will help you sell more homes in less time.</description>
    <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 16:00:59 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 16:00:59 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Meet Your Goals by Using the Success Cycle</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ewvzOwSkfS0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Following the success cycle can help you accomplish the big goals you’ve set for 2019.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently attended a Tony Robbins event, and one of the powerful topics he covered was the &lt;strong&gt;success cycle.&lt;/strong&gt; To help you find more success in your own real estate endeavors, I’ll be sharing Tony’s success cycle with you today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The success cycle is made up of four parts: potential, action, results, and belief/certainty.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each one of us has the &lt;strong&gt;potential&lt;/strong&gt; to do anything we set our mind to. Let’s use an example goal of completing 100 transactions in 2019. Our &lt;strong&gt;actions&lt;/strong&gt; will determine how we close these transactions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we do this, we need to track our &lt;strong&gt;results.&lt;/strong&gt; For example, we need to know what our conversion ratio is when we meet with a seller. If you go on 10 listing appointments and gain a client through five, you have a 50% conversion ratio. Once you have this ratio, you can figure out how many listing appointments you’ll need to go on to achieve your goal of 100 transactions in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have taken action, but if you don’t have the &lt;strong&gt;belief or certainty&lt;/strong&gt; in what you’re trying to achieve, it will be difficult to get things done. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to share a story with you about belief and certainty. Many years ago, I went to a CRS conference where some attendees wore a color-coded dot on their badge. &lt;strong&gt;This dot meant they had done 100 transactions that year&lt;/strong&gt;, and most people wearing these dots were speaking about their success on stage. I had never heard of anybody doing 100 transactions in a year, but once I learned how it could be done, I was certain I could do it. &lt;strong&gt;At this same conference the next year, I was able to wear the coveted dot on my badge.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you don’t have the belief or certainty in what you’re trying to achieve, it will be difficult to get things done.%20https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-to-meet-your-goals-by-using-the-success-cycle.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you don’t have the belief or certainty in what you’re trying to achieve, it will be difficult to get things done.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to achieve greater things in 2019, reach out to me and we can figure out a plan that works for you. I’d be more than happy to coach you throughout the year and help you hit each goal you set. In the meantime, let me know if you have any questions or need more information. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 15:31:46 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-to-meet-your-goals-by-using-the-success-cycle.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-to-meet-your-goals-by-using-the-success-cycle.html</guid>
        
        <category>Planning</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Doing the Right Thing Is a Must for Realtors</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OpOPtffGpgg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are you following your ethical responsibility as a Realtor to do the right thing? Today, we’ll discuss why this is important and what it entails.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past few months, ethical concerns have been top-of-mind for Phoenix buyers, sellers, and homeowners. As a Realtor myself, &lt;strong&gt;I have noticed the rise of a few problematic trends within the industry. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, there’s the matter of how showings are conducted. There is a set of instructions real estate professionals are supposed to follow when showing properties. Lately, many Realtors are ignoring these guidelines. This must change. Following the showing instructions will improve the process for everyone involved. Ignoring these guidelines, meanwhile, can engender feelings of ill will. Remember: You aren’t the only person who your actions affect. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were to cancel a showing or show up late without giving the seller notice, for example, imagine how disheartening this might be for them. &lt;strong&gt;Treating everyone’s time as being as valuable as your own is simply the right thing to do.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to this problem, there’s also the issue of showing agents not providing sellers with feedback. Oftentimes, the seller of a property will ask that showing agents tell them what they thought by filling out a short questionnaire. This questionnaire is usually sent via email, and it’s generally very easy to complete. Taking the few moments required to provide this feedback is the least we as Realtors can do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Each choice you make will shape the way our industry is viewed as a whole.%20https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/why-doing-the-right-thing-is-a-must-for-realtors.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Each choice you make will shape the way our industry is viewed as a whole.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, make sure this feedback isn’t too generic. Saying that the “buyer didn’t like the house” with no additional reason or context isn’t good feedback at all. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When making decisions as an agent, put yourself in the seller’s shoes.&lt;/strong&gt; As professionals, we must never disregard their time, needs, and feelings. Each choice you make will shape the way our industry is viewed as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 11:14:29 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/why-doing-the-right-thing-is-a-must-for-realtors.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/why-doing-the-right-thing-is-a-must-for-realtors.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate Martinez's Journey Through Real Estate</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FgSBK_PUT2c?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 14:38:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nate-martinezs-journey-through-real-estate.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nate-martinezs-journey-through-real-estate.html</guid>
        
        <category>Reviews and Referrals</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Simple Concept That Can Transform Your Real Estate Business</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ueda1d03Y84?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;What if I told you that you could increase your business just by remembering “3, 2, 1?” Here’s what I mean.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got a great tip for all of you agents out there today. &lt;strong&gt;It’s a simple way to communicate with 1,250 people over the next 12 months. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were to talk with 1,250 people in the next year, do you think your business would be better than it is now? It definitely would. &lt;strong&gt;Here’s how the “3, 2, 1” method works.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, focus on &lt;strong&gt;calling three past clients&lt;/strong&gt; or other people from your SOI every day and have a conversation with them. If you do this each day, Monday through Friday, that would equal 750 contacts over the course of the year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, focus on &lt;strong&gt;prospecting each day until you find two possible leads&lt;/strong&gt; you can add to your SOI. That’s another 500 contacts over the course of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were able to close just 1% of those contacts, that’s an additional 12.5 transactions per year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Calling three people per day will result in an additional 1,250 touches per year.%20https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/a-simple-concept-that-can-transform-your-real-estate-business.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Calling three people per day will result in an additional 1,250 touches per year.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, you need to &lt;strong&gt;take some time out of each week to learn one new thing.&lt;/strong&gt; Whether it’s a lesson from a webinar, a book, or a conference, learning something new every week will give you 52 new pieces of knowledge each year. If you can work in one referral per day to someone in your SOI, that is a huge bonus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you use this method to increase your business and have more success in the coming year. If you have any questions about the “3, 2, 1” method or anything else related to the real estate business, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 11:40:49 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/a-simple-concept-that-can-transform-your-real-estate-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/a-simple-concept-that-can-transform-your-real-estate-business.html</guid>
        
        <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Truth About Whether Our Market Is Headed for a Crash</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Uvg63C7dhfc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are we headed for a crash? Let’s discuss this crucial question.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, a lot of people have been asking us whether the market is going to crash. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In our local Phoenix area, the economy and the new construction market are booming.&lt;/strong&gt; This is very similar to what we saw before the last market crash, but this doesn’t necessarily mean history will repeat itself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the last crash, a lot of investors were entering our market with the intention of riding out potential appreciation. Today, though, the prospect of appreciation isn’t the primary driving force behind most home purchases. &lt;strong&gt;This fact alone highlights the stark contrast between our market now and what we saw years ago.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is this: We may experience a correction within the next year or two, but today’s market conditions are a far cry from what was the case during the last crash. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We may experience a correction within the next year or two, but today’s market conditions are a far cry from what was the case during the last crash.%20https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/the-truth-about-whether-our-market-is-headed-for-a-crash.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We may experience a correction within the next year or two, but today’s market conditions are a far cry from what was the case during the last crash.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 15:16:52 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/the-truth-about-whether-our-market-is-headed-for-a-crash.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/the-truth-about-whether-our-market-is-headed-for-a-crash.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Buyers &amp; Sellers Should Know About Earnest Money</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Lyhnr7eaBpY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;What role the earnest money deposit plays in a real estate transaction impacts buyers and sellers in different ways.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a real estate transaction, earnest money is a dollar amount that buyers put down as a deposit to show the seller that they’re sincere. What should buyers and sellers know specifically about this earnest money deposit, though?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a buyer, I recommend an earnest money deposit of at least 1% of your total offer—maybe even 2% if you’re in a multiple offer situation. For example, if your offer is $500,000, your earnest money deposit should be $5,000 (or perhaps $10,000). &lt;strong&gt;Your earnest money deposit is protected by the purchase contract we have here in Arizona&lt;/strong&gt;, and there are many ways you can get it back if the deal falls through as long as you’re bargaining in good faith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I recommend an earnest money deposit of at least 1% of your total offer.%20https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/what-buyers-sellers-should-know-about-earnest-money.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I recommend an earnest money deposit of at least 1% of your total offer.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re a seller, you want to get as much earnest money back as possible&lt;/strong&gt; because you’re the one who’s liable in this situation. If your house is off the market for two months and the buyer doesn’t qualify at the last minute, you’ll have to relinquish that money—you won’t be able to reclaim it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if the buyer gets to close of escrow, they’re completely funded, and they meet all other contingencies, but for whatever reason they just decided not to close, then you’d be completely refunded for having your house off the market for that long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about the earnest money deposit, real estate contracts, or the home buying process in general, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 14:54:24 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/what-buyers-sellers-should-know-about-earnest-money.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/what-buyers-sellers-should-know-about-earnest-money.html</guid>
        
        <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Interest Rates Will Affect Your Clients</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/sDEcnd5d4Lo?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interest rates are predicted to continue rising. Today I want to take a look at what it means for your clients.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to take a minute to talk about a common topic in the real estate industry: interest rate predictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jamie Dimon, the CEO of JPMorgan Chase, predicts that the yield on the 10-year Treasury bond will go up 5% in the next 24 to 36 months. Typically the spread between the 10-year Treasury bond and a 30-year mortgage is about a 1.75% yield. &lt;strong&gt;The yield as of August 7 for a 30-year mortgage is 4.75% with a spread of 1.77%.&lt;/strong&gt; If the yield goes to 5% then the 30-year mortgage rates rise to 6.75%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these interest rate changes, your clients’ buying power will of course be affected. For example, if they were to buy a home for $290,000 with 5% down, their payment would be $1,437. However, if they wait until the interest rate increases to 6.75%, that same loan would give them a payment of $1,786 per month. This $349 increase in interest paid per month is nearly $4,200 per year and $125,000 over the life of the loan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Now is the time to encourage your buyers and sellers to jump into the market before it is too late.%20https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-interest-rates-will-affect-your-clients.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Now is the time to encourage your buyers and sellers to jump into the market before it is too late.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we believe that the interest rates are going to increase, now is the time to encourage your buyers and sellers to jump into the market before it is too late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This communication is provided to you for informational purposes only and should not be relied upon by you. Nate Martinez nor RE/MAX Professionals are not mortgage lenders and so you should contact a qualified mortgage broker directly to learn more about its mortgage products and your eligibility for such products.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 11:53:09 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-interest-rates-will-affect-your-clients.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-interest-rates-will-affect-your-clients.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Prospects</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Agents: It's Time to Find out What's Happening in Our Market</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/scYkAmFsseU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;What’s going on right now in our Phoenix area real estate market? Let’s examine the latest numbers and find out.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest numbers for our Phoenix metro real estate market are in, so let’s review them today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of July, there were only 15,754 active listings in our residential market. This constitutes an 11.1% year-over-year decrease. Meanwhile, the number of pending listings also dropped—undergoing a 3.4% decrease from last year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monthly median sales prices, though, have risen 9.4% since July of 2017, for a current median sale price of $267,990. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the new construction market, activity is booming.&lt;/strong&gt; Yet with so few homes being built in the $200,000 and under price range, both resale and new construction homes within this bracket are seeing rapid appreciation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The market right now is very strong here in our Phoenix area, and it will likely continue to be so. With all of this in mind, you may be wondering what these conditions mean for those looking to buy or sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The market right now is very strong here in our Phoenix area, and it will likely continue to be so.%20https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/agents-its-time-to-find-out-whats-happening-in-our-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The market right now is very strong here in our Phoenix area, and it will likely continue to be so.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For sellers, it’s important to keep a pulse on how seasonal market trends may impact your goals. &lt;strong&gt;Conditions tend to lag slightly as we head into the fourth quarter, so being mindful of this change and strategizing your sale accordingly will be crucial to your success. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a buyer, it’s important to realize that interest rates are set to rise. That said, those thinking of buying should seize the opportunity to buy now while conditions are still favorable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 16:37:36 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/agents-its-time-to-find-out-whats-happening-in-our-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/agents-its-time-to-find-out-whats-happening-in-our-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Realtors Must Know About Zillow’s Instant Offer Program</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gvKlD23K2BM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;What does Zillow&amp;rsquo;s new Instant Offer program mean for Realtors? Today I will discuss how this change may impact you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zillow has undergone some changes recently, so today I would like to talk about what is new with the site. If you visit Zillow’s website right now, you’ll probably notice that Realtors have been removed from every listing on the site. Now, instead of the name of an agent, the site is advertising their new Instant Offer program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This program shows what Zillow will pay a homeowner for their property. Before, Zillow gave homeowners the opportunity to reach out to agents directly. Now, they are moving past that. This isn’t to say Zillow may not sell leads back to Realtors, but for now, &lt;strong&gt;the Instant Offer program has taken the place of agents on the site.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how is this affecting today’s Realtors? For one thing, it means that people who advertise heavily through Zillow, myself included, will no longer have the option to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it is actually investors who will be most affected by this change. This is because Zillow will be getting the first crack at properties investors may have previously been the first to capture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also believe that this change will place Zillow in more direct competition with other platforms like Opendoor and OfferPad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Zillow will be getting the first crack at properties investors may have previously been the first to capture.%20https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/what-realtors-must-know-about-zillows-instant-offer-program.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Zillow will be getting the first crack at properties investors may have previously been the first to capture.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important for Realtors to be aware of this change and how it may affect them. Staying informed is a critical aspect of any agent’s career. &lt;strong&gt;If you are concerned about this change, my recommendation is to focus on your past client database.&lt;/strong&gt; Build deeper connections with people you have already formed relationships with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 08:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/what-realtors-must-know-about-zillows-instant-offer-program.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/what-realtors-must-know-about-zillows-instant-offer-program.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How’s the Phoenix Market Doing Right Now?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/B0KJGngf8P4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phoenix real estate is doing extremely well right now. Here’s what the latest numbers are telling us.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest numbers are in and I’m excited to share them with you today. Let’s get right to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In March of this year, 9,402 homes closed escrow. In January, we only had 6,000 closed sales, which is still a strong number. &lt;strong&gt;This is one of the strongest first quarters we’ve seen in a while.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The market is up 36%, but inventory has dropped almost 12% at the same time. There are currently 21,703 homes active on the MLS today. The average list price is up 8.8% to $381,000 and the average sale price is up 9.5% to $316,400.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One of the most fascinating things I found was when looking at this year’s numbers compared to the numbers from the past 18 years.&lt;/strong&gt; Back in 2001, the average price in the valley was $175,900. In 2007, the market roared to a peak of $345,900 before crashing and bottoming out in 2009 at $159,080. We’ve made a significant rebound since. Today, the average price is $316,365.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People who bought at the peak are close to being back where they were. People who bought 17 years ago have more than doubled their money, as have the people who bought at the bottom of the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=People who bought at the peak are seeing values rise back to where they were before.%20https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/hows-the-phoenix-market-doing-right-now.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“People who bought at the peak are seeing values rise back to where they were before.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an added note, I’ve seen more cranes in the sky in the Phoenix than I have in the last 10 years. &lt;strong&gt;High-rises, hotels, and more are being built all around the Valley, which is great news for our economy and ultimately, our market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope your market is doing well. If you have any questions for me at all about the latest numbers or about the business in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/hows-the-phoenix-market-doing-right-now.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/hows-the-phoenix-market-doing-right-now.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
