<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Valley of the Sun's Best Real Estate Training</title>
    <description>Nate Martinez, a top Real Estate Agent in The Valley of the Sun, shares his own internal real estate agent training for free. His Real Estate Training, Tips and Advice will help you sell more homes in less time.</description>
    <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 10:06:49 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 10:06:49 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message June 24, 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/181219-natemondaymessage-v1-9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-message&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to another edition of Nate’s Monday Morning Message! As we are constantly working on improving ourselves and our situations, we try to make things better each day, in big and small ways. The challenge becomes the consistency of doing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many things in life they get harder to do over time and we need to dig deeper and deeper to find the strength and determination to succeed. What it comes down to is passion. Do you have the passion to achieve the goal that you are working towards? Do you have the passion to put up with the bad with the hope that the good will be so very worth it? You must find your passion in everything you do. It is a mindset and it can be created over and over and over if you desire the end result bad enough. Passion is the gas that runs your engine. Find yours and put it to work! Let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;L- Love: your passion is something you love to do.&lt;br /&gt;I- Interest: your passion is something that interests you.&lt;br /&gt;F- Fulfilling: your passion gives you a sense of fulfillment.&lt;br /&gt;E- Empowering: your passion usually empowers and energizes you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P- Personal: your passion has personal significance to you and you alone.&lt;br /&gt;A- Abilities: your passion capitalizes on your assets, attributes and abilities.&lt;br /&gt;S- Service: your passion will usually provide a service or fulfill a need.&lt;br /&gt;S- Spiritual: your passion and its pursuit represent an area of spiritual growth.&lt;br /&gt;I- Inspiring: your passion is inspiring to you and therefore will inspire others too.&lt;br /&gt;O- Obvious: your passion, once found, is usually something obvious to you.&lt;br /&gt;N- Natural: your passion is often unstudied and comes naturally to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Every great dream begins with a dreamer. Always remember, you have within you the strength, the patience, and the passion to reach for the stars to change the world.” - Harriet Tubman&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Follow your passion, be prepared to work hard and sacrifice, and, above all, don’t let anyone limit your dreams.” - Donovan Bailey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is no passion to be found playing small - in settling for a life that is less than the one you are capable of living.”- Nelson Mandela&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-june-24-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-june-24-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message June 17, 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/181219-natemondaymessage-v1-9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-message&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Nate’s Monday Morning Message! This morning, I wanted to remind all of you of the 5 P’s of Life: Prior - Planning - Prevents - Poor - Performance. To be truly successful in all we do both personally and professionally, planning is a must! We must plan for what we need to do and also plan for the different roadblocks that may and most likely will get in our way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When these roadblocks pop-up we will be prepared and able to act quickly. Once we have our plans, we can go after our goals with the passion, determination, and focus to be successful. Spending a small amount of time in the beginning can save you a bunch of time in the end. Remember that you must also take action! Taking action is honestly the single biggest differentiator to success. Follow the 5 P’s and take action EVERYDAY! Let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Principles of Life:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winning isn’t everything but wanting to win is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You would achieve more, if you don’t mind who gets the credit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When everything else is lost, the future still remains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t fight too much or the enemy will know your art of war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only job you start at the top is when you dig a grave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t stand for something, you’ll fall for everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do little things well, you’ll do big ones better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only thing that comes to you without effort is old age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You won’t get a second chance to make a first impression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only those who do nothing do not make mistakes.If you are not failing, you’re not taking enough risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t try to get rid of your bad temper by losing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If at first you don’t succeed, skydiving is not for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who don’t make mistakes usually don’t make anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two kinds of failures: Those who think and never do, and those who do and never think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pick battles big enough to matter, small enough to win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All progress has resulted from unpopular decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change your thoughts and you change your world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding proves intelligence, not the speed of the learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two kinds of fools in this world: Those who give advice and those who don’t take it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Management is doing things right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leadership is doing the right things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friendship founded on business is always better than business founded on friendship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When it is obvious that the goals cannot be reached, don’t adjust the goals, adjust the action steps.” – Confucius&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Successful people maintain a positive focus in life no matter what is going on around them. They stay focused on their past successes rather than their past failures, and on the next action steps they need to take to get them closer to the fulfillment of their goals rather than all the other distractions that life presents to them.” - Jack Canfield&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Vision without action is merely a dream. Action without vision just passes the time. Vision with action can change the world.” - Joel A. Barker&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-june-17-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-june-17-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message June 10, 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/181219-natemondaymessage-v1-9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-message&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Nate’s Monday Morning Message! Over time we accumulate things that are a result of our hard work and determination. However, let us keep in mind that the tangible possessions around us are not the reason for living, but rather the result of a life lived properly. The people and the experiences we have are so much more valuable than any item we may acquire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let this week’s message be a reminder to be present in all that you do. Slow down and concentrate on the conversations you are having with your children, spouse, or other loved ones. Slow down and enjoy the thoughts that you may have about experiences of the past. Slow down and think about all the great people and opportunities that are surrounding you each day. Commit to living a life you truly enjoy…and let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Coffee&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A group of alumni, highly established in their careers, got together to visit their old university professor. Conversation soon turned into complaints about stress in work and life. Offering his guests coffee, the professor went to the kitchen and returned with a large pot of coffee and an assortment of cups - porcelain, plastic, glass, crystal, some plain looking, some expensive, some exquisite - telling them to help themselves to the coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When all the students had a cup of coffee in hand, the professor said: “If you noticed, all the nice looking expensive cups were taken up, leaving behind the plain and cheap ones. While it is normal for you to want only the best for yourselves, that is the source of your problems and stress. Be assured that the cup itself adds no quality to the coffee in most cases, it’s just more expensive and in some cases even hides what we drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What all of you really wanted was coffee, not the cup, but you consciously went for the best cups… and then began eyeing each other’s cups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now consider this: Life is the coffee, and the jobs, money and position in society are the cups. They are just tools to hold and contain Life, and the type of cup we have does not define, nor change the quality of Life we live. Sometimes, by concentrating only on the cup, we fail to enjoy the coffee.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My mission in life is not merely to survive, but to thrive; and to do so with some passion, some compassion, some humor, and some style.” - Maya Angelou&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Only I can change my life. No one can do it for me.” - Carol Burnett&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Learn to enjoy every minute of your life. Be happy now. Don’t wait for something outside of yourself to make you happy in the future. Think how really precious is the time you have to spend, whether it’s at work or with your family. Every minute should be enjoyed and savored.” - Earl Nightingale&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-june-10-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-june-10-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Top 10 Sales Associates &amp; Team for May 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to our top ten agents and teams for the month of May - keep up the hard work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/190604-top10-may19-ig-assoc-teams-v1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/top-10-sales-associates-team-for-may-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/top-10-sales-associates-team-for-may-2019.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message June 3, 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/181219-natemondaymessage-v1-9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-message&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week’s edition of Nate’s Monday Message…its hard to believe it is already June, which means that school is out, vacations are on the horizon and of course, the temperatures will soar into the triple digits! Amid the summertime fun, we must not lose sight of our goals and ambitions in life. So this week, I’d like to talk about persistence. We need to focus on a plan and putting action steps in place so we can remain on track over the next few months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge of doing anything worthwhile is being able to do what is necessary over and over and not giving up – which is persistence. Let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing Good Corn, Author Unknown &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There once was a farmer who grew award-winning corn. Each year he entered his corn in the state fair where it won a blue ribbon.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One year a newspaper reporter interviewed him and learned something interesting about how he grew it. The reporter discovered that the farmer shared his seed corn with his neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How can you afford to share your best seed corn with your neighbors when they are entering corn in competition with yours each year?” the reporter asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why sir,” said the farmer, “didn’t you know? The wind picks up pollen from the ripening corn and swirls it from field to field. If my neighbors grow inferior corn, cross-pollination will steadily degrade the quality of my corn. If I am to grow good corn, I must help my neighbors grow good corn.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is very much aware of the connectedness of life. His corn cannot improve unless his neighbor’s corn also improves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it is with our lives. Those who choose to live in peace must help their neighbors to live in peace. Those who choose to live well must help others to live well, for the value of a life is measured by the lives it touches. And those who choose to be happy must help others to find happiness, for the welfare of each is bound up with the welfare of all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lesson for each of us is this: if we are to grow good corn, we must help our neighbors grow good corn. It is possible to give away and become richer! It is also possible to hold on too tightly and lose everything. Yes, the liberal man shall be rich! By watering others, he waters himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Patience, persistence and perspiration make an unbeatable combination for success. Napoleon Hill&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ambition is the path to success, persistence is the vehicle you arrive in.” - William Eardley IV&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Persistence is a secret weapon for everyone.” - Liu Wen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-june-3-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-june-3-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message May 20, 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/181219-natemondaymessage-v1-9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-message&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week’s edition of Nate’s Monday Message! Over the weekend, as I spent time with my family it got me thinking about how we spend our time whether it is at work or at play or simple hanging out at home. Are we really making the best use of our time each and every day? Are there times when if we planned a little better, we could get more done? Do we wish we had more time to spend on the things we truly love? There is a solution to maximizing our time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set a goal, create a plan, and then accomplish it. This will be our challenge for this week. If you found 30 minutes a day, what would you do with it? Think long and hard about this answer as this will be what you think about while figuring out what you can change around, do differently, or eliminate from your schedule. Time is the one thing that is equal among all of us. How we use it is what makes all the difference in the world. Use it wisely for once it is gone it can never be replaced. Let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take time to laugh&lt;br /&gt;It is the music of the soul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take time to thinkI&lt;br /&gt;t is the source of power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take time to play&lt;br /&gt;It is the source of perpetual youth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take time to read&lt;br /&gt;It is the fountain of wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take time to pray&lt;br /&gt;It is the greatest power on earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take time to love and be loved&lt;br /&gt;It is a God-given privilege.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take time to be friendly&lt;br /&gt;It is the road to happiness&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take time to give&lt;br /&gt;It is too short a day to be selfish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Successful people maintain a positive focus in life no matter what is going on around them. They stay focused on their past successes rather than their past failures, and on the next action steps they need to take to get them closer to the fulfillment of their goals rather than all the other distractions that life presents to them.” - Jack Canfield&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In every day, there are 1,440 minutes. That means we have 1,440 daily opportunities to make a positive impact.” - Les Brown&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Keep your face to the sunshine and you cannot see a shadow.” - Helen Keller&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P.S. You are invited&lt;/strong&gt; to join me for a &lt;strong&gt;3-hour business planning workshop&lt;/strong&gt; that I am hosting on Thursday, &lt;strong&gt;May 30th from 3:30-6:30pm&lt;/strong&gt; at Modern Margarita in Glendale. A taco bar and margaritas included! Space is limited so be sure to secure your seat today by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/3-hour-business-planning-workshop-tickets-53697126551&quot;&gt;clicking here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-may-20-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-may-20-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to RE/MAX Professionals Veronica Acevedo</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Please help us welcome Veronica to the RE/MAX Professionals’ family!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/veronica-a.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/190205-welcomeaboard-gkatz-v1-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/welcome-to-remax-professionals-veronica-acevedo.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/welcome-to-remax-professionals-veronica-acevedo.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to RE/MAX Professionals Kim Glasgow</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Please help us welcome Kim to the RE/MAX Professionals’ family!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/190515-welcomeaboard-kglasgow-h-v1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/190205-welcomeaboard-gkatz-v1-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/welcome-to-remax-professionals-kim-glasgow.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/welcome-to-remax-professionals-kim-glasgow.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message May 13, 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/181219-natemondaymessage-v1-9.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-message&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week’s edition of Nate’s Monday Message! I hope everyone had a wonderful Mother’s Day celebration! As we prepare ourselves for another amazing week, let us keep in mind that what we choose to do with our time is completely up to us. We can choose to be in a great mood, or we can choose not to. We can choose to focus on the things in our lives we have control over, or we can choose not to. We can choose to work harder, smarter, and more creatively than our competition or we can choose not to. What do you have control over and what will you do about it? The wonderful thing about life is that it is all up to us. Focus on actions and the results will follow. Let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We shall do much in the years to come,&lt;br /&gt;But what have we done today?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We shall give out gold in a princely sum,&lt;br /&gt;But what did we give today?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We shall lift the heart and dry the tear,&lt;br /&gt;We shall plant a hope in the place of fear,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We shall speak the words of love and cheer,&lt;br /&gt;But what did we speak today ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We shall be so kind in the after while,&lt;br /&gt;But what have we done today?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We shall bring to each lonely life a smile,&lt;br /&gt;But what have we brought today?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We shall give to truth a grander birth,&lt;br /&gt;And to steadfast faith a deeper worth,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We shall feed the hungering souls of earth,&lt;br /&gt;But whom have we fed today?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We shall reap such joys in the by and by,&lt;br /&gt;But what have we sown today?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We shall build us mansions in the sky,&lt;br /&gt;But what have we built today? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;`Tis sweet in the idle dreams to bask;&lt;br /&gt;But here and now, do we our task?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, this is the thing our souls must ask,&lt;br /&gt;What have we done today?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By: Nixon Waterman&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Learn to enjoy every minute of your life. Be happy now. Don’t wait for something outside of yourself to make you happy in the future. Think how really precious is the time you have to spend, whether it’s at work or with your family. Every minute should be enjoyed and savored.” - Earl Nightingale&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Look at the sky. We are not alone. The whole universe is friendly to us and conspires only to give the best to those who dream and work.” - A. P. J. Abdul Kalam&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Success isn’t always about greatness. It’s about consistency. Consistent hard work leads to success. Greatness will come.” - Dwayne Johnson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P.S. You are invited&lt;/strong&gt; to join me for a &lt;strong&gt;3-hour business planning workshop&lt;/strong&gt; that I am hosting on Thursday, &lt;strong&gt;May 30th from 3:30-6:30pm&lt;/strong&gt; at Modern Margarita in Glendale. A taco bar and margaritas included! Space is limited so be sure to secure your seat today by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/3-hour-business-planning-workshop-tickets-53697126551&quot;&gt;clicking here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-may-13-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-may-13-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message May 6, 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/happy-mothers-day-nate-monday-morning-message.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-message&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week’s edition of Nate’s Monday Message! I want to take this opportunity to wish each of you reading this who are mother’s - including those who are step-moms and grandmother’s doing double duty - a very happy Mother’s Day celebration this coming weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also want to give a big shout out to my daughter Brandi for being an amazing mother to my granddaughter, Hayden. It is a joy I can’t describe to see my child raising her own child with such grace, confidence, love and compassion. To my partner Tonya, who is the mother of my youngest daughter Mila, I want to thank you for your constant dedication to our family, to our home and the efforts you put into raising our daughter to be a bright, loving, ambition young lady. I could not do it without you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly to my own Mother, I want to say thank you for helping me to become the man I am today. I know it was not an easy journey raising me and my siblings by yourself and I want you to know that there isn’t a day that goes by that I don’t thank you for your dedication, love and strength.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that you will each take a moment this week and over the weekend to thank your own mom on this Mother’s Day celebration. Let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Mother’s Love &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Of all the special joys in life, &lt;br /&gt;The big ones and the small, &lt;br /&gt;A mother’s love and tenderness &lt;br /&gt;Is the greatest of them all. &lt;em&gt;~ Anon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mama was my greatest teacher, a teacher of compassion, love and fearlessness. If love is sweet as a flower, then my mother is that sweet flower of love.” - Stevie Wonder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sometimes the strength of motherhood is greater than natural laws.” - Barbara Kingsolver&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Motherhood: All love begins and ends there.” - Robert Browning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I remember my mother’s prayers and they have always followed me. They have clung to me all my life.” - Abraham Lincoln&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P.S. You are invited&lt;/strong&gt; to join me for a &lt;strong&gt;3-hour business planning workshop&lt;/strong&gt; that I am hosting on Thursday, &lt;strong&gt;May 30th from 3:30-6:30pm&lt;/strong&gt; at Modern Margarita in Glendale. A taco bar and margaritas included! Space is limited so be sure to secure your seat today by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/3-hour-business-planning-workshop-tickets-53697126551&quot;&gt;clicking here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-may-6-2019.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-may-6-2019.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
