<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Valley of the Sun's Best Real Estate Training</title>
    <description>Nate Martinez, a top Real Estate Agent in The Valley of the Sun, shares his own internal real estate agent training for free. His Real Estate Training, Tips and Advice will help you sell more homes in less time.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 10:04:35 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 10:04:35 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message Volume 1,110</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/020406-nmmm-v1-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-messagevolume-1110&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;br /&gt;Volume 1,110&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week’s edition of Nate’s Morning Message! This past week I had the great privilege of witnessing a few of our agents receive an award at our local board for their hard work helping families with their real estate needs. One of the core values we live by at RE/MAX Professionals is recognition, because we know the power that a word of congratulations, or a job well done shout out can do for someone’s day, their life, their business – and ultimately how it impacts their family. Recognition feels good. It creates momentum. It inspires. This week, I’d like to ask each of you to take a moment and recognize someone in your life – your child for a good grade at school – your spouse for picking up the groceries – your business partner for their collaboration on a new idea – the cashier at the store for their hard work – “good job” goes a long way in making a difference in our world. Let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;100 Ways to Praise Your Child (some of these apply to the adults too!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;That’s Incredible!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How Extraordinary!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re Very Talented!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Outstanding Performance!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Far Out!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Great!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Very Brave!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marvelous!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I Can’t Get Over It!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wonderful!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You Figured It Out!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You Should Be Proud!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amazing Effort!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unbelievable Work!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re the Greatest!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phenomenal!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ve Got It!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Superb!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How Original!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re Special!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cool!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Excellent!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Congratulations!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your Project is First Rate!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Way To Go!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ve Outdone Yourself!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re Super!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thumbs Up!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What A Great Listener!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your Help Counts!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You Make Me Smile!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You Came Through!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Terrific!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You Tried Hard!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re A Pleasure To Know!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fabulous!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your Effort Really Shows!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You Made It Happen!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What A Genius Idea!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re A Real Trooper!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It Couldn’t Be Better!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bravo!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re A Champ!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re Unique!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exceptional!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You Set A Good Example!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Right On!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fantastic Work!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Breathtaking!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep Up The Good Work!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clever!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Awesome!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I Knew You Had It In You!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ve Made Progress!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Magnificent!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your Work Is Out of Sight!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What An Imagination!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s Everything I Hoped For!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brilliant!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stupendous!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re Sensational!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Very Good!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re A-OK!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You Made The Difference!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Good For You!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A+ Work!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re So Kind!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take A Bow!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Super Job!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How Thoughtful of You!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re Sharp!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nice Going!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Class Act!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Well Done!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thanks For Helping!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re Inspiring!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How Artistic!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You Go The Extra Mile!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ve Earned My Respect!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hooray For You!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re A Joy!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re A Shining Star!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re #1!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re Amazing!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What A Great Idea!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Great Answer!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Great Discovery!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extra Special Work!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You Deserve A Hug&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re Getting Better!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wow!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re Tops!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re Catching On!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re Neat!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re Very Responsible!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ve Got What It Takes!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spectacular Work!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re A Winner!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thanks For Caring!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beautiful!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t work for recognition, but do work worthy of recognition.” - H. Jackson Brown, Jr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do not dwell in the past, do not dream of the future, concentrate the mind on the present moment.” – Buddha&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There are two things people want more than sex and money…recognition and praise.” - Mary Kay Ash&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright © 2022 Nate Martinez. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/nates-monday-morning-message-volume-1110.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/nates-monday-morning-message-volume-1110.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message Volume 1,109</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/020406-nmmm-v1-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-messagevolume-1109&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;br /&gt;Volume 1,109&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week’s edition of Nate’s Morning Message! I hope this email finds you well, rested, and optimistic for the week that is ahead of us. Today, I want to talk about fear. There is a lot going on in our world, both here in the U.S. and around the globe that is scary and uncertain – most of it is outside of our control – yet I believe there are some of people putting their life on hold because of what they hear or read in the news. For me, the word “fear” stands for “false evidence, appearing real.” Now, I share that not to diminish what is happening in our world, because that is very much real, however there are plenty of challenges or perceptions that we make into a much bigger deal than they need to be – which leaves us crippled by false evidence, appearing real. This week, I want to challenge you to turn off the news and tune into your heart’s desires, focus on your family, take a walk with dog – get quiet and breath. What fears are holding you back right now that you need to let go of? I’d love to hear them – shoot me an email, or a text! Let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John and his friends used to go mountain climbing once every year. This time they have decided to climb mountains in the Swiss Alps. They reached the famous mountain spot in the Swiss Alps and were surprised to see many people climbing the mountains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John and his friends started wearing all the mountain climbing gear and started climbing. In no time, they reached the top of the hill. After reaching there, friends decided to camp there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then John saw another mountain where only a handful of people were trying to climb it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He told his friends, “Let us go and climb that mountain also. It will be fun and challenging instead of camping here.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend replied, “No way, I have heard people talking about that mountain. It seems the path is difficult to climb, and only a few people can able to climb.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People nearby hearing the conversation made fun of John and said, “If it was easy to climb, why we were sitting idle here.” Hearing them, John took that as a challenge and went alone towards climbing the peak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two hours later, he reached the top of the hill. People who were already there welcomed John with a round of applause. John was happy having climbed the peak. He could see the beautiful views of nature from the top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He started a conversation with people and asked them, “While climbing this peak, I felt it was not so difficult. Then why only a handful of people here? If people could climb the below peak, they can climb here also if they put in some effort.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A veteran climber replied, “Most people in the crowd right there are happy with what they find easy. They never think that they have the potential to achieve more. Even people who are not happy there do not want to take any risk. They think if we take risks, they will lose what they already have. But to reach a new peak, we need to put in our effort. Many of them do not show any courage, and they remain part of the crowd the whole life. And keep complaining about the handful of courageous people and call them lucky.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hearing this, John thanked the veteran for explaining the importance of courage in our life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moral of the story&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our life, many of us stay in our comfort zone. But to achieve something big, we need effort and courage. We should never stop, have the courage to push ourselves out of the crowd. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://winnersstory.com/short-stories-about-courage-1/&quot;&gt;https://winnersstory.com/short-stories-about-courage-1/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Even death is not to be feared by one who has lived wisely.” – Buddha&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I have learned over the years that when one’s mind is made up, this diminishes fear; knowing what must be done does away with fear.” - Rosa Parks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Thinking will not overcome fear but action will.” - W. Clement Stone&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright © 2022 Nate Martinez. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/nates-monday-morning-message-volume-1109.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/nates-monday-morning-message-volume-1109.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message Volume 1,108</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/020406-nmmm-v1-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-messagevolume-1108&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;br /&gt;Volume 1,108&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week’s edition of Nate’s Morning Message! I hope this email finds you well, rested and that you had a lovely weekend celebrating with family and friends. Today, I want to talk about priorities. Over the years, our priorities change – for example, when my children were young, they were my priority – to provide a beautiful home, a good education – now as they are grown and started their own families, my priority is now my grandchildren. I wasn’t always great at putting my priorities in the right order, which was painful and costly, in many ways. It takes an effort, and it takes acknowledging what your priorities are – how important are they? Are you willing to move mountains for them? Are you willing to sacrifice? Are you willing to do whatever it takes? This week, I’d like to challenge you to reconsider your priorities – and ask yourself if they are in the right order so you can live your best life – and your family can too. Let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine that you are juggling five balls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of them is representing important parts of our life – family, health, spirit, friends and work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four balls are made of glass and only one is made of rubber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to recognize that work is a rubber ball. While family, friends, health and spirit are very fragile, and if you drop one of them, they will be irreversibly damaged or even shattered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This understanding will help to keep the balance in your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inspirationalstories.eu/&quot;&gt;https://www.inspirationalstories.eu/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The key is not to prioritize what’s on your schedule, but to schedule your priorities.” - Stephen Covey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Action expresses priorities.” - Mahatma Gandhi&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sometimes when you’re overwhelmed by a situation - when you’re in the darkest of darkness - that’s when your priorities are reordered.” - Phoebe Snow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright © 2022 Nate Martinez. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/nates-monday-morning-message-volume-1108.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/nates-monday-morning-message-volume-1108.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message Volume 1,107</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/020406-nmmm-v1-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-messagevolume-1107&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;br /&gt;Volume 1,107&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week’s edition of Nate’s Morning Message! How did your week go? Did you find an opportunity to embrace the changes in your life? I’d love to hear from you! This week let’s talk about the real estate market and more importantly interest rates. If you are in the industry, you know that rates took a bit of a hike last week – and if you are an active buyer in the market, this might have you concerned about the affordability. When I bought my first house, the interest rate on my loan was 18 percent – we have come a long way!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years, we have been spoiled and perhaps we have taken for granted the low, low interest rates. There are many factors contributing to the Fed’s decision to raise the rates, and I won’t bore you with the complexities of inflation and how the real estate industry contributes. What I do want to share, is this – we can’t control the interest rates, we can’t control inflation, we can’t control what someone is willing to pay for a home. What we can control is our decision to be a homeowner. The vast benefits of owning your own home (or two or three) far outweigh paying a little more in interest, especially if you plan to occupy the home for 10+ years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been blessed to serve my community for more than 35 years and I have experienced many different markets, including the great crash – if you are thinking we will experience that again, and you are waiting to buy, please reach out to me today. If you are an agent struggling to find your clients homes, let’s connect. If you are a homeowner and would love to sell but you don’t know where you’d go, please give me a call - none of our clients have ever been homeless!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our decisions are the only thing we can control. Remember that. Let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just One – Unknown&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One song can spark a moment,&lt;br /&gt;One flower can wake the dream&lt;br /&gt;One tree can start a forest,&lt;br /&gt;One bird can herald spring.&lt;br /&gt;One smile begins a friendship,&lt;br /&gt;One handclasp lifts a soul.&lt;br /&gt;One star can guide a ship at sea,&lt;br /&gt;One word can frame the goal&lt;br /&gt;One vote can change a nation,&lt;br /&gt;​​One sunbeam lights a room&lt;br /&gt;One candle wipes out darkness,&lt;br /&gt;One laugh will conquer gloom.&lt;br /&gt;One step must start each journey.&lt;br /&gt;One word must start each prayer.&lt;br /&gt;One hope will raise our spirits,&lt;br /&gt;One touch can show you care.&lt;br /&gt;One voice can speak with wisdom,&lt;br /&gt;One heart can know what’s true,&lt;br /&gt;One life can make a difference,&lt;br /&gt;You see, it’s up to you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The ache for home lives in all of us, the safe place where we can go as we are and not be questioned.” - Maya Angelou&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Owning a home is a keystone of wealth - both financial affluence and emotional security.” - Suze Orman&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Home is the nicest word there is.” - Laura Ingalls Wilder&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright © 2022 Nate Martinez. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/nates-monday-morning-message-volume-1107.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/nates-monday-morning-message-volume-1107.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message Volume 1,106</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/020406-nmmm-v1-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-messagevolume-1106&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;br /&gt;Volume 1,106&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week’s edition of Nate’s Morning Message! Spring has sprung and before we know it, the triple digits will be here in the Valley of the Sun! As the season changes, change is a great topic for today’s message. Most of us don’t enjoy change, however, there are very few things in life that are a guarantee and change happens to be one of them. While some changes can be painful and uncomfortable, there is also something beautiful and unique with every change we experience – we can gracefully accept that change is inevitable, or we can create resistance which leads to more pain and discomfort. How do you handle change? I’d love to hear from you! This week, I want to challenge you to embrace change and look for the opportunity to grow and become a newer version of yourself. Let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes your biggest weakness can become your biggest strength. Take, for example, the story of one 10-year-old boy who decided to study judo despite the fact that he had lost his left arm in a devastating car accident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boy began lessons with an old Japanese judo master. The boy was doing well, so he couldn’t understand why, after three months of training the master had taught him only one move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sensei,” the boy finally said, “Shouldn’t I be learning more moves?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is the only move you know, but this is the only move you’ll ever need to know,” the sensei replied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not quite understanding, but believing in his teacher, the boy kept training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several months later, the sensei took the boy to his first tournament. Surprising himself, the boy easily won his first two matches. The third match proved to be more difficult, but after some time, his opponent became impatient and charged; the boy deftly used his one move to win the match. Still amazed by his success, the boy was now in the finals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time, his opponent was bigger, stronger, and more experienced. For a while, the boy appeared to be overmatched. Concerned that the boy might get hurt, the referee called a time-out. He was about to stop the match when the sensei intervened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No,” the sensei insisted, “Let him continue.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon after the match resumed, his opponent made a critical mistake: he dropped his guard. Instantly, the boy used his move to pin him. The boy had won the match and the tournament. He was the champion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way home, the boy and sensei reviewed every move in each and every match. Then the boy summoned the courage to ask what was really on his mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sensei, how did I win the tournament with only one move?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You won for two reasons,” the sensei answered. “First, you’ve almost mastered one of the most difficult throws in all of judo. And second, the only known defense for that move is for your opponent to grip your left arm.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boy’s biggest weakness had become his biggest strength.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bizmove.com/inspiration/&quot;&gt;https://www.bizmove.com/inspiration/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To improve is to change; to be perfect is to change often.” - Winston Churchill&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is nothing permanent except change.” – Heraclitus&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Since we cannot change reality, let us change the eyes which see reality.” - Nikos Kazantzakis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright © 2022 Nate Martinez. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/nates-monday-morning-message-volume-1106.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/nates-monday-morning-message-volume-1106.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message Volume 1,105</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/020406-nmmm-v1-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-messagevolume-1105&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;br /&gt;Volume 1,105&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week’s edition of Nate’s Morning Message! It’s the last week of Q1 of 2022 – how are you doing with your goals so far? Are you on track or do you need to make some adjustments? I was going through an old notebook the other day, and I came across some notes I wrote in 2018 on a few goals I wanted to accomplish. As I read through them, I couldn’t help but smile and be reminded of the power of intentionally planning your life. Many of the things I wrote down I had accomplished. This week, I want to encourage you to review your progress so far for 2022 – reflect on what is working and revise what is not. Reset, refocus and let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a man, who lived in the mountain village, and he was known because he has never argued with anyone. One day some correspondent, who wished to write about this man in the Guinness book of records, came to him. They had the following conversation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Please tell me, is it true, that you have lived more than 90 years and never argued with anyone?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes, it is true.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Absolutely with no one? Absolutely with no one, at all! Even with your wife?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Even with my wife.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Even with your children?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Even with my children.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Not once for 90 years?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Not once.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Not once absolutely with no one?” — becoming angry, the correspondent asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes,” —the old man said quietly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The correspondent (blushing and becoming irritated): “It can‘t be, that you had not argued with anyone for all your life!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I had, had, had…” the old man said apologetically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inspirationalstories.eu&quot;&gt;https://www.inspirationalstories.eu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A man who dares to waste one hour of time has not discovered the value of life.” - Charles Darwin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There are three constants in life… change, choice and principles.” - Stephen Covey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Find ecstasy in life; the mere sense of living is joy enough.” - Emily Dickinson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright © 2022 Nate Martinez. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/nates-monday-morning-message-volume-1105.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/nates-monday-morning-message-volume-1105.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Reasons Why Our Market Will Stay Strong</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ABCPcqgoYCw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;Four reasons why our market isn’t going to crash anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is our market going to crash? I get this question almost every day, and my answer is a hard no. The demand for real estate in our Phoenix market is unheard of, and besides that, there are four good reasons why our market is still strong:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Multiple offers.&lt;/strong&gt; Even after 16 months of a competitive market, we still see multiple-offer situations, so demand is not letting up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Low inventory.&lt;/strong&gt; This goes back to supply and demand. We have a very small supply of homes and a huge demand from buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Job creation.&lt;/strong&gt; There are cranes and new manufacturing plants everywhere you look in Phoenix. Another 150,000 homes are supposed to be built in the north Phoenix valley soon. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Price appreciation.&lt;/strong&gt; Homes increased in value by 32% last year. There is a lot of equity in the market, and it shows no signs of slowing down. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about the market or just want to chat, give me a call at (602) 942-7000. I’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 11:25:14 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-reasons-why-our-market-will-stay-strong.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/4-reasons-why-our-market-will-stay-strong.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message Volume 1,104</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/020406-nmmm-v1-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-messagevolume-1104&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;br /&gt;Volume 1,104&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week’s edition of Nate’s Morning Message! I hope this email finds you well, refreshed and ready to accomplish another week. Last week we talked about choosing your words wisely – how did that go for you over the past week? There is so much noise in our world today, and much negativity that it can be a challenge to focus on the good. Today, I’d like to gently remind you that no matter what is happening with the world, no matter how bleak things might seem, there is always something good to see around you. Even as small as a newly budding tree, a beautiful sunrise, the sound of a child’s laughter, or the smell of a freshly brewed cup of coffee – there is always something that you can be grateful for. This week, turn off the news, put down your cell phone and take a moment to breath in life. There is &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; something good. Let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One cowardly person came to a master of martial arts and asked to teach him bravery. The master looked at him and said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I will teach you only with one condition: one month you will have to live in a big city and tell every person that you meet on your way that you are a coward. You will have to say it loudly, openly and looking straight into the person’s eyes.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The person got really sad, because this task seemed very scary to him. For a couple of days he was very sad and thoughtful, but to live with his cowardice was so unbearable that he travelled to the city to accomplish his mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, when meeting the passers, he quailed, lost his speech and couldn’t contact anyone. But he needed to finish the master’s task, so he began to overcome himself. When he came up to his first passer to talk about his cowardice, it seemed to him that he would die from fear. But his voice sounded louder and more confident with every passing day. Suddenly came a moment, when the man caught himself thinking that he’s not scared anymore, and the further he continued doing the master’s task, the more convinced he was that the fear was abandoning him. That way a month had passed. The person came back to the master, bowed to him and said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Thank you, teacher. I finished your task. Now I’m not afraid anymore. But how did you know that this strange task will help me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The thing is that cowardice is only a habit. And by doing the things that scare us, we can destroy the stereotypes and come to a conclusion that you came to. And now you know that bravery – is also a habit. And if you want to make bravery a part of yourself- you need to move forward into the fear. Then the fear will go away, and bravery will take its place.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inspirationalstories.eu&quot;&gt;https://www.inspirationalstories.eu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Courage is found in unlikely places.” - J. R. R. Tolkien&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You cannot have a positive life and a negative mind.” - Joyce Meyer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Some of us think holding on makes us strong; but sometimes it is letting go.” - Hermann Hesse&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright © 2022 Nate Martinez. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/nates-monday-morning-message-volume-1104.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/nates-monday-morning-message-volume-1104.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message Volume 1,103</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/020406-nmmm-v1-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-messagevolume-1103&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;br /&gt;Volume 1,103&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week’s edition of Nate’s Morning Message! I heard this quote the other day, which has inspired me for today’s message… “the words I speak are the house I live in.” That got me thinking, especially because, as you know, we sell a few houses around here! Our home is so much more than the place we put our head down to sleep at night. It’s our bodies, it’s our families, it’s our health, it’s our dreams, it’s our struggles, but most importantly, its our mindset. What we think, we speak, and what we speak becomes our reality. Choose your words wisely, because the words you speak, are the house you live in. Let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2015, nine-year-old Marlee Pack was informed that she was suffering from alveolar rhabdomyosarcoma, a rare form of soft tissue cancer. Marlee was forced to miss a lot of school due to her treatment, which involved weeks of grueling chemotherapy. When the time came for Marlee to return to class at Meridian Elementary School in Broomfield, Colorado, she felt worried about being the only one with a shaved head. That’s when her friend Cameron McLaughlin decided to shave her head in solidarity with her close pal. 80 students and some teachers from the school followed suit, all shaving their heads in support of Marlee at a school event called “Be Bold, Be Brave, Go Bald”. The event raised more than $25,000 (£19,000] for St Baldrick’s Foundation, a childhood cancer research organization. “I didn’t think that many people would shave their heads, but I feel good about going back to school and not being the only bald one,” Marlee told Today.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: independent.co.uk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Opportunities are like sunrises. If you wait too long, you miss them.” - William Arthur Ward&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I get up in the morning looking for an adventure.” - George Foreman&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“First thing every morning before you arise say out loud, ‘I believe,’ three times.” - Ovid&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright © 2022 Nate Martinez. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/nates-monday-morning-message-volume-1103.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/nates-monday-morning-message-volume-1103.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message Volume 1,102</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/020406-nmmm-v1-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;960&quot; height=&quot;960&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nates-monday-morning-messagevolume-1102&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nate’s Monday Morning Message&lt;br /&gt;Volume 1,102&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to this week’s edition of Nate’s Morning Message! As you read last week, I spent the week in Las Vegas attending the 49th annual RE/MAX convention. It was a jam-packed week of learning, networking and celebrating the milestone of my team’s achievements from 2021 and those we have the privilege to work with at RE/MAX Professionals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first time in real estate history, RE/MAX became the first real estate brand to sell more than two million homes worldwide – wow! What an honor it is to be surrounded by the best-of-the-best in our industry and to be able to provide the level of service we do for our clients so that we can have this type of reach around the globe. I want to thank each of you reading this email for your trust and confidence over the past 35+ years. This gratitude is extended to the agents who call themselves RE/MAX Professionals – we could not have accomplished this greatness without each of you! THANK YOU! Let’s make it a great week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;24 Thoughts Never To Forget…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your presence is a present to the world.&lt;br /&gt;You’re unique and one of a kind.&lt;br /&gt;Your life can be what you want it to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take the days just one at a time.&lt;br /&gt;Count your blessings, not your troubles.&lt;br /&gt;You’ll make it through whatever comes along.&lt;br /&gt;Within you are so many answers.&lt;br /&gt;Understand, have courage, be strong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t put limits on yourself.&lt;br /&gt;So many dreams are waiting to be realized.&lt;br /&gt;Decisions are too important to leave to chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reach for your peak, your goal, your prize.&lt;br /&gt;Nothing wastes more energy than worrying.&lt;br /&gt;The longer one carries a problem, the heavier it gets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t take things too seriously.&lt;br /&gt;Live a life of serenity, not a life of regrets.&lt;br /&gt;Remember that a little love goes a long way…Remember that a lot…goes forever.&lt;br /&gt;Remember that friendship is a wise investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life’s treasures are people…together.&lt;br /&gt;Realize that it’s never too late.&lt;br /&gt;Do ordinary things in an extraordinary way.&lt;br /&gt;Have health and hope and happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take time to wish upon a star.&lt;br /&gt;And don’t ever forget…for even a day…How very special you are. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WORDS OF INSPIRATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt;Opportunities are like sunrises. If you wait too long, you miss them.” - William Arthur Ward&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I remind myself every morning: Nothing I say this day will teach me anything. So if I’m going to learn, I must do it by listening.” - Larry King&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There was never a night or a problem that could defeat sunrise or hope.” - Bernard Williams&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals&lt;br /&gt;www.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com&lt;br /&gt;623-362-3000&lt;br /&gt;consult@rmxprofessionals.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright © 2022 Nate Martinez. All rights reserved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/nates-monday-morning-message-volume-1102.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/nates-monday-morning-message-volume-1102.html</guid>
        
        <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
