<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Valley of the Sun Real Estate Podcast with Nate Martinez</title>
    <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from RE/MAX Professionals - your professional Valley of the Sun Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Nate Martinez</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2019-07-16 15:21:45 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Nate Martinez</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>NateM@Remax.net</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Nate Martinez</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Valley of the Sun Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from RE/MAX Professionals - your professional Valley of the Sun Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message July 15, 2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-july-15-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-07-14 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Nate’s Monday Morning Message

Welcome to Nate’s Monday Morning Message! We all face similar challenges in our lives, and we all handle those challenges differently. There a few things that we all could do better to make the challenges that will come a little easier to handle. First, keep in mind that there will always be challenges and disruptions that throw us off course; that is life and we all go through it. Second, your reaction to what happens to you is 100 percent within your control. You may not control what happens, but you control what you do about it. Third, pointing fingers or placing blame on others never solves the problem at hand. The goal is to understand what happened why and what you learned from it. Then move on. Fourth, love more and argue less. Spend your time loving rather than arguing with many. Fifth, realize your time here is limited and the clock is ticking. Don’t waste time because once it’s gone, you can’t get it back. Let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

It’s the Journey That’s Important by John McLeod

Life, sometimes so wearyingIs worth its weight in goldThe experience of travelingLends a wisdom that is old

Beyond our ‘living memory’A softly spoken prayer:”It’s the journey that’s important,Not the getting there!”

Ins and outs and ups and downsLife’s road meanders aimlessly?Or so it seems, but somehowLeads us where we need to be,

And being simply humanWe oft question and compare…“Is the journey so importantOr the getting there?”

And thus it’s always beenThat question pondered down the agesBy simple people with simple waysTo wise and ancient sages…

How sweet then, quietly knowingReaching destination fair:“It’s the journey that’s important,Not the getting there!“ 

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“I will love the light for it shows me the way, yet I will endure the darkness because it shows me the stars.” - Og Mandino

“If a man does not keep pace with his companions, perhaps it is because he hears a different drummer. Let him step to the music which he hears, however measured or far away.” - Henry David Thoreau

“I can’t change the direction of the wind, but I can adjust my sails to always reach my destination.” - Jimmy Dean

PS…You are invited to my Business Planning Workshop - including happy hour! We’re doing it again! Come grab some FREE tacos, margaritas and advice on how to turn your real estate business into a 7-figure success. This event will be held at Urban Margarita on 67th Ave and the 101 Loop starting at 3:30pm. I hope to see you there!

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionalswww.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com623-362-3000consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>You Are Invited! Happy Hour Included!</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/you-are-invited-happy-hour-included.html</link>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-07-09 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>You Are Invited - Happy Hour Included!

Please join us next Thursday for a 3 hour business planning workshop with happy hour included! More details below.



Space is limited - to secure your seat today, please click here. We look forward to seeing you on July 18th! 

RE/MAX Professionals623-362-3000consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>You Are Invited - Happy Hour Included!

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>You Are Invited - Happy Hour Included!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Top 10 Sales Associates & Team for June 2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/top-10-sales-associates-team-for-june-2019.html</link>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-07-09 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Congratulations to our top ten agents and teams for the month of June - keep up the hard work!



RE/MAX Professionals623-362-3000consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Congratulations to our top ten agents and teams for the month of June - keep up the hard work!

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Congratulations to our top ten agents and teams for the month of June - keep up the hard work!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message July 8, 2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-july-8-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-07-07 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Nate’s Monday Morning Message

Welcome to Nate’s Monday Morning Message! I hope that each of you reading this are enjoying the summer so far and prepared for the monsoon season that is quickly approaching! This time of year, in the Valley of the Sun provides much needed water for the desert and the monsoons give us some pretty amazing sunsets. I hope that you will take some time during the evenings this summer to enjoy the awe-inspiring clouds and vivid colors that fill our sky; it truly is magnificent and a perfect reminder of the simple blessings that surround us every day. We often stare at a door that has closed for too long and in the process miss the one that has opened. Don’t take for granted the simple beauties in life, as they pave the way to finding a deeper meaning to happiness. Take time to appreciate all the good in your life and make each moment count! Let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

A Fish Stranded in a Drying Puddle

Once there was a fellow walking along a road. Suddenly he heard a faint cry. He looked around but saw nothing. Thinking he heard nothing, he continued to walk. Again he heard the faint cry. This time the call was nearby. He searched high and low, and found the sound was coming out of a little fish lying in a drying pond. His mouth gurgling. That person looked at the fish strangely and asked,”Was that you who was just calling me? Was it you needing my help?”The small fish looking pleading at the man gasping and breathless said, “Please save me quickly, I am dying, I need water. I am not a normal fish, rather I am the eastern sea dragon’s official. Please give me a little water.” That person hearing this hurriedly nodded his head and said, “I understand, I will immediately go to the south and let the southern king redirect a river to here so that you can swim and return to the eastern sea.” The fish angrily cried out, “Can a fish live out of water? I am only in need of a little water. Your idea is pointless. I think that the next time you see me will be in a shop that sells dried fish. “The story tells us to reconsider solutions that we usually propose to solve real life problems. Sometimes we take our time too much to find the most ideal solution, while what the problem really needs is time critical solution.We must always aware that many times in our lives we don’t need the best solution but some quick fixes for the current situation to prevent it of becoming worse. Only until then, we have much more time to think and find the ideal solution.

Source: http://chinese-tales.blogspot.com/

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“Gratitude unlocks the fullness of life. It turns what we have into enough, and more. It turns denial into acceptance, chaos to order, confusion to clarity. It can turn a meal into a feast, a house into a home, a stranger into a friend.” - Melody Beattie

“To succeed in life, you need three things: a wishbone, a backbone and a funny bone.” - Reba McEntire

“Find joy in everything you choose to do. Every job, relationship, home… it’s your responsibility to love it, or change it.” - Chuck Palahniuk

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionalswww.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com623-362-3000consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to RE/MAX Professionals Austin Jones</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/welcome-to-remax-professionals-austin-jones.html</link>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-07-01 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Please help us welcome Austin to the RE/MAX Professionals’ family!



RE/MAX Professionals623-362-3000consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Please help us welcome Austin to the RE/MAX Professionals’ family!

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Please help us welcome Austin to the RE/MAX Professionals’ family!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message July 1, 2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-july-1-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-30 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Nate’s Monday Morning Message

Welcome to Nate’s Monday Morning Message! In honor of the upcoming Fourth of July holiday, I want to take the opportunity to say thank you to the countless men and women who have dedicated their lives so we can celebrate the freedoms we enjoy and celebrate this week. I hope you will take a moment to express your gratitude for what it means to be an American. From all of us on my team, we want to wish each of you a very happy, healthy and safe Fourth of July holiday! Let’s make it a great week!

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“One flag, one land, one heart, one hand, one nation evermore!” - Oliver Wendell Holmes

“America was not built on fear. America was built on courage, on imagination, and an unbeatable determination to do the job at hand.” – Harry S. Truman

“We will stand by the right, we will stand by the true, we will live, we will die for the red, white, and blue.” - Unknown

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionalswww.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com623-362-3000consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Not to Lose Clients to iBuyers</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-not-to-lose-clients-to-ibuyers.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Prospects</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-24 12:43:22 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2019/Have+Your+Own+Story.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Telling the right stories can help you secure more clients, and today I’ll explain how.

I recently read an article that explained how sellers lost $14 billion in equity last year because of the increasing number of iBuyers entering our market. Selling to these companies is usually advertised as a convenient deal, but is actually a very ineffective move for today’s sellers. 

So, what can you do to dissuade sellers from going that route? One of the simplest ways is by doing what you do best: offering expert real estate advice.

“You can use personal success stories of the clients you’ve helped to secure future clients.”

Given that 71% of buyers are afraid to buy a home that needs work, some of the best advice you can offer sellers is to make strategic repairs. The right repairs and upgrades will not only bring a high return, but they’ll also help sellers to close quickly and for top dollar. 

Once you’ve guided a seller to closing using this (or any other tips), you can use the success stories that come out of these experiences to help you secure future clients who might have otherwise considered selling to an iBuyer.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2019/Have+Your+Own+Story.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2019/Have+Your+Own+Story.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Telling the right stories can help you secure more clients, and today I’ll explain how.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Telling the right stories can help you secure more clients, and today I’ll explain how.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message June 24, 2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-june-24-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-23 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Nate’s Monday Morning Message

Welcome to another edition of Nate’s Monday Morning Message! As we are constantly working on improving ourselves and our situations, we try to make things better each day, in big and small ways. The challenge becomes the consistency of doing it.

Like many things in life they get harder to do over time and we need to dig deeper and deeper to find the strength and determination to succeed. What it comes down to is passion. Do you have the passion to achieve the goal that you are working towards? Do you have the passion to put up with the bad with the hope that the good will be so very worth it? You must find your passion in everything you do. It is a mindset and it can be created over and over and over if you desire the end result bad enough. Passion is the gas that runs your engine. Find yours and put it to work! Let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

L- Love: your passion is something you love to do.I- Interest: your passion is something that interests you.F- Fulfilling: your passion gives you a sense of fulfillment.E- Empowering: your passion usually empowers and energizes you.

P- Personal: your passion has personal significance to you and you alone.A- Abilities: your passion capitalizes on your assets, attributes and abilities.S- Service: your passion will usually provide a service or fulfill a need.S- Spiritual: your passion and its pursuit represent an area of spiritual growth.I- Inspiring: your passion is inspiring to you and therefore will inspire others too.O- Obvious: your passion, once found, is usually something obvious to you.N- Natural: your passion is often unstudied and comes naturally to you.

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“Every great dream begins with a dreamer. Always remember, you have within you the strength, the patience, and the passion to reach for the stars to change the world.” - Harriet Tubman

“Follow your passion, be prepared to work hard and sacrifice, and, above all, don’t let anyone limit your dreams.” - Donovan Bailey

“There is no passion to be found playing small - in settling for a life that is less than the one you are capable of living.”- Nelson Mandela

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionalswww.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com623-362-3000consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message June 17, 2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-june-17-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-16 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Nate’s Monday Morning Message

Welcome to Nate’s Monday Morning Message! This morning, I wanted to remind all of you of the 5 P’s of Life: Prior - Planning - Prevents - Poor - Performance. To be truly successful in all we do both personally and professionally, planning is a must! We must plan for what we need to do and also plan for the different roadblocks that may and most likely will get in our way.

When these roadblocks pop-up we will be prepared and able to act quickly. Once we have our plans, we can go after our goals with the passion, determination, and focus to be successful. Spending a small amount of time in the beginning can save you a bunch of time in the end. Remember that you must also take action! Taking action is honestly the single biggest differentiator to success. Follow the 5 P’s and take action EVERYDAY! Let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

Principles of Life:

Winning isn’t everything but wanting to win is.

You would achieve more, if you don’t mind who gets the credit.

When everything else is lost, the future still remains.

Don’t fight too much or the enemy will know your art of war.

The only job you start at the top is when you dig a grave.

If you don’t stand for something, you’ll fall for everything.

If you do little things well, you’ll do big ones better.

Only thing that comes to you without effort is old age.

You won’t get a second chance to make a first impression.

Only those who do nothing do not make mistakes.If you are not failing, you’re not taking enough risks.

Don’t try to get rid of your bad temper by losing it.

If at first you don’t succeed, skydiving is not for you.

Those who don’t make mistakes usually don’t make anything.

There are two kinds of failures: Those who think and never do, and those who do and never think.

Pick battles big enough to matter, small enough to win.

All progress has resulted from unpopular decisions.

Change your thoughts and you change your world.

Understanding proves intelligence, not the speed of the learning.

There are two kinds of fools in this world: Those who give advice and those who don’t take it.

Management is doing things right.

Leadership is doing the right things.

Friendship founded on business is always better than business founded on friendship.

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“When it is obvious that the goals cannot be reached, don’t adjust the goals, adjust the action steps.” – Confucius

“Successful people maintain a positive focus in life no matter what is going on around them. They stay focused on their past successes rather than their past failures, and on the next action steps they need to take to get them closer to the fulfillment of their goals rather than all the other distractions that life presents to them.” - Jack Canfield

“Vision without action is merely a dream. Action without vision just passes the time. Vision with action can change the world.” - Joel A. Barker

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionalswww.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com623-362-3000consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message June 10, 2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-june-10-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-09 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Nate’s Monday Morning Message

Welcome to Nate’s Monday Morning Message! Over time we accumulate things that are a result of our hard work and determination. However, let us keep in mind that the tangible possessions around us are not the reason for living, but rather the result of a life lived properly. The people and the experiences we have are so much more valuable than any item we may acquire.

Let this week’s message be a reminder to be present in all that you do. Slow down and concentrate on the conversations you are having with your children, spouse, or other loved ones. Slow down and enjoy the thoughts that you may have about experiences of the past. Slow down and think about all the great people and opportunities that are surrounding you each day. Commit to living a life you truly enjoy…and let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

The Coffee

A group of alumni, highly established in their careers, got together to visit their old university professor. Conversation soon turned into complaints about stress in work and life. Offering his guests coffee, the professor went to the kitchen and returned with a large pot of coffee and an assortment of cups - porcelain, plastic, glass, crystal, some plain looking, some expensive, some exquisite - telling them to help themselves to the coffee.

When all the students had a cup of coffee in hand, the professor said: “If you noticed, all the nice looking expensive cups were taken up, leaving behind the plain and cheap ones. While it is normal for you to want only the best for yourselves, that is the source of your problems and stress. Be assured that the cup itself adds no quality to the coffee in most cases, it’s just more expensive and in some cases even hides what we drink.

What all of you really wanted was coffee, not the cup, but you consciously went for the best cups… and then began eyeing each other’s cups.

Now consider this: Life is the coffee, and the jobs, money and position in society are the cups. They are just tools to hold and contain Life, and the type of cup we have does not define, nor change the quality of Life we live. Sometimes, by concentrating only on the cup, we fail to enjoy the coffee.”

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“My mission in life is not merely to survive, but to thrive; and to do so with some passion, some compassion, some humor, and some style.” - Maya Angelou

“Only I can change my life. No one can do it for me.” - Carol Burnett

“Learn to enjoy every minute of your life. Be happy now. Don’t wait for something outside of yourself to make you happy in the future. Think how really precious is the time you have to spend, whether it’s at work or with your family. Every minute should be enjoyed and savored.” - Earl Nightingale

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionalswww.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com623-362-3000consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Top 10 Sales Associates & Team for May 2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/top-10-sales-associates-team-for-may-2019.html</link>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-04 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Congratulations to our top ten agents and teams for the month of May - keep up the hard work!



RE/MAX Professionals623-362-3000consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Congratulations to our top ten agents and teams for the month of May - keep up the hard work!

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Congratulations to our top ten agents and teams for the month of May - keep up the hard work!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message June 3, 2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-june-3-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-02 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Nate’s Monday Morning Message

Welcome to this week’s edition of Nate’s Monday Message…its hard to believe it is already June, which means that school is out, vacations are on the horizon and of course, the temperatures will soar into the triple digits! Amid the summertime fun, we must not lose sight of our goals and ambitions in life. So this week, I’d like to talk about persistence. We need to focus on a plan and putting action steps in place so we can remain on track over the next few months.

The challenge of doing anything worthwhile is being able to do what is necessary over and over and not giving up – which is persistence. Let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

Growing Good Corn, Author Unknown 

There once was a farmer who grew award-winning corn. Each year he entered his corn in the state fair where it won a blue ribbon.  

One year a newspaper reporter interviewed him and learned something interesting about how he grew it. The reporter discovered that the farmer shared his seed corn with his neighbors.

“How can you afford to share your best seed corn with your neighbors when they are entering corn in competition with yours each year?” the reporter asked.

“Why sir,” said the farmer, “didn’t you know? The wind picks up pollen from the ripening corn and swirls it from field to field. If my neighbors grow inferior corn, cross-pollination will steadily degrade the quality of my corn. If I am to grow good corn, I must help my neighbors grow good corn.”

He is very much aware of the connectedness of life. His corn cannot improve unless his neighbor’s corn also improves.

So it is with our lives. Those who choose to live in peace must help their neighbors to live in peace. Those who choose to live well must help others to live well, for the value of a life is measured by the lives it touches. And those who choose to be happy must help others to find happiness, for the welfare of each is bound up with the welfare of all.

The lesson for each of us is this: if we are to grow good corn, we must help our neighbors grow good corn. It is possible to give away and become richer! It is also possible to hold on too tightly and lose everything. Yes, the liberal man shall be rich! By watering others, he waters himself.

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“Patience, persistence and perspiration make an unbeatable combination for success. Napoleon Hill

“Ambition is the path to success, persistence is the vehicle you arrive in.” - William Eardley IV

“Persistence is a secret weapon for everyone.” - Liu Wen

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionalswww.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com623-362-3000consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message May 20, 2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-may-20-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-19 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Nate’s Monday Morning Message

Welcome to this week’s edition of Nate’s Monday Message! Over the weekend, as I spent time with my family it got me thinking about how we spend our time whether it is at work or at play or simple hanging out at home. Are we really making the best use of our time each and every day? Are there times when if we planned a little better, we could get more done? Do we wish we had more time to spend on the things we truly love? There is a solution to maximizing our time.

Set a goal, create a plan, and then accomplish it. This will be our challenge for this week. If you found 30 minutes a day, what would you do with it? Think long and hard about this answer as this will be what you think about while figuring out what you can change around, do differently, or eliminate from your schedule. Time is the one thing that is equal among all of us. How we use it is what makes all the difference in the world. Use it wisely for once it is gone it can never be replaced. Let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

Take Time

Take time to laughIt is the music of the soul.

Take time to thinkIt is the source of power.

Take time to playIt is the source of perpetual youth.

Take time to readIt is the fountain of wisdom.

Take time to prayIt is the greatest power on earth.

Take time to love and be lovedIt is a God-given privilege.

Take time to be friendlyIt is the road to happiness

Take time to giveIt is too short a day to be selfish

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“Successful people maintain a positive focus in life no matter what is going on around them. They stay focused on their past successes rather than their past failures, and on the next action steps they need to take to get them closer to the fulfillment of their goals rather than all the other distractions that life presents to them.” - Jack Canfield

“In every day, there are 1,440 minutes. That means we have 1,440 daily opportunities to make a positive impact.” - Les Brown

“Keep your face to the sunshine and you cannot see a shadow.” - Helen Keller

P.S. You are invited to join me for a 3-hour business planning workshop that I am hosting on Thursday, May 30th from 3:30-6:30pm at Modern Margarita in Glendale. A taco bar and margaritas included! Space is limited so be sure to secure your seat today by clicking here.

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionalswww.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com623-362-3000consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to RE/MAX Professionals Veronica Acevedo</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/welcome-to-remax-professionals-veronica-acevedo.html</link>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-15 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Please help us welcome Veronica to the RE/MAX Professionals’ family!



RE/MAX Professionals623-362-3000consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Please help us welcome Veronica to the RE/MAX Professionals’ family!

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Please help us welcome Veronica to the RE/MAX Professionals’ family!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to RE/MAX Professionals Kim Glasgow</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/welcome-to-remax-professionals-kim-glasgow.html</link>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-15 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Please help us welcome Kim to the RE/MAX Professionals’ family!



RE/MAX Professionals623-362-3000consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Please help us welcome Kim to the RE/MAX Professionals’ family!

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Please help us welcome Kim to the RE/MAX Professionals’ family!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message May 13, 2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-may-13-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-12 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Nate’s Monday Morning Message

Welcome to this week’s edition of Nate’s Monday Message! I hope everyone had a wonderful Mother’s Day celebration! As we prepare ourselves for another amazing week, let us keep in mind that what we choose to do with our time is completely up to us. We can choose to be in a great mood, or we can choose not to. We can choose to focus on the things in our lives we have control over, or we can choose not to. We can choose to work harder, smarter, and more creatively than our competition or we can choose not to. What do you have control over and what will you do about it? The wonderful thing about life is that it is all up to us. Focus on actions and the results will follow. Let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

We shall do much in the years to come,But what have we done today?

We shall give out gold in a princely sum,But what did we give today?

We shall lift the heart and dry the tear,We shall plant a hope in the place of fear,

We shall speak the words of love and cheer,But what did we speak today ?

We shall be so kind in the after while,But what have we done today?

We shall bring to each lonely life a smile,But what have we brought today?

We shall give to truth a grander birth,And to steadfast faith a deeper worth,

We shall feed the hungering souls of earth,But whom have we fed today?

We shall reap such joys in the by and by,But what have we sown today?

We shall build us mansions in the sky,But what have we built today? 

`Tis sweet in the idle dreams to bask;But here and now, do we our task?

Yet, this is the thing our souls must ask,What have we done today?

By: Nixon Waterman

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“Learn to enjoy every minute of your life. Be happy now. Don’t wait for something outside of yourself to make you happy in the future. Think how really precious is the time you have to spend, whether it’s at work or with your family. Every minute should be enjoyed and savored.” - Earl Nightingale

“Look at the sky. We are not alone. The whole universe is friendly to us and conspires only to give the best to those who dream and work.” - A. P. J. Abdul Kalam

“Success isn’t always about greatness. It’s about consistency. Consistent hard work leads to success. Greatness will come.” - Dwayne Johnson

P.S. You are invited to join me for a 3-hour business planning workshop that I am hosting on Thursday, May 30th from 3:30-6:30pm at Modern Margarita in Glendale. A taco bar and margaritas included! Space is limited so be sure to secure your seat today by clicking here.

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionalswww.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com623-362-3000consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message May 6, 2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-may-6-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-05 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Nate’s Monday Morning Message

Welcome to this week’s edition of Nate’s Monday Message! I want to take this opportunity to wish each of you reading this who are mother’s - including those who are step-moms and grandmother’s doing double duty - a very happy Mother’s Day celebration this coming weekend.

I also want to give a big shout out to my daughter Brandi for being an amazing mother to my granddaughter, Hayden. It is a joy I can’t describe to see my child raising her own child with such grace, confidence, love and compassion. To my partner Tonya, who is the mother of my youngest daughter Mila, I want to thank you for your constant dedication to our family, to our home and the efforts you put into raising our daughter to be a bright, loving, ambition young lady. I could not do it without you.

Lastly to my own Mother, I want to say thank you for helping me to become the man I am today. I know it was not an easy journey raising me and my siblings by yourself and I want you to know that there isn’t a day that goes by that I don’t thank you for your dedication, love and strength.

I hope that you will each take a moment this week and over the weekend to thank your own mom on this Mother’s Day celebration. Let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

A Mother’s Love Of all the special joys in life, The big ones and the small, A mother’s love and tenderness Is the greatest of them all. ~ Anon.

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“Mama was my greatest teacher, a teacher of compassion, love and fearlessness. If love is sweet as a flower, then my mother is that sweet flower of love.” - Stevie Wonder

“Sometimes the strength of motherhood is greater than natural laws.” - Barbara Kingsolver

“Motherhood: All love begins and ends there.” - Robert Browning

“I remember my mother’s prayers and they have always followed me. They have clung to me all my life.” - Abraham Lincoln

P.S. You are invited to join me for a 3-hour business planning workshop that I am hosting on Thursday, May 30th from 3:30-6:30pm at Modern Margarita in Glendale. A taco bar and margaritas included! Space is limited so be sure to secure your seat today by clicking here.

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionalswww.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com623-362-3000consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message April 29, 2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-april-29-2019-copy.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-28 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Nate’s Monday Morning Message

Welcome to this week’s edition of Nate’s Monday Message! I hope you all had a fabulous weekend and that you found some time to relax and refresh before hitting the ground running for another amazing week. Remember the reasons why you work so hard: accomplishment, satisfaction, provide for your family, build wealth, charter new waters, fine tune your skills, competition, etc.  

Please take five minutes this Monday morning to remember and really think about why you do what you do. The purpose behind your actions is what will get you through difficult times. The goals that you set are the markers of success and achievement. They will guide you on the journey. The actions you take daily are what move you forward little by little to achieve all that you desire. Keep your purpose in sight and work hard on the actions that will lead to your success.  And remember, never, never, never quit! Let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

Climb ‘Til Your Dream Comes TrueWrittenby Helen Steiner Rice

Often your tasks will be many, And more than you think you can do. 

Often the road will be rugged And the hills insurmountable, too.

But always remember, the hills aheadAre never as steep as they seem, 

And with Faith in your heart start upwardAnd climb ‘til you reach your dream. 

For nothing in life that is worthyIs ever too hard to achieve

If you have the courage to try it, And you have the faith to believe.  

For faith is a force that is greaterThan knowledge or power or skill, 

And many defeats turn to triumphIf you trust in God’s wisdom and will.  

For faith is a mover of mountains, There’s nothing that God cannot do, 

So, start out today with faith in your heart, And climb ‘til your dream comes true!

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“For beautiful eyes, look for the good in others; for beautiful lips, speak only words of kindness; and for poise, walk with the knowledge that you are never alone.” - Audrey Hepburn

“To enjoy good health, to bring true happiness to one’s family, to bring peace to all, one must first discipline and control one’s own mind. If a man can control his mind he can find the way to Enlightenment, and all wisdom and virtue will naturally come to him.” - Buddha

“When it is obvious that the goals cannot be reached, don’t adjust the goals, adjust the action steps.” - Confucius

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionalswww.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com623-362-3000consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message April 22, 2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-april-22-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-21 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Nate’s Monday Morning Message

Welcome to this week’s edition of Nate’s Monday Message! I hope everyone enjoyed the Easter holiday weekend! Let’s start out this week taking a few minutes to examine where we are in both our personal and business lives. 

Do we have a stated purpose for both? Do we have a plan to achieve the result desired? Are we working each and every day on the actions that our plan calls for? Are we happy? Do we need to make some changes or work a little harder or smarter to achieve our goals? Are we allowing negative people or thoughts to influence us?

We decide what we will or will not do. We have control over what thoughts will or will not influence us. We choose to act the way we do every minute of every day. If we choose to, we have the power to change anything in our lives for the better. I would love to hear from you on what you plan to do this week to get you closer to your purpose in life! Let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

“Storms Bring Out the Eagles, But the Little Birds Take Cover.” - Helen Steiner Rice

When the “storms of life”

Gather darkly ahead,

I think of these wonderful words 

I once read.

And I say to myself 

As “threatening clouds” hover,

Don’t “fold up your wings”

And “run for cover.”

But like the eagle,

“Spread wide your wings”

And “soar far above”

The troubles life brings.

For the eagle knows

That the higher he flies,

The more tranquil and brighter 

Become the skies. 

And there is nothing in life

God ever asks us to bear 

That we can’t soar above 

“On the wings of prayer.”

And in looking back over

The “storm you passed through,”

You’ll find you gained strength 

And new courage, too.

For in facing “life’s storms”

With an eagle’s wings,

You can fly far above 

Earth’s small, petty things.

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“Learn to get in touch with the silence within yourself, and know that everything in life has purpose. There are no mistakes, no coincidences, all events are blessings given to us to learn from.” - Elisabeth Kubler-Ross

“What you get by achieving your goals is not as important as what you become by achieving your goals.” - Zig Ziglar

“Successful people maintain a positive focus in life no matter what is going on around them. They stay focused on their past successes rather than their past failures, and on the next action steps they need to take to get them closer to the fulfillment of their goals rather than all the other distractions that life presents to them.” - Jack Canfield

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionalswww.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com623-362-3000consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message April 15, 2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-april-15-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-14 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Welcome to this week’s edition of Nate’s Monday Message! What is it that we are going to accomplish this week? In order to success at anything we set out to do, we need a plan. We need to be prepared. We need to be determined. We need to have a great attitude. You can accomplish whatever it is that you choose to accomplish! Make this the week you do something big. You can and you should; the time is now. Let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

The Rocks and Sand Experiment

A philosophy professor stood before his class and had some items in front of him. When class began, wordlessly he picked up a large empty mayonnaise jar and proceeded to fill it with rocks, rocks about 2” in diameter.

He then asked the students if the jar was full. They agreed that it was. So the professor then picked up a box of pebbles and poured them into the jar. He shook the jar lightly. The pebbles, of course, rolled into the open areas between the rocks.

He then asked the students again if the jar was full. They agreed it was. The students laughed. The professor picked up a box of sand and poured it into the jar. Of course, the sand filled up everything else. “Now,” said the professor, “I want you to recognize that this is your life. The rocks are the important things - your family, your partner, your health, your children - anything that is so important to you that if it were lost, you would be nearly destroyed. The pebbles are the other things that matter like your job, your house, your car.”

“The sand is everything else. The small stuff. If you put the sand into the jar first, there is no room for the pebbles or the rocks. The same goes for your life. If you spend all your energy and time on the small stuff, you will never have room for the things that are important to you. Pay attention to the things that are critical to your happiness. Play with your children. Take time to get medical checkups. Take your partner out dancing. There will always be time to go to work, clean the house, give a dinner party and fix the disposal.”

“Take care of the rocks first - the things that really matter. Set your priorities. The rest is just sand.”

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“Stay true to yourself, yet always be open to learn. Work hard, and never give up on your dreams, even when nobody else believes they can come true but you. These are not clichés but real tools you need no matter what you do in life to stay focused on your path.” - Phillip Sweet

“I learned that we can do anything, but we can’t do everything… at least not at the same time. So think of your priorities not in terms of what activities you do, but when you do them. Timing is everything.” -Dan Millman

“Every great dream begins with a dreamer. Always remember, you have within you the strength, the patience, and the passion to reach for the stars to change the world.” - Harriet Tubman 

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionalswww.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com623-362-3000consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can Realtors Compete with Direct Buyer Programs?</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-can-realtors-compete-with-direct-buyer-programs.html</link>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-10 04:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Should Realtors be concerned about new technology in real estate? Our panel of experts weighed in on this topic recently.

There’s recently been a lot of hype surrounding new technology in real estate. Whether it’s from OpenDoor, Zillow, or any other number of companies, there is no shortage of online homebuyers who are looking to make instant offers on homes for sale. As Realtors, should we be worried about this new level of competition?

We recently discussed this issue with a panel of experts from RE/MAX Professionals on how they navigate the market now that these direct buyer programs have entered the fray.

Some of the topics we discussed include:


  Strategies for representing both sellers and buyers through iBuyer programs
  Scripting techniques and negotiating commissions when working with direct buyers
  How you can demonstrate your value as an agent compared to a technology company
  Setting expectations for service fees and repairs on a listing
  How to proceed when a client has received a previous offer from a direct buyer


Watch this short video to view a few highlights from this panel discussion so you can stay ahead of the curve when dealing with new trends in real estate technology.

If you’d like to view the full hour-long discussion, you can watch it in its entirety here.

As always, if you have any questions or there’s anything I can help you with, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There's recently been a lot of hype surrounding new technology in real estate. As Realtors, should we be worried about this new level of competition?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There's recently been a lot of hype surrounding new technology in real estate. As Realtors, should we be worried about this new level of competition?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message April 8, 2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-april-8-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-07 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Welcome to this week’s edition of Nate’s Monday Message! Today I want to write about persistence. The challenge of doing anything meaningful in life, is being able to do what is necessary over and over and not giving up, even with it gets hard. This is the part that we must focus on daily. A plan without action is worthless. We need enough persistence to continuously work the plan day-in and day-out. Persistence will get us to where we want to be…and what need to achieve a big dream. Let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

Growing Good Corn, Author Unknown

There once was a farmer who grew award-winning corn. Each year he entered his corn in the state fair where it won a blue ribbon.

One year a newspaper reporter interviewed him and learned something interesting about how he grew it. The reporter discovered that the farmer shared his seed corn with his neighbors.

“How can you afford to share your best seed corn with your neighbors when they are entering corn in competition with yours each year?” the reporter asked.

“Why sir,” said the farmer,” didn’t you know? The wind picks up pollen from the ripening corn and swirls it from field to field. If my neighbors grow inferior corn, cross-pollination will steadily degrade the quality of my corn. If I am to grow good corn, I must help my neighbors grow good corn.”

He is very much aware of the connectedness of life. His corn cannot improve unless his neighbor’s corn also improves.

So it is with our lives. Those who choose to live in peace must help their neighbors to live in peace. Those who choose to live well must help others to live well, for the value of a life is measured by the lives it touches. And those who choose to be happy must help others to find happiness, for the welfare of each is bound up with the welfare of all.

The lesson for each of us is this: if we are to grow good corn, we must help our neighbors grow good corn. 

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“Success is almost totally dependent upon drive and persistence. The extra energy required to make another effort or try another approach is the secret of winning.” - Denis Waitley

“The most interesting thing about a postage stamp is the persistence with which it sticks to its job.” - Napoleon Hill

“Success is not a matter of mastering subtle, sophisticated theory but rather of embracing common sense with uncommon levels of discipline and persistence.” - Patrick Lencioni

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionalswww.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com623-362-3000consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message - You are invited to see Rock Thomas!</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-you-are-invited-to-see-rock-thomas.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-24 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Nate’s Monday Morning Message



Welcome to this week’s edition of Nate’s Monday Message! Today I am excited to personally invite you to a special event we are hosting on Wednesday with self-made millionaire and motivational speaker, Rock Thomas. I have known Rock for a few years now, and it is a privilege to have him share his is Sunday System for Success (this presentation is valued at $297.00 per ticket). He’s run several successful businesses, six award-winning RE/MAX franchises, sold countless best-selling books and created life-changing programs that help people turn ideas into action and action into success. 

You don’t have to be in real estate to benefit from his presentation, meaning that this invitation is open to anyone who is committed to self-mastery, so please share it with your friends and family!

We will be providing lunch and everyone who attends will receive a planner which is valued at $39.00. You can register to attend by clicking here. I hope you will join us on Wednesday, March 27th at 11am! Let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

THE BEAUTY OF MATHEMATICS

BE sure to read to the END…Just the math part is good enough, the end is even better. 

1 x 8 + 1 = 9 12 x 8 + 2 = 98 123 x 8 + 3 = 987 1234 x 8 + 4 = 9876 12345 x 8 + 5 = 98765 123456 x 8 + 6 = 987654 1234567 x 8 + 7 = 9876543 12345678 x 8 + 8 = 98765432 123456789 x 8 + 9 = 987654321  

1 x 9 + 2 = 11 12 x 9 + 3 = 111 123 x 9 + 4 = 1111 1234 x 9 + 5 = 11111 12345 x 9 + 6 = 111111 123456 x 9 + 7 = 1111111 1234567 x 9 + 8 = 11111111 12345678 x 9 + 9 = 111111111 123456789 x 9 +10= 1111111111  

9 x 9 + 7 = 88 98 x 9 + 6 = 888 987 x 9 + 5 = 8888 9876 x 9 + 4 = 88888 98765 x 9 + 3 = 888888 987654 x 9 + 2 = 8888888 9876543 x 9 + 1 = 88888888 98765432 x 9 + 0 = 888888888  

1 x 1 = 1 11 x 11 = 121 111 x 111 = 12321 1111 x 1111 = 1234321 11111 x 11111 = 123454321 111111 x 111111 = 12345654321 1111111 x 1111111 = 1234567654321 11111111 x 11111111 = 123456787654321 111111111 x 111111111 = 12345678987654321  

Mind Boggling… Now, take a look at this… 

From a strictly mathematical viewpoint: What Equals 100%? What does it mean to give MORE than 100%?  

Here’s a little mathematical formula that might help answer these questions:  

If: A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z  Is represented as: 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26.  

Then: H-A-R-D-W-O- R- K  8+1+18+4+23+15+18+11 = 98% 

And: K-N-O-W-L-E- D-G-E 11+14+15+23+12+5+4+7+ 5 = 96% 

But: A-T-T-I-T-U- D-E 1+20+20+9+20+ 21+4+5 = 100% 

Attitude Matters!!! 

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“Only one who devotes himself to a cause with his whole strength and soul can be a true master. For this reason, mastery demands all of a person.” Albert Einstein

“Your attitude, not your aptitude, will determine your altitude.” - Zig Ziglar

“I fear not the man who has practiced 10,000 kicks once, but I fear the man who has practiced one kick 10,000 times.” - Bruce Lee
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Nate’s Monday Morning Message

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Nate’s Monday Morning Message

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message March 18, 2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-march-18-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-17 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Welcome to this week’s edition of Nate’s Monday Message…I am going to keep this email short and sweet this week! We are almost through the first quarter of 2019. How are you doing with your goals? Are you working a plan to achieve them? We’ve got to work a little harder than the competition, innovate, create and then level up. But remember to smile and have fun, be caring and compassionate, and make a difference. Let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

Just for Today! Written by Sybyl F Partridge in 1916 and printed in “How to Stop Worrying, And Start Living” by Dale Carnegie, 1951


  
    Just for today I will be happy.  This assumes that what Abraham Lincoln said is true, that “most folks are about as happy as they make up their minds to be.” Happiness is from within; it is not a matter of externals.
  
  
    Just for today I will try to adjust myself to what is, and not try to adjust everything to my own desires. I will take my family, my business, and my luck as they come and fit myself to them.
  
  
    Just for today I will take care of my body. I will exercise it, care for it, nourish it, not abuse nor neglect it, so that it will be a perfect machine for my bidding.
  
  
    Just for today I will try to strengthen my mind. I will learn something useful. I will not be a mental loafer. I will read something that requires effort, thought and concentration.
  
  
    Just for today I will exercise my soul in three ways; I will do somebody a good turn and not get found out. I will do at least two things I don’t want to do as William James suggests, just for exercise.
  
  
    Just for today I will be agreeable. I will look as well as I can, dress as becomingly as possible, talk low, act courteously, be liberal with praise, criticize not at all, nor fault with anything and not try to regulate nor improve anyone.
  
  
    Just for today I will try to live through this day only, not to tackle my whole life problem at once.  I can do things for twelve hours that would appall me if I had to keep them up for a lifetime.
  
  
    Just for today I will have a program. I will write down what I expect to do every hour.  I may not follow it exactly, but I will have it.  It will eliminate two pests, hurry and indecision.
  
  
    Just for today I will have a quiet half hour all by myself and relax. In this half hour sometimes I will think of God, so as to get a little more perspective into my life.
  
  
    Just for today I will be unafraid, especially I will not be afraid to be happy, to enjoy what is beautiful, to love, and to believe that those I love, love me.
  


If we want to develop a mental attitude that will bring us peace and happiness, here is rule # 1: Think and act cheerfully, and you will feel cheerful.

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“Setting goals is the first step in turning the invisible into the visible.” - Tony Robbins

“What you get by achieving your goals is not as important as what you become by achieving your goals.” - Zig Ziglar

“People with goals succeed because they know where they’re going.” - Earl Nightingale

“If you go to work on your goals, your goals will go to work on you. If you go to work on your plan, your plan will go to work on you. Whatever good things we build end up building us.” - Jim Rohn

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionalswww.joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com623-362-3000consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message March 11, 2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-march-11-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-10 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Nate’s Monday Morning Message



Welcome to this week’s edition of Nate’s Monday Message! I trust that each of you reading this had a wonderful weekend, filled with enjoyment and memories made. Today, I want to talk to you about fairness and understanding. Many of us heard as children that “life just is not fair.” I am not sure that I agree, because you see life is what you make of it, and fairness is subjective. We all know people who are deliberate, thoughtful, and fair. We also know people who are non-deliberate, non-thoughtful and not very fair.

I would encourage you to take a look at yourself and ask if you are deliberate, thoughtful, and fair. Regardless of what life has done for you up until today, the future is a clean canvas and you are the painter. Make wise choices and be fair and understanding. Life will bring back to you what you give to others. Let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

TEAMWORK by Katrina Losta 

Concentrate 10% on lack of communication…And 90% in being PART OF ESTABLISHING IT. 

Concentrate 10% on un-professionalism…And 90% on LEADING BY EXAMPLE.

Concentrate 10% on someone else’s weakness…And 90% on IMPROVING YOUR OWN.

Concentrate 10% on accusations…And 90% on GETTING THE FACTS. 

Concentrate 10% on lack of training…And 90% on HOW TO OBTAIN IT. 

Concentrate 10% on complaining…And 90% on COMPLIMENTING. 

Concentrate 10% on flaws in the system…And 90% on BEING PART OF IMPROVING THEM. 

Concentrate 10% on constructive criticism…And 90% on LEARNING FROM IT. 

Concentrate 10% on others…And 90% on YOURSELF. 

Concentrate 10% on fear of making a mistake…And 90% on ACHIEVING SUCCESS.

Concentrate 10% on watching the clock…And 90% on PRODUCTIVITY! 

Concentrate 10% on conflict…And 90% on RESOLUTION. 

Concentrate 10% on what you want to be…And 90% on HOW TO GET THERE!

Concentrate 10% on obstacles…And 90% on PERSEVERANCE AND VICTORY!

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“I think for any relationship to be successful, there needs to be loving communication, appreciation, and understanding.” - Miranda Kerr

“I think perfect objectivity is an unrealistic goal; fairness, however, is not.” - Michael Pollan

“Beginning today, treat everyone you meet as if they were going to be dead by midnight. Extend to them all the care, kindness and understanding you can muster, and do it with no thought of any reward. Your life will never be the same again.” - Og Mandino

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals602-430-5226consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Nate’s Monday Morning Message

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Nate’s Monday Morning Message

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Brady Bosworth Joined RE/MAX Professionals</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/why-brady-bosworth-joined-remax-professionals-copy.html</link>
        
          <category>RE/MAX Professionals</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-05 15:53:02 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2019/Interview+With+Brady+Bosworth.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Why do agents join RE/MAX Professionals? Today I’m interviewing fellow agent Brady Bosworth to help answer that question.

Today I’m sitting down with fellow RE/MAX agent Brady Bosworth to talk about his career as an agent, why he joined RE/MAX Professionals, and how this decision has benefited his business moving forward. 

For your convenience, I’ve provided timestamps of our conversation in the video above so that you can jump ahead to the section(s) that interest you the most:

0:22—Some background on Brady’s career  5:05—Why he joined RE/MAX Professionals a little over a year ago7:47—The success he’s enjoyed because of this switch9:11—How he met his last client11:08—What he does for fun outside of real estate12:49—The best vacation he’s ever had 13:43—What’s on his travel bucket list 15:03—His business goals for 2019 1615—The assistance he’s gotten from other RE/MAX agents17:36—Why RE/MAX looks for learning-based individuals18:25—The value of our training classes 19:19—The type of mindset we encourage 20:26—What a solo agent can gain from joining RE/MAX22:38—Why Brady chose real estate 23:53—A recent transaction that’s symbolic of what RE/MAX is all about 25:54—Wrapping things up 

As always, if you have any questions or there’s anything I can help you with, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2019/Interview+With+Brady+Bosworth.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2019/Interview+With+Brady+Bosworth.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Why do agents join RE/MAX Professionals? Today I’m interviewing fellow agent Brady Bosworth to help answer that question.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Why do agents join RE/MAX Professionals? Today I’m interviewing fellow agent Brady Bosworth to help answer that question.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message March 4, 2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-march-4-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-03 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Nate’s Monday Morning Message

Welcome to this week’s edition of Nate’s Monday Message! We spend a lot of time thinking about all the things we need to fix or improve in our lives. However, what amount of time do we spend being proud of what we have accomplished so far, or feeling thankful for the blessings we currently have? Let us focus some of our attention on those items this week and every week going forward. True, we must work hard, but we also need to look at how far we’ve come, and smile. Life is a journey of experiences! Let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

My Dog Can Walk on Water

There was a hunter who came into the possession of a special bird dog. The dog was the only one of its kind, because it can walk on water. One day he invited a friend to go hunting with him so that he could show off his prized possession. After some time, they shot a few ducks, which fell into the river. The man ordered his dog to run and fetch the birds. The dog ran on water to fetch the birds. The man was expecting a compliment about the amazing dog but did not receive it. Being curious, he asked his friend if the friend had noticed anything unusual about the dog. The friend replied, “Yes, I did see something unusual about your dog. Your dog can’t swim!”

Moral of the story: More than 90 percent of the people that we face every day are negative. They choose to look at the hole in the middle rather than the doughnut. Do not expect compliments or encouragement from them. These are the people who cannot pull you out of your present situation. They can only push you down. So be aware of them, spend less time with them, and do not let them steal your dreams away from you.

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“Appreciation is a wonderful thing: It makes what is excellent in others belong to us as well.” - Voltaire

“A healthy attitude is contagious but don’t wait to catch it from others. Be a carrier.” - Tom Stoppard

“When I started counting my blessings, my whole life turned around.” - Willie Nelson

“Gratitude unlocks the fullness of life. It turns what we have into enough, and more. It turns denial into acceptance, chaos to order, confusion to clarity. It can turn a meal into a feast, a house into a home, a stranger into a friend.” - Melody Beattie

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals623-362-3000consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message Feb. 25, 2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-feb-25-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-24 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Nate’s Monday Morning Message

Welcome to this edition of Nate’s Monday Message! Are you prepared for the success that you are about to have? This is one of the biggest things that holds people back from success: the fear of success itself. But did you know that fear has the same physical emotion in the body as extreme excitement? It is all in how we label what we feel. Fear merely stands for: false evidence appearing real. Be prepared for the success you have working towards, and it is more likely to happen. Put yourself in a position to succeed in all aspects of your life daily. Let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

Just BE THANKFUL 

Be thankful that you don’t already have everything you desire. If you did, what would there be to look forward to? Be thankful when you don’t know something, for it gives you the opportunity to learn new things. Be thankful for the difficult times. Those are the times you grow. Be thankful for your limitations, because they give you opportunities for improvement. Be thankful for your mistakes. They will teach you valuable lessons for the future. 

Be thankful when you are tired and weary, because it means you’ve made a difference. It’s easy to be thankful for the good things. A life of rich fulfillment comes to those who are also thankful for the setbacks and bumpy times. Find a way to be thankful for your troubles, and they can become your blessings. 

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“Success is no accident. It is hard work, perseverance, learning, studying, sacrifice and most of all, love of what you are doing or learning to do.”- Pele

“If you want to conquer fear, don’t sit home and think about it. Go out and get busy.” - Dale Carnegie

“Without continual growth and progress, such words as improvement, achievement, and success have no meaning.” - Benjamin Franklin

“The only thing we have to fear is fear itself.” - Franklin D. Roosevelt

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionalsconsult@rmxprofessionals.com623-362-3000
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Tracking Your Leads Can Save You Money</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-tracking-your-leads-can-save-you-money.html</link>
        
          <category>Lead Conversion</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-19 12:18:33 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2019/Feb+1+Recruiting.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I want to give you my professional advice about how to track your leads.

At one point in my 33-year career, I used to only track where my closings came from. But about two years ago, I was introduced to tracking every lead—how it comes in, the source, and our conversion rate. Let me give you an example:

You do an open house and you get five leads. You add the five leads to the tracker, including their name, address, phone number, and you include the source (the open house, in this case). Additionally, if they give you the information that they’re interested in buying or selling, you’ll want to categorize them in the tracker accordingly.

On our lead-tracking spreadsheet, we have all that information recorded, plus, the first contact date with the lead, the next contact date scheduled with them, and also the value of that lead—for example, a buyer looking to purchase in the $300,000 price range. From there, we can calculate a $9,000 projected commission.

Looking at my 2018 tracker, I notice that we had 213 leads come in, 45 of which came in with an income potential of $912,000. My leads had an average of $20,000 in potential income per lead.

“Knowing exactly how much return you get on your leads and their sources is vital.”

By tracking our leads, I’ve found that we’re able to save money and/or move our money away from something that isn’t giving us the conversion we’re looking for and put it towards something with a higher conversion. Last year, we underwent 10 months of parallel tracking for two different high-cost marketing for internet leads. 

For example, after tracking Zillow and a pay-per-click service, we found that one of those was producing three times the amount of revenue as the other. Because we could see that, we stopped paying money for one and then doubled down on the one that was working. Don’t be afraid to stop investing in something that isn’t working because you’re afraid of losing a possible lead that will come in. Knowing exactly how much return you get on your leads and their sources is vital, no matter if you’re running a team or if you’re working as an individual.

Here are some other interesting facts our tracker also tells me about our 2018 business:


  11% came from agent and client referrals
  22% was tracked all the way to close
  26% came from open houses
  9% came from Zillow
  4% came from sign calls
  5% came from our sphere of influence


At the end of the day, we know exactly where all our leads are coming from. I challenge you to start tracking each and every one of your own leads so that you can identify which sources are worth investing in.

If you have any questions about lead tracking, feel free to reach out to me. I’d be happy to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2019/Feb+1+Recruiting.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2019/Feb+1+Recruiting.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I want to give you my professional advice about how to track your leads.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I want to give you my professional advice about how to track your leads.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message Feb. 18, 2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-feb-18-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-17 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Welcome to this edition of Nate’s Monday Message…Happy President’s Day! There are many things in life that we have control over, and many things that we do not. But most importantly, we have choices and we get to choose to start each day with the proper mindset. We get to choose our own actions, and what we will do or not do today. You can’t control others, but you can choose how you interact with them. You can’t control the outcome, but you can choose how you react to it. This week, make it a point to focus on your choices, and you will find that you have more control that you realize. Let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

Yesterday, Today and Tomorrow - Author Unknown

There are two days in every week about which we should not worry. Two days which should be kept free from fear and apprehension.One of these days is yesterday with its mistakes and cares,Its faults and blunders, Its aches and pains.Yesterday has passed forever beyond our control.All the money in the world cannot bring back yesterday.We cannot undo a single act we performed.We cannot erase a single word we said. Yesterday is gone.The other day we should not worry about is tomorrow.With its possible adversities, its burdens, Its large promise and poor performance.Tomorrow is also beyond our immediate control.Tomorrow’s Sun will rise, either in splendor or behind a mask of clouds, but it will rise.Until it does, we have no stake in tomorrow, for it is yet unborn.This just leaves only one day . . . Today.Any person can fight the battles of just one day.It is only when you and I add the burdens of those two awful eternity’s - yesterday and tomorrow that we break down.It is not the experience of today that drives people mad.It is the remorse or bitterness for something which happened yesterday and the dread of what tomorrow may bring.Let us therefore live but one day at a time.

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“Success is not final, failure is not fatal: it is the courage to continue that counts.” - Winston Churchill

“Always be yourself, express yourself, have faith in yourself, do not go out and look for a successful personality and duplicate it.” - Bruce Lee

“Every day brings new choices.” - Martha Beck

“Today I choose life. Every morning when I wake up, I can choose joy, happiness, negativity, pain… To feel the freedom that comes from being able to continue to make mistakes and choices - today I choose to feel life, not to deny my humanity but embrace it.” - Kevyn Aucoin

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionalsconsult@rmxprofessionals.com623-362-3000
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to RE/MAX Professionals Jim Culleton</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/welcome-to-remax-professionals-jim-culleton.html</link>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-12 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Welcome to RE/MAX Professionals Jim Culleton

Please help us welcome Jim to our Arrowhead North office location!



RE/MAX Professionals623-362-3000consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Welcome to RE/MAX Professionals Jim Culleton

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Welcome to RE/MAX Professionals Jim Culleton

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message - Happy Valentine's Day</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-happy-valentines-day.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-10 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Welcome to this edition of Nate’s Monday Message…Love is in the air as the day for lovers is just around the corner! Whether you are in a committed relationship, or still search for the “one” Valentine’s Day is a day to celebrate what love truly means. It isn’t about the flowers or the chocolates, but more importantly about an expression of our emotions for those we hold near and dear, beyond a romantic relationship. I hope you will take a moment this week to say “I love you” to those who need to hear. I want to wish each of you reading this email a very happy Valentine’s Day! Let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

A ValentinePoet: Catherine Pulsifer, © 2016 Let me say this Valentines quoteIs one that I wish I wrote It tells of love that is so deepIt is one that I will always keep.It reminds me so much of youI will read it over when I’m blue.It was written by John McLeod,And I would encourage you to read aloud:“Love much dear friends for love will bringthe healing joy and hope of Spring.” 

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“If you have only one smile in you give it to the people you love.” - Maya Angelou

“For it was not into my ear you whispered, but into my heart. It was not my lips you kissed, but my soul.” - Judy Garland

“Doubt thou the stars are fire, Doubt that the sun doth move. Doubt truth to be a liar, But never doubt I love.” - William Shakespeare

“The heart has its reasons of which reason knows nothing.” - Blaise Pascal

“We are most alive when we’re in love.” - John Updike

P.S. You are invited to a special 3-hour Business Planning Workshop that I am hosting tomorrow, February 12th from 3:30pm to 6:30pm. Tacos and margaritas included! Click here to secure your seat. 

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionalsconsult@rmxprofessionals.com623-362-3000
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to RE/MAX Professionals Gia Katz</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/welcome-to-remax-professionals-gia-katz.html</link>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-05 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Please help us welcome Gia to the RE/MAX Professionals’ family!



RE/MAX Professionals623-362-3000consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Please help us welcome Gia to the RE/MAX Professionals’ family!

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Please help us welcome Gia to the RE/MAX Professionals’ family!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Monday Morning Message 2.4.2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/monday-morning-message-2-4-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-27 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Nate’s Monday Morning Message

Welcome to this edition of Nate’s Monday Message! The weather has been a little unusual for the Valley of the Sun this winter, and this week brings us more rain and cooler temps. There is one thing for certain though, and that is seasons always change and the sun will always rise - in our lives and our businesses.

Are you prepared to make the most out of this week? Are you organized; determined; motivated; and just all around ready to succeed? Take a few minutes today to sit quietly and gather your thoughts. What are the five things you must do this week to be a success? What are the five things you must not do this week to be a success? Write them down and keep them with you. We must be prepared to succeed. Let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

Everything Happens for The Good  

There was once a King who had a wise adviser. The adviser followed the King everywhere, and his favorite advice was, “everything happens for the good.” One day the King went hunting and had a little accident. He shot an arrow at his own foot and was injured. He asked the adviser what he thought about the accident, to which the adviser replied, “Everything happens for the good.” This time the King was really upset and ordered for his adviser to be put in prison. The King asked his adviser, “Now, what do you think?” The adviser again replied, “Everything happens for the good.” So, the adviser remained in prison. 

The King later went on a hunting trip, this time without the adviser. The King was then captured by some cannibals. He was taken to the cannibals’ camp where he was to be the evening meal for the cannibals. Before putting him into the cooking pot he was thoroughly inspected. The cannibals saw the wound on the King’s foot and decided to throw him back into the jungle. According to the cannibals’ tradition, they would not eat anything that was imperfect. As a result, the King was spared. The King suddenly realized what his adviser said was true. The adviser also escaped death because had he not been in prison, he would have followed the King on the hunting trip and would have ended up in the cooking pot. 

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“The roots of all goodness lie in the soil of appreciation for goodness.” - Dalai Lama

“If you don’t like something, change it. If you can’t change it, change your attitude.” - Maya Angelou

“Success is no accident. It is hard work, perseverance, learning, studying, sacrifice and most of all, love of what you are doing or learning to do.” – Pele

“People may hear your words, but they feel your attitude.” - John C. Maxwell

Nate Martinez,RE/MAX Professionals602-430-5226natem@remax.netconsult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Monday Morning Message 1.28.2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/monday-morning-message-1-28-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-27 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Welcome to this edition of Nate’s Monday Message! I hope you all had a fantastic weekend and were able to spend quality time with your family and friends. We all work hard, and we are often times so dedicated to our careers that we forget to enjoy the little things. We need to find time every day, every week to celebrate the small things that make a difference both at work and at home. Let us remember that we don’t live to work, but rather work to live!

This week, let’s commit to our family and friends; to the people we love. If we don’t make them a priority, then what is it that we are working towards? Priorities are the people and things we place value on. What are yours? Decide. Commit. Then do. Let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

It’s Up to YouAuthor - unknown

One song can spark a moment,One flower can wake the dream.One tree can start a forest,One bird can herald spring.One smile begins a friendship,One handclasp lifts a soul.One star can guide a ship at sea,One word can frame the goal.One vote can change a nation,One sunbeam lights a room.One candle wipes out darkness,One laugh will conquer gloom.One step must start each journey,One word must start each prayer.One hope will raise our spirits,One touch can show you care.One voice can speak with wisdom,One heart can know what’s true.One life can make the difference,You see, IT’S UP TO YOU!

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“Learn to enjoy every minute of your life. Be happy now. Don’t wait for something outside of yourself to make you happy in the future. Think how really precious is the time you have to spend, whether it’s at work or with your family. Every minute should be enjoyed and savored.” - Earl Nightingale

“Family and friendships are two of the greatest facilitators of happiness.” - John C. Maxwell

“To enjoy good health, to bring true happiness to one’s family, to bring peace to all, one must first discipline and control one’s own mind. If a man can control his mind he can find the way to Enlightenment, and all wisdom and virtue will naturally come to him.” - Buddha

PS You are invited to a 3 hour Business Planning Event I am hosting on Tuesday, February 12th from 3:30-6:30pm. Come for the tacos and margaritas and kick start your 2019 selling season! Click here to save your seat today!

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionalswww.NatesHomes.comwww.NatesLuxuryHomes.com602-430-5226Nate@NatesHomes.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to RE/MAX Professionals William Collins</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/welcome-to-remax-professionals-william-collins.html</link>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-22 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Please help us welcome William Collins to RE/MAX Professionals. He will be working out of our Avondale, Arizona office location. Welcome William!



RE/MAX Professionals623-362-3000
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Please help us welcome William Collins to RE/MAX Professionals. He will be working out of our Avondale, Arizona office location. Welcome William!

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Please help us welcome William Collins to RE/MAX Professionals. He will be working out of our Avondale, Arizona office location. Welcome William!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to RE/MAX Professionals Paul Newell</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/welcome-to-remax-professionals-paul-newell.html</link>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-22 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Please help us welcome Paul Newell to RE/MAX Professionals. He will be working out of our Glendale, Arizona office location. Welcome Paul!



RE/MAX Professionals623-362-3000
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Please help us welcome Paul Newell to RE/MAX Professionals. He will be working out of our Glendale, Arizona office location. Welcome Paul!

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Please help us welcome Paul Newell to RE/MAX Professionals. He will be working out of our Glendale, Arizona office location. Welcome Paul!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to RE/MAX Professionals Lynda Eckols</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/welcome-to-remax-professionals-lynda-eckols.html</link>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-22 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Please help us welcome Lynda Eckols to RE/MAX Professionals. She will be working out of our Glendale, Arizona office location. Welcome Lynda!



RE/MAX Professionals623-362-3000
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Please help us welcome Lynda Eckols to RE/MAX Professionals. She will be working out of our Glendale, Arizona office location. Welcome Lynda!

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Please help us welcome Lynda Eckols to RE/MAX Professionals. She will be working out of our Glendale, Arizona office location. Welcome Lynda!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to RE/MAX Professionals Diana Koistinen</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/welcome-to-remax-professionals-diana-koistinen.html</link>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-22 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Please help us welcome Diana Koistinen to RE/MAX Professionals. She will be working out of our Avondale, Arizona office location with the Bourland Team. Welcome Diana!



RE/MAX Professionals623-362-3000
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Please help us welcome Diana Koistinen to RE/MAX Professionals. She will be working out of our Avondale, Arizona office location with the Bourland Team. Welcome Diana!

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Please help us welcome Diana Koistinen to RE/MAX Professionals. She will be working out of our Avondale, Arizona office location with the Bourland Team. Welcome Diana!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to RE/MAX Professionals Arnelly Castejon</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/welcome-to-remax-professionals-arnelly-castejon.html</link>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-22 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Please help us welcome Arnelly Castejon to RE/MAX Professionals. She will be working out of our Avondale, Arizona office location with Team Colato. Welcome Arnelly!



RE/MAX Professionals623-362-3000
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Please help us welcome Arnelly Castejon to RE/MAX Professionals. She will be working out of our Avondale, Arizona office location with Team Colato. Welcome Arnelly!

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Please help us welcome Arnelly Castejon to RE/MAX Professionals. She will be working out of our Avondale, Arizona office location with Team Colato. Welcome Arnelly!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>RE/MAX Professionals 2018 Award Winners</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/remax-professionals-2018-award-winners.html</link>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-22 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>We want to say CONGRATULATIONS to all these incredible RE/MAX Professionals’ agents who had an outstanding 2018. Congratulations on your success, and thank you for your dedication and hard work!!!



RE/MAX Professionals623-362-3000consult@rmxprofessionals.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We want to say CONGRATULATIONS to all these incredible RE/MAX Professionals’ agents who had an outstanding 2018. Congratulations on your success, and thank you for your dedication and hard work!!!

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We want to say CONGRATULATIONS to all these incredible RE/MAX Professionals’ agents who had an outstanding 2018. Congratulations on your success, and thank you for your dedication and hard work!!!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message 1.21.19</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message-1-21-19.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-20 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Welcome to this edition of Nate’s Monday Message. Today I want to honor the memory of Martin Luther King, Jr. by sharing with you a part of his I have a dream speech from August 1963. It doesn’t take an extraordinary person to make history; it just takes a dream. Let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

Martin Luther King’s I have a dream speech August 28, 1963

I say to you today, my friends, so even though we face the difficulties of today and tomorrow, I still have a dream. It is a dream deeply rooted in the American dream.

I have a dream that one day this nation will rise up and live out the true meaning of its creed: “We hold these truths to be self-evident; that all men are created equal.”

I have a dream that one day on the red hills of Georgia the sons of former slaves and the sons of former slave owners will be able to sit down together at the table of brotherhood.

I have a dream that one day even the state of Mississippi, a state sweltering with the heat of injustice, sweltering with the heat of oppression, will be transformed into an oasis of freedom and justice.

I have a dream that my four little children will one day live in a nation where they will not be judged by the color of their skin but by the content of their character.

I have a dream today.

I have a dream that one day down in Alabama, with its vicious racists, with its governor having his lips dripping with the words of interposition and nullification, that one day right down in Alabama little black boys and black girls will be able to join hands with little white boys and white girls as sisters and brothers.

I have a dream today.

I have a dream that one day every valley shall be exhalted, every hill and mountain shall be made low, the rough places will be made plain, and the crooked places will be made straight, and the glory of the Lord shall be revealed, and all flesh shall see it together.

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“Darkness cannot drive out darkness; only light can do that. Hate cannot drive out hate; only love can do that.” - Martin Luther King, Jr.

“Faith is taking the first step even when you don’t see the whole staircase.” - Martin Luther King, Jr.

“The ultimate measure of a man is not where he stands in moments of comfort and convenience, but where he stands at times of challenge and controversy.” - Martin Luther King, Jr. 

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionalswww.NatesHomes.comwww.NatesLuxuryHomes.com602-430-5226Nate@NatesHomes.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Monday Morning Message 1.14.2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/monday-morning-message-1-14-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-13 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Welcome to this edition of Nate’s Monday Message. I had the pleasure of hearing author Mark Sanborn speak this last week at the Leverage ’19 real estate event in Scottsdale. He talked about an acronym he developed to help us stay on track with our goals. I want to share that with you today…

F.I.T. which stands for frequency, intensity and technique.

Successful people do the things that they need to do to produce the results every single day (frequency). They also give 110% of their effort (intensity) and they use the right technique. The definition of insanity is doing the same over and over again and expecting a different result. Focusing on the right technique is vital, combined with frequency and intensity. F.I.T. can be applied to anything you want to accomplish, including that list of New Year’s Resolutions you wrote down such as losing weight, saving more money or spending more time with family and friends. How can you apply F.I.T. to your life? Let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

Focus: The 5%/95% Rule

Focus 5% on what you fear 95% on getting educated and skilled to face it.  

Focus 5% on the problem 95% on the healthiest solution.  

Focus 5% on the mistake 95% on learning from it.  

Focus 5% on who to blame 95% on making sure to heal.  

Focus 5% on what you must do 95% on enjoying the process of it.  

Focus 5% on the conflict 95% on the win-win-win resolution.  

Focus 5% on what you can’t control 95% on what you do have control over.  

Focus 5% on what others say 95% on what you believe.  

Focus 5% on what you have 95% on what you want to have.  

Focus 5% on reading this 95% on applying it.

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“Successful people maintain a positive focus in life no matter what is going on around them. They stay focused on their past successes rather than their past failures, and on the next action steps they need to take to get them closer to the fulfillment of their goals rather than all the other distractions that life presents to them.” - Jack Canfield

“I don’t focus on what I’m up against. I focus on my goals and I try to ignore the rest.” - Venus Williams

“Give yourself a gift of five minutes of contemplation in awe of everything you see around you. Go outside and turn your attention to the many miracles around you. This five-minute-a-day regimen of appreciation and gratitude will help you to focus your life in awe.” - Wayne Dyer

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionalswww.NatesHomes.comwww.NatesLuxuryHomes.com602-430-5226Nate@NatesHomes.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Monday Morning Message</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/monday-morning-message.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-06 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Welcome to the first Monday Morning Message on 2019! Let’s talk about resolutions and what is important for the New Year. Have you taken time to really think about what it is that you truly desire? How did you get to where you are today? The vast majority of people wake-up every day and go through the motions of what they have to do, and not necessarily what they want to do.

I would like to challenge you this year to live a more purposeful life; to be conscious of all the decisions you make (or don’t make). The only difference between you and the those who are living life on purpose is how you decide to spend your time. Let us resolve for 2019, to put the things that matter most, first. Let us resolve today that we will not let another week, or another year, go by without us taking full control and responsibility for all of our actions. Let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

Beginning Today (Author Unknown)

Beginning today I will no longer worry about yesterday.It is in the past and the past will never change.Only I can change by choosing to do so.

Beginning today I will no longer worry about tomorrow.Tomorrow will always be there, waiting for me to make the most of it.But I cannot make the most of tomorrow without firstmaking the most of today.

Beginning today I will look in the mirror and I will see a person worthy of my respect and admiration. This capable person looking back at me is someone I enjoy spending timewith and someone I would like to get to know better.

Beginning today I will cherish each moment of my life.I value this gift bestowed upon me in this world and I will unselfishlyshare this gift with others. I will use this gift to enhance the lives of others.

Beginning today I will take a moment to step off the beaten path and torevel in the mysteries I encounter.I will face challenges with courage and determination.I will overcome what barriers there may be which hinder my quest for growth and self-improvement.

Beginning today I will take life one day at a time, one step at a time.Discouragement will not be allowed to taint my positive self-image,my desire to succeed or my capacity to love.

Beginning today I walk with renewed faith in human kindness.Regardless of what has gone before, I believe there is hopefor a brighter and better future.

Beginning today I will open my mind and my heart.I will welcome new experiences. I will meet new people.I will not expect perfection from myself nor anyone else: perfection does not exist in an imperfect world.But I will applaud the attempt to overcome human foibles.

Beginning today I am responsible for my own happiness and I will do things that make me happy . . .admire the beautiful wonders of nature, listen to my favorite music,pet a kitten or a puppy, soak in a bubble bath . . .pleasure can be found in the most simple of gestures.

Beginning today I will learn something new; I will try something different; I will savor all the various flavors life has to offer.I will change what I can and the rest I will let go.I will strive to become the best me I can possibly be.

Beginning today. And every day.

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

“If you don’t like something, change it. If you can’t change it, change your attitude.” - Maya Angelou

“Learn to enjoy every minute of your life. Be happy now. Don’t wait for something outside of yourself to make you happy in the future. Think how really precious is the time you have to spend, whether it’s at work or with your family. Every minute should be enjoyed and savored.” - Earl Nightingale

“The past cannot be changed. The future is yet in your power.” - Unknown

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionalswww.NatesHomes.comwww.NatesLuxuryHomes.com602-430-5226Nate@NatesHomes.com
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>RE/MAX Professionals Insider Newsletter January 2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/remax-professionals-insider-newsletter-january-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate Martinez</category>
        
          <category>RE/MAX Professionals</category>
        
          <category>Arizona</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-31 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>















RE/MAX Professionals20241 N 67th Ave, Suite A1Glendale, Arizona 85308623-362-3000
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nate's Monday Morning Message</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nates-monday-morning-message.html</link>
        
          <category>Nate's Monday Morning Message</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-31 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Welcome to this week’s Monday Morning Message…it’s the last day of 2018, which means there is still a small window of time to mark off your list, hit that final goal or connect with a long-lost friend or family member. As we close the chapter on another year, I wanted to share the lyrics to Elton John’s song The Circle of Life, which is perfect timing for today’s message. Let’s welcome the New Year by celebrating the circle… and miracle of life! Let’s make it a great week!

ENCOURAGEMENT CORNER

The Circle of Life (Music by Elton John, Lyrics by Tim Rice, From the soundtrack of “The Lion King”)

From the day we arrive on the planetAnd blinking, step into the sunThere’s more to see than can ever be seenMore to do than can ever be done

There’s far too much to take in hereMore to find than can ever be foundBut the sun rolling highThrough the sapphire skyKeeps great and small on the endless round

It’s the circle of lifeAnd it moves us allThrough despair and hopeThrough faith and love

Till we find our placeOn the path unwindingIn the circleThe circle of life

It’s the circle of lifeAnd it moves us allThrough despair and hopeThrough faith and love

Till we find our placeOn the path unwindingIn the circleThe circle of life

WORDS OF INSPIRATION

The new year stands before us, like a chapter in a book, waiting to be written. We can help write that story by setting goals. Melody Beattie

And now we welcome the new year. Full of things that have never been. Rainer Maria Rilke

Cheers to a new year and another chance for us to get it right. Oprah Winfrey

Nate Martinez, RE/MAX Professionals602-430-5226NateM@remax.net
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Welcome to this week’s Monday Morning Message…it’s the last day of 2018, which means there is still a small window of time to mark off your list, hit that final goal or connect with a long-lost friend or family member. As we close the chapter on another year, I wanted to share the lyrics to Elton John’s song The Circle of Life, which is perfect timing for today’s message. Let’s welcome the New Year by celebrating the circle… and miracle of life! Let’s make it a great week!

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Welcome to this week’s Monday Morning Message…it’s the last day of 2018, which means there is still a small window of time to mark off your list, hit that final goal or connect with a long-lost friend or family member. As we close the chapter on another year, I wanted to share the lyrics to Elton John’s song The Circle of Life, which is perfect timing for today’s message. Let’s welcome the New Year by celebrating the circle… and miracle of life! Let’s make it a great week!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Create a Business Plan for 2019</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-to-create-a-business-plan-for-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Reviews and Referral System</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-25 19:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/How+to+Create+a+Business+Plan+for+2019.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Creating a business plan will ensure you meet your goals. Here’s how.

I’ve talked before about the success cycle, and today we’ll be using an aspect of that cycle in our discussion on business plans: clarity. Clarity helps you know exactly what goals you want to achieve, and creating a business plan is the best way to achieve your goals.

When writing a business plan, there are a few things I recommend you do. First, do a SWOT analysis, which is essentially a self-examination of your own strengths, weaknesses, opportunities, and threats. Jot down these categories on a piece of paper and make a list for each one. You can ask others, such as loved ones or even real estate professionals, to do a SWOT analysis on you as well. This is a good way to find out things from another perspective (things you may not have admitted to yourself). 

After you have a good list from your SWOT analysis, also think about including a marketing plan for the full 12 months of 2019. In my almost 33 years in real estate, I’ve noticed that most real estate agents have no sort of plan whatsoever. However, the successful ones do. Having a plan on how many blogs you’re going to write, how many postcards you’ll send out, or how you’ll attain leads are all ways to ensure a successful plan.

“Clarity helps you know exactly what goals you want to achieve, and creating a business plan is the best way to achieve your goals.”

Including a clear vision statement of what you want by the end of 2019 will help set the course you need to follow. Let’s say you want to close 100 transactions next year—how will you achieve this? You’ll break down how many listings you’ll need to take each month, how many buyer presentations you’ll need to go on, etc. I have some powerful tools that can help crunch the numbers on how much business you need to attract to meet your goals.

All agents are different; some like working with expired listings, some use direct mail, some use open houses, and so on. I’d be more than happy to help you create a customized plan that focuses on what you like to do—just reach out to me. Together we can create a path for you to follow in the new year.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/How+to+Create+a+Business+Plan+for+2019.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/How+to+Create+a+Business+Plan+for+2019.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Creating a business plan will ensure you meet your goals. Here’s how.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Creating a business plan will ensure you meet your goals. Here’s how.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Meet Your Goals by Using the Success Cycle</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-to-meet-your-goals-by-using-the-success-cycle.html</link>
        
          <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
          <category>Lead Conversion</category>
        
          <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-11 15:31:46 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+Success+Cycle.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Following the success cycle can help you accomplish the big goals you’ve set for 2019.

I recently attended a Tony Robbins event, and one of the powerful topics he covered was the success cycle. To help you find more success in your own real estate endeavors, I’ll be sharing Tony’s success cycle with you today.

The success cycle is made up of four parts: potential, action, results, and belief/certainty.

Each one of us has the potential to do anything we set our mind to. Let’s use an example goal of completing 100 transactions in 2019. Our actions will determine how we close these transactions. 

As we do this, we need to track our results. For example, we need to know what our conversion ratio is when we meet with a seller. If you go on 10 listing appointments and gain a client through five, you have a 50% conversion ratio. Once you have this ratio, you can figure out how many listing appointments you’ll need to go on to achieve your goal of 100 transactions in 2019.

You may have taken action, but if you don’t have the belief or certainty in what you’re trying to achieve, it will be difficult to get things done. 

I’d like to share a story with you about belief and certainty. Many years ago, I went to a CRS conference where some attendees wore a color-coded dot on their badge. This dot meant they had done 100 transactions that year, and most people wearing these dots were speaking about their success on stage. I had never heard of anybody doing 100 transactions in a year, but once I learned how it could be done, I was certain I could do it. At this same conference the next year, I was able to wear the coveted dot on my badge.

“If you don’t have the belief or certainty in what you’re trying to achieve, it will be difficult to get things done.”

If you want to achieve greater things in 2019, reach out to me and we can figure out a plan that works for you. I’d be more than happy to coach you throughout the year and help you hit each goal you set. In the meantime, let me know if you have any questions or need more information. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+Success+Cycle.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+Success+Cycle.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Following the success cycle can help you accomplish the big goals you’ve set for 2019.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Following the success cycle can help you accomplish the big goals you’ve set for 2019.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Doing the Right Thing Is a Must for Realtors</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/why-doing-the-right-thing-is-a-must-for-realtors.html</link>
        
          <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-15 11:14:29 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+doing+the+right+thing+11.19.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are you following your ethical responsibility as a Realtor to do the right thing? Today, we’ll discuss why this is important and what it entails.

Over the past few months, ethical concerns have been top-of-mind for Phoenix buyers, sellers, and homeowners. As a Realtor myself, I have noticed the rise of a few problematic trends within the industry. 

First, there’s the matter of how showings are conducted. There is a set of instructions real estate professionals are supposed to follow when showing properties. Lately, many Realtors are ignoring these guidelines. This must change. Following the showing instructions will improve the process for everyone involved. Ignoring these guidelines, meanwhile, can engender feelings of ill will. Remember: You aren’t the only person who your actions affect. 

If you were to cancel a showing or show up late without giving the seller notice, for example, imagine how disheartening this might be for them. Treating everyone’s time as being as valuable as your own is simply the right thing to do. 

In addition to this problem, there’s also the issue of showing agents not providing sellers with feedback. Oftentimes, the seller of a property will ask that showing agents tell them what they thought by filling out a short questionnaire. This questionnaire is usually sent via email, and it’s generally very easy to complete. Taking the few moments required to provide this feedback is the least we as Realtors can do.

“Each choice you make will shape the way our industry is viewed as a whole.”

Also, make sure this feedback isn’t too generic. Saying that the “buyer didn’t like the house” with no additional reason or context isn’t good feedback at all. 

When making decisions as an agent, put yourself in the seller’s shoes. As professionals, we must never disregard their time, needs, and feelings. Each choice you make will shape the way our industry is viewed as a whole.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+doing+the+right+thing+11.19.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+doing+the+right+thing+11.19.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are you following your ethical responsibility as a Realtor to do the right thing? Today, we’ll discuss why this is important and what it entails.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are you following your ethical responsibility as a Realtor to do the right thing? Today, we’ll discuss why this is important and what it entails.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Nate Martinez's Journey Through Real Estate</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/nate-martinezs-journey-through-real-estate.html</link>
        
          <category>Reviews and Referral System</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-13 14:38:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+Nate+Martinez%2527s+Journey+Through+Real+Estate.mp4</guid>
        <description>
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+Nate+Martinez%2527s+Journey+Through+Real+Estate.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+Nate+Martinez%2527s+Journey+Through+Real+Estate.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Simple Concept That Can Transform Your Real Estate Business</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/a-simple-concept-that-can-transform-your-real-estate-business.html</link>
        
          <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-26 11:40:49 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+321+11.6.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What if I told you that you could increase your business just by remembering “3, 2, 1?” Here’s what I mean.

I’ve got a great tip for all of you agents out there today. It’s a simple way to communicate with 1,250 people over the next 12 months. 

If you were to talk with 1,250 people in the next year, do you think your business would be better than it is now? It definitely would. Here’s how the “3, 2, 1” method works.

First, focus on calling three past clients or other people from your SOI every day and have a conversation with them. If you do this each day, Monday through Friday, that would equal 750 contacts over the course of the year. 

Next, focus on prospecting each day until you find two possible leads you can add to your SOI. That’s another 500 contacts over the course of the year.

If you were able to close just 1% of those contacts, that’s an additional 12.5 transactions per year. 

“Calling three people per day will result in an additional 1,250 touches per year.”

Finally, you need to take some time out of each week to learn one new thing. Whether it’s a lesson from a webinar, a book, or a conference, learning something new every week will give you 52 new pieces of knowledge each year. If you can work in one referral per day to someone in your SOI, that is a huge bonus.

I hope you use this method to increase your business and have more success in the coming year. If you have any questions about the “3, 2, 1” method or anything else related to the real estate business, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+321+11.6.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+321+11.6.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What if I told you that you could increase your business just by remembering “3, 2, 1?”. Here’s what I mean.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What if I told you that you could increase your business just by remembering “3, 2, 1?”. Here’s what I mean.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Truth About Whether Our Market Is Headed for a Crash</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/the-truth-about-whether-our-market-is-headed-for-a-crash.html</link>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-15 15:16:52 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+market+crash+10.8+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are we headed for a crash? Let’s discuss this crucial question.

Recently, a lot of people have been asking us whether the market is going to crash. 

In our local Phoenix area, the economy and the new construction market are booming. This is very similar to what we saw before the last market crash, but this doesn’t necessarily mean history will repeat itself. 

During the last crash, a lot of investors were entering our market with the intention of riding out potential appreciation. Today, though, the prospect of appreciation isn’t the primary driving force behind most home purchases. This fact alone highlights the stark contrast between our market now and what we saw years ago. 

The bottom line is this: We may experience a correction within the next year or two, but today’s market conditions are a far cry from what was the case during the last crash. 

“We may experience a correction within the next year or two, but today’s market conditions are a far cry from what was the case during the last crash.”

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+market+crash+10.8+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+market+crash+10.8+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are we headed for a crash? Let’s discuss this crucial question.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are we headed for a crash? Let’s discuss this crucial question.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Buyers & Sellers Should Know About Earnest Money</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/what-buyers-sellers-should-know-about-earnest-money.html</link>
        
          <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-02 14:54:24 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Buyers+%2526+Sellers+Should+Know+About+Earnest+Money.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What role the earnest money deposit plays in a real estate transaction impacts buyers and sellers in different ways.

In a real estate transaction, earnest money is a dollar amount that buyers put down as a deposit to show the seller that they’re sincere. What should buyers and sellers know specifically about this earnest money deposit, though?

If you’re a buyer, I recommend an earnest money deposit of at least 1% of your total offer—maybe even 2% if you’re in a multiple offer situation. For example, if your offer is $500,000, your earnest money deposit should be $5,000 (or perhaps $10,000). Your earnest money deposit is protected by the purchase contract we have here in Arizona, and there are many ways you can get it back if the deal falls through as long as you’re bargaining in good faith.

“I recommend an earnest money deposit of at least 1% of your total offer.”

If you’re a seller, you want to get as much earnest money back as possible because you’re the one who’s liable in this situation. If your house is off the market for two months and the buyer doesn’t qualify at the last minute, you’ll have to relinquish that money—you won’t be able to reclaim it.

However, if the buyer gets to close of escrow, they’re completely funded, and they meet all other contingencies, but for whatever reason they just decided not to close, then you’d be completely refunded for having your house off the market for that long.

If you have any other questions about the earnest money deposit, real estate contracts, or the home buying process in general, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Buyers+%2526+Sellers+Should+Know+About+Earnest+Money.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+Buyers+%2526+Sellers+Should+Know+About+Earnest+Money.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What role the earnest money deposit plays in a real estate transaction impacts buyers and sellers in different ways.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What role the earnest money deposit plays in a real estate transaction impacts buyers and sellers in different ways.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Interest Rates Will Affect Your Clients</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-interest-rates-will-affect-your-clients.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Presentations</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-07 11:53:09 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+interest+rates+9.26+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Interest rates are predicted to continue rising. Today I want to take a look at what it means for your clients.

Today I want to take a minute to talk about a common topic in the real estate industry: interest rate predictions.

Jamie Dimon, the CEO of JPMorgan Chase, predicts that the yield on the 10-year Treasury bond will go up 5% in the next 24 to 36 months. Typically the spread between the 10-year Treasury bond and a 30-year mortgage is about a 1.75% yield. The yield as of August 7 for a 30-year mortgage is 4.75% with a spread of 1.77%. If the yield goes to 5% then the 30-year mortgage rates rise to 6.75%

With these interest rate changes, your clients’ buying power will of course be affected. For example, if they were to buy a home for $290,000 with 5% down, their payment would be $1,437. However, if they wait until the interest rate increases to 6.75%, that same loan would give them a payment of $1,786 per month. This $349 increase in interest paid per month is nearly $4,200 per year and $125,000 over the life of the loan.

“Now is the time to encourage your buyers and sellers to jump into the market before it is too late.”

Since we believe that the interest rates are going to increase, now is the time to encourage your buyers and sellers to jump into the market before it is too late.

If you have any questions, please feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to speaking with you soon.

This communication is provided to you for informational purposes only and should not be relied upon by you. Nate Martinez nor RE/MAX Professionals are not mortgage lenders and so you should contact a qualified mortgage broker directly to learn more about its mortgage products and your eligibility for such products.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+interest+rates+9.26+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+interest+rates+9.26+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Interest rates are predicted to continue rising. Today I want to take a look at what it means for your clients.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Interest rates are predicted to continue rising. Today I want to take a look at what it means for your clients.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Agents: It's Time to Find out What's Happening in Our Market</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/agents-its-time-to-find-out-whats-happening-in-our-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Presentations</category>
        
          <category>Listing Presentations</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-24 16:37:36 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+market+update+8.29+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

What’s going on right now in our Phoenix area real estate market? Let’s examine the latest numbers and find out.

The latest numbers for our Phoenix metro real estate market are in, so let’s review them today. 

As of July, there were only 15,754 active listings in our residential market. This constitutes an 11.1% year-over-year decrease. Meanwhile, the number of pending listings also dropped—undergoing a 3.4% decrease from last year. 

Monthly median sales prices, though, have risen 9.4% since July of 2017, for a current median sale price of $267,990. 

In the new construction market, activity is booming. Yet with so few homes being built in the $200,000 and under price range, both resale and new construction homes within this bracket are seeing rapid appreciation. 

The market right now is very strong here in our Phoenix area, and it will likely continue to be so. With all of this in mind, you may be wondering what these conditions mean for those looking to buy or sell.

“The market right now is very strong here in our Phoenix area, and it will likely continue to be so.”

For sellers, it’s important to keep a pulse on how seasonal market trends may impact your goals. Conditions tend to lag slightly as we head into the fourth quarter, so being mindful of this change and strategizing your sale accordingly will be crucial to your success. 

For a buyer, it’s important to realize that interest rates are set to rise. That said, those thinking of buying should seize the opportunity to buy now while conditions are still favorable. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+market+update+8.29+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+market+update+8.29+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What’s going on right now in our Phoenix area real estate market? Let’s examine the latest numbers and find out.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What’s going on right now in our Phoenix area real estate market? Let’s examine the latest numbers and find out.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Realtors Must Know About Zillow’s Instant Offer Program</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/what-realtors-must-know-about-zillows-instant-offer-program.html</link>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-22 08:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+zillow+(2).mp4</guid>
        <description>

What does Zillow&rsquo;s new Instant Offer program mean for Realtors? Today I will discuss how this change may impact you.

&nbsp;

Zillow has undergone some changes recently, so today I would like to talk about what is new with the site. If you visit Zillow’s website right now, you’ll probably notice that Realtors have been removed from every listing on the site. Now, instead of the name of an agent, the site is advertising their new Instant Offer program.

This program shows what Zillow will pay a homeowner for their property. Before, Zillow gave homeowners the opportunity to reach out to agents directly. Now, they are moving past that. This isn’t to say Zillow may not sell leads back to Realtors, but for now, the Instant Offer program has taken the place of agents on the site.

So, how is this affecting today’s Realtors? For one thing, it means that people who advertise heavily through Zillow, myself included, will no longer have the option to do so.

However, it is actually investors who will be most affected by this change. This is because Zillow will be getting the first crack at properties investors may have previously been the first to capture.

I also believe that this change will place Zillow in more direct competition with other platforms like Opendoor and OfferPad.

“Zillow will be getting the first crack at properties investors may have previously been the first to capture.”

It is important for Realtors to be aware of this change and how it may affect them. Staying informed is a critical aspect of any agent’s career. If you are concerned about this change, my recommendation is to focus on your past client database. Build deeper connections with people you have already formed relationships with.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+zillow+(2).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/2018/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+zillow+(2).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What does Zillow’s new Instant Offer program mean for Realtors? Today I will discuss how this change may impact you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What does Zillow’s new Instant Offer program mean for Realtors? Today I will discuss how this change may impact you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How’s the Phoenix Market Doing Right Now?</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/hows-the-phoenix-market-doing-right-now.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Presentations</category>
        
          <category>Listing Presentations</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2018-04-29 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+Latest+Phoenix+Real+Estate+Numbers+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Phoenix real estate is doing extremely well right now. Here’s what the latest numbers are telling us.

&nbsp;

The latest numbers are in and I’m excited to share them with you today. Let’s get right to it.

In March of this year, 9,402 homes closed escrow. In January, we only had 6,000 closed sales, which is still a strong number. This is one of the strongest first quarters we’ve seen in a while.

The market is up 36%, but inventory has dropped almost 12% at the same time. There are currently 21,703 homes active on the MLS today. The average list price is up 8.8% to $381,000 and the average sale price is up 9.5% to $316,400.

One of the most fascinating things I found was when looking at this year’s numbers compared to the numbers from the past 18 years. Back in 2001, the average price in the valley was $175,900. In 2007, the market roared to a peak of $345,900 before crashing and bottoming out in 2009 at $159,080. We’ve made a significant rebound since. Today, the average price is $316,365.

People who bought at the peak are close to being back where they were. People who bought 17 years ago have more than doubled their money, as have the people who bought at the bottom of the market.

“People who bought at the peak are seeing values rise back to where they were before.”

As an added note, I’ve seen more cranes in the sky in the Phoenix than I have in the last 10 years. High-rises, hotels, and more are being built all around the Valley, which is great news for our economy and ultimately, our market.

I hope your market is doing well. If you have any questions for me at all about the latest numbers or about the business in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+Latest+Phoenix+Real+Estate+Numbers+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+Latest+Phoenix+Real+Estate+Numbers+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Phoenix real estate is doing extremely well right now. Here’s what the latest numbers are telling us.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Phoenix real estate is doing extremely well right now. Here’s what the latest numbers are telling us.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Phoenix Real Estate Market Is Hot</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/the-phoenix-real-estate-market-is-hot.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Presentations</category>
        
          <category>Listing Presentations</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-30 10:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent+Phoenix%E2%80%99s+red-hot+market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What&rsquo;s going on in the Phoenix real estate market? Here&rsquo;s what you need to know.

&nbsp;

Let’s talk about the hot, robust real estate market in Phoenix.

Last month alone, almost 17% of all homes that closed did so above list price. When it comes to buyers making offers on houses, you’ve got to make sure that you’re writing your offers very aggressively.

Only 3% of the upper-end homes actually got any type of seller concessions. When you get below $250,000, that’s still a pretty high percentage of sellers that will offer concessions. In that same price point, homes are selling way above list price as well.

We’ve experienced multiple offers on almost every home listed above $250,000. In preparing an offer, you want to come in with a higher earnest money deposit, short inspection time, few contingencies, and don’t ask for concessions.

“In this market, you need to come forward with your highest and best offer.”

When you’re representing the seller in today’s market, make sure that you’re studying the different buyers and talking to their lenders so that you can select the absolute best buyer possible. Again, in a hot market like today’s, when houses are selling above list price, you need to come forward with your highest and best offer.

Houses aren’t staying on the market very long. In fact, we have less than three months of inventory available, which is almost 18% lower than this time last year.

If you have any questions, please feel free to reach out to me. If there is a topic you’d like me to discuss in a future video, send them my way; if I select yours, I’ll send you a $50 gift card to a restaurant of your choice.

I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent+Phoenix%E2%80%99s+red-hot+market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent+Phoenix%E2%80%99s+red-hot+market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What’s going on in the Phoenix real estate market? Here’s what you need to know.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What’s going on in the Phoenix real estate market? Here’s what you need to know.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Level Up Your Real Estate Business</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-to-level-up-your-real-estate-business.html</link>
        
          <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
          <category>Lead Conversion</category>
        
          <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-16 15:19:14 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Level+Up+Your+Real+Estate+Business.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m joined by Sarah Michelle Bliss, who has been by my side for the last 20 years of my real estate career. She’s a great success coach, author, and real estate trainer. We’ve put together a great class on Thursday, July 26th from 3:00 p.m. to 6:00 p.m. that we want to tell you about.

It’s called “10 Ways to Level Up Your Real Estate Business” and we will be walking you through a ton of information to help you become more proficient and get the most out of the hours that you are working.

The class is around three hours long, but it’s filled with content that will help you be more present at work and have more time off to enjoy life.

“We can’t wait for you to join us.”

As a bonus for being there, we’re also going to be giving you a copy of our 2018 business plan. It’s a complete business plan that takes you all the way through the steps it takes to build a successful real estate company.

Two of the buzzwords we use in our complete agent development are proactive and intentional. That’s where most agents struggle. They aren’t being consistent and proactive and completing the necessary activities to generate the results you want.

Space is limited so make sure you get signed up soon. You can register here.

If you have any questions about the class or the real estate business in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Level+Up+Your+Real+Estate+Business.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+to+Level+Up+Your+Real+Estate+Business.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I’m excited for you to hear about our upcoming real estate business class. Here’s how we’re going to help agents take their careers to the next level.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I’m excited for you to hear about our upcoming real estate business class. Here’s how we’re going to help agents take their careers to the next level.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Beat the Competition in This Scorching Hot Market?</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-can-you-beat-the-competition-in-this-scorching-hot-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Listing Presentations</category>
        
          <category>Buyer Presentations</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-19 14:36:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Can+You+Beat+the+Competition+in+this+Scorching+Hot+Market%253F+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today, I have some advice on how you can handle multiple offer situations.

The Phoenix real estate market is absolutely on fire, and December 2017 was one of the busiest months of my career. Now that we’re in January of 2018, we’re getting multiple offers on just about every property that we place on the market. This affects the buyers possibly even more than the sellers.

“An escalation clause is a technique that may be necessary to get the house you want in this hot market.”

If you’re a buyer or representing a buyer in today’s marketplace, an escalation clause will help you beat out the current highest offer by offering a certain amount more. Essentially, it is a clause in the contract that says that the buyer is willing to pay X amount more than the highest offer received by the seller.  For example, let’s say you’re making an offer on a house priced at $400,000. You can put in an escalation clause that says you’ll outbid any other buyer by, say, $1,000. This might be a technique that is necessary to get the house that you want.

Inventory is still very low in the valley, but the demand is very high, so hopefully an escalation clause will help give you the edge you need to get the home of your dreams.

If you have any other questions about escalation clauses or you’re thinking about buying or selling a home in our market, give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Can+You+Beat+the+Competition+in+this+Scorching+Hot+Market%253F+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Can+You+Beat+the+Competition+in+this+Scorching+Hot+Market%253F+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How can you win in a multiple offer situation in this red-hot seller’s market? I have an idea that could help you succeed.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How can you win in a multiple offer situation in this red-hot seller’s market? I have an idea that could help you succeed.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Valuable Presentation on Building Wealth in Your Life</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/a-valuable-presentation-on-building-wealth-in-your-life.html</link>
        
          <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
          <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
          <category>Reviews and Referral System</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-30 09:57:55 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Valuable+Presentation+on+Building+Wealth+in+Your+Life+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

As you may remember, I did a video a couple of months ago on the book “Wealth Can’t Wait” by David Osborn and Paul Morris.

Around that same time, I had the pleasure of flying David in to give an hour-long talk on his book and how to build wealth. The information he shared was truly valuable and is sure to help you build wealth in your life.

“In his talk, David provides a lot of insight into how to build wealth.”

The next time you have an hour of free time, I’d like you to sit down and watch David’s presentation. You can find the video from that seminar here.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Valuable+Presentation+on+Building+Wealth+in+Your+Life+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Valley+of+the+Sun+Real+Estate+Agent-+A+Valuable+Presentation+on+Building+Wealth+in+Your+Life+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I’ve got a special opportunity to share with you today. If you weren’t able to see David Osborn’s presentation a few months ago on how to build wealth in your life, now is your chance.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I’ve got a special opportunity to share with you today. If you weren’t able to see David Osborn’s presentation a few months ago on how to build wealth in your life, now is your chance.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What You Need to Know About Radon Gas</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/what-you-need-to-know-about-radon-gas.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Presentations</category>
        
          <category>Listing Presentations</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-18 07:27:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+You+Need+to+Know+About+Radon+Gas.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Over the last couple of months, I’ve heard the word “radon” too many times.

It’s interesting because whenever I talk to other real estate professionals, I ask them how many of the homes they’ve dealt with have had radon in them, and they always say, “None.”

Some buyers from the East Coast have some knowledge about radon, as do a few homeowners.

Radon came to my attention when I was representing a buyer during a transaction on a house in Scottsdale. This house had fallen out of escrow because the radon test came back two points higher than the national standard of 4%.

“If the house has a basement or underground air units, order a radon test.”

Radon is an odorless, poisonous gas that can cause lung cancer over long periods of exposure. As I’ve learned more about radon, I’ve found that the reason most people don’t find it in our area is that hardly anyone looks for it.

I was always taught that radon tests are necessary in mountainous regions because radon comes from granite in the ground. However, this Scottsdale house was on a flat piece of dirt and ended up having a high radon content.

We made the offer contingent on the seller getting radon levels down. At first, the seller paid $5,000 to fix the problem. The radon levels did not go down. The seller then spent another $5,000. After all the work they did and money they spent, the radon levels actually went higher, which was no good, and the buyer walked away.

I just want to make sure that people are aware that radon is out there. If you are buying a home, ask for a radon test. They only cost $300 to $350. If the house has a basement or underground air units, then you definitely need to order a radon test.

If you have any other questions about radon or buying a home, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+You+Need+to+Know+About+Radon+Gas.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+What+You+Need+to+Know+About+Radon+Gas.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Why should you order a radon test when buying a home? I’ll go over a few reasons today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Why should you order a radon test when buying a home? I’ll go over a few reasons today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>14 Activities Every Real Estate Agent Should Master: Part Two</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/14-activities-every-real-estate-agent-should-master-part-two.html</link>
        
          <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
          <category>Lead Conversion</category>
        
          <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-28 07:45:55 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+14+Activities+Every+Real+Estate+Agent+Should+Master-+Part+Two.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are 14 vital activities that every real estate agent should do. Last time, we focused on the seven things you need to do to help sellers. Today, we’ll focus on what you need to do to master representing buyers.

1. Lead generation. Again, you need to be constantly generating new leads through open houses, Zillow, yard signs, and referrals from past clients, family, and friends.

2. Have a conversion process. What do you do to convert this person from a name and number into a buyer and broker contract?

3. Paperwork. Get that agreement signed and take care of agency disclosures and buyer advisories while you are in the beginning stages of working with the buyer.   

4. Finding and showing the perfect home. This is the fun part. You get to guide the buyer through their home search.

“You need to be able to write an offer that will get accepted.”

5. Writing and negotiating the best purchase agreement. You need to be proficient in making sure that your offers protect the buyer’s best interests. You also need to make sure that the buyer understands all of the inspections and finance contingencies. The bottom line is that you need to be able to write an offer that will be accepted.

6. Closing. Again, it’s important to make sure that the closing process goes smoothly. Be there with your buyer at the closing table in case they have any questions or concerns. You are there to be their advocate. Let them know that you care by showing up to closing. Then, when everything has been done, you can ask if there is anyone they can refer you to.

7. Post-closing activities. In my 31 years of real estate, I’ve noticed that this step gets skipped the most. What are you doing to develop a deep relationship with this client after you close escrow? After all, they may be a client who will bring you business for the rest of your life.

You need to have detailed plans in place to make sure that you are relevant in their mind. Call them up every now and then, invite them to sporting events, or host annual client appreciation events. You can also check to see how they like the house. If they have any challenges or need a repairman, you can put them in touch with one. You will position yourself as a great real estate resource.

I hope these 14 activities will help you grow your business. If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+14+Activities+Every+Real+Estate+Agent+Should+Master-+Part+Two.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+14+Activities+Every+Real+Estate+Agent+Should+Master-+Part+Two.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I’m back with the last seven activities that every real estate agent needs to do. The first seven focused on listings, so today, we’ll focus on homebuyers.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I’m back with the last seven activities that every real estate agent needs to do. The first seven focused on listings, so today, we’ll focus on homebuyers.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Skip These 14 Activities Every Real Estate Agent Should Master</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/dont-skip-these-14-activities-every-real-estate-agent-should-master.html</link>
        
          <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
          <category>Buyer Presentations</category>
        
          <category>Listing Presentations</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-10 06:08:55 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+Dont+Skip+These+14+Activities+Every+Real+Estate+Agent+Should+Master.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are 14 vital activities that each Realtor should do. I’ll go over the first seven for you today.

1. Lead generation. It’s so important to constantly generate leads.

2. Converting leads. Turn those leads into appointments and then into contracts.

3. Administrative work. Most Realtors don’t like paperwork, which is why we have transaction coordinators to help us out. Administrative paperwork is a vital activity that we must do ourselves or delegate to others.

4. Have good presentation. It’s important to present at listing appointments, in front of buyers, and in the negotiation of contracts. Whether you are representing the buyer or seller, you have to be able to negotiate on their behalf.

5. Marketing. You need to have a strategic marketing plan in place. Whether you are trying to connect with people through farming, Zillow, or wherever it may be that you are spending money to generate leads, marketing is a highly important function of being a Realtor.

“There are many components that you need to master, but the closing component is extremely important.”

6. Closing. All of your hard work goes into the closing day. You want to make sure that you are able to get the closing done right. There are many components that you need to master, but the closing component is extremely important. Make sure you go to closings so that you can represent your client. By going to the closing, you will also be present in your client’s mindset and they will be more likely to send your information to their friends and family.

7. Post-closing activities. What do you do once the house is closed? Do you just cash the check and never talk to those people again? Or do you want these people to become part of the fabric of your life? It’s very important to have an ongoing follow-up plan for everyone you represent.

After all, if you had a good transaction, then they know, like, and trust you. They also know what to expect by working with you. Now it’s up to you to stay in constant contact with them. If they need help with the house, finding contractors, or dealing with home warranty issues, you should be their advocate. Invite them to dinner, call on them cordially after closing, or invite them to client events.

Stay tuned for the next seven tasks that every real estate agent should do. In the meantime, if you have any questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+Dont+Skip+These+14+Activities+Every+Real+Estate+Agent+Should+Master.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+Dont+Skip+These+14+Activities+Every+Real+Estate+Agent+Should+Master.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Every real estate agent needs to do 14 activities in order to be successful. I’ll cover the first seven for you today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Every real estate agent needs to do 14 activities in order to be successful. I’ll cover the first seven for you today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>We Want to Teach You How to Build Your Wealth</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/we-want-to-teach-you-how-to-build-your.html</link>
        
          <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
          <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
          <category>Reviews and Referral System</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-20 12:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+We+Want+to+Teach+You+How+to+Build+Your+Wealth.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are you a real estate agent who wants to build wealth? I want to let you know that you’re invited to our next training session, where you’ll learn how to do exactly that.

Join RE/MAX Professionals

Are you a real estate agent who wants to build wealth? I want to let you know that you’re invited to our next training session, where you’ll learn how to do exactly that. You’ll learn how to embrace the habits and mindsets of the wealthy.

You’ll also learn the seven pillars of wealth-building from none other than the guy who wrote the book—literally. We’re flying in “Wealth Can’t Wait” author David Osborn. We’re going to give away all of our strategies and systems so you can build a profitable business.

When the event is over, you’ll leave with not only the knowledge to build wealth, but also a copy of David’s book.

“We’re giving away all of our strategies and systems so you can build a profitable business.”

However, space is limited so only the first 200 in attendance will receive this free copy. To RSVP for this free event, click here.

But there is one catch after you register: you have to show up.

We hope to see you there on Thursday, November 2nd starting at 8:30 a.m.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+We+Want+to+Teach+You+How+to+Build+Your+Wealth.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+We+Want+to+Teach+You+How+to+Build+Your+Wealth.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Are you a real estate agent who wants to build wealth? I want to let you know that you’re invited to our next training session, where you’ll learn how to do exactly that.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Are you a real estate agent who wants to build wealth? I want to let you know that you’re invited to our next training session, where you’ll learn how to do exactly that.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Did You Sell Any of the 14,904 Homes Yesterday?</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/did-you-sell-any-of-14904-homes.html</link>
        
          <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
          <category>Reviews and Referral System</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-26 10:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/+Videos/2017/September/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+Did+You+Sell+Any+of+the+14%252C904+Homes+Yesterday%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Only a small percentage of agents make the most sales. Our team is part of that small percentage.

Join RE/MAX Professionals

Did you know that 14,904 homes sold yesterday alone? That’s straight from the National Association of Realtors.

In the Phoenix area, there are about 88,000 home sales per year. That breaks down to 7,400 each month and 275 each day. With over 35,000 Realtors in the Valley of the Sun, there are at least 26,000 Realtors who didn’t even sell a home last month.

How does this happen? As you may or may not know, a lot of licensed agents around here only work in real estate part-time. At Re/MAX Professionals, we focus on real estate as a full-time career. This is one of the reasons why our agents are able to sell 24 homes per year on average, the highest average in the Valley.

“There are at least 26,000 realtors who don’t sell a home each month.”

We train well, we pay well, and we support well. We have several events coming up soon. For one, we offer two real estate classes, called Momentum, each week. Momentum is all about mastering the basics. To learn more about Momentum, click here.



Also, I wan to remind you that I’m bringing in David Osborn, one of the authors of “Wealth Can’t Wait” on November 2nd. You’ll learn a lot and walk away with a free hardcover copy of David’s book. Learn more about the event here.



If you have any other questions for us in the meantime, don’t hesitate to reach out and give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/+Videos/2017/September/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+Did+You+Sell+Any+of+the+14%252C904+Homes+Yesterday%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/+Videos/2017/September/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+Did+You+Sell+Any+of+the+14%252C904+Homes+Yesterday%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Only a small percentage of agents make the most sales. Our team is part of that small percentage.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Only a small percentage of agents make the most sales. Our team is part of that small percentage.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Recent Trends in Hispanic Homeownership</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/recent-trends-in-hispanic-homeownership.html</link>
        
          <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-11 15:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/+Videos/2017/September/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+Recent+Trends+in+Hispanic+Homeownership.mp4</guid>
        <description>

It’s pretty amazing to see some of the home buying numbers in the Hispanic community. Here are a few that stick out to us.

Join RE/MAX Professionals

The National Association of Hispanic Real Estate Professionals has recently published a report that I wanted to talk about today. There are a lot of interesting numbers in here that point to an upward trend in Hispanic homeownership that no other demographic is seeing. Here’s what’s been going on:

• In 2016, there were 7.3 million Hispanic homeowners in the U.S.

• Also in 2016, there were 209,000 new Hispanic homeowners.

• Hispanic people account for 60% of the U.S.’s overall growth in homeownership.

• Hispanic people will account for 52% of new homeownership between 2010 and 2030.

• From 2010 to 2015, Hispanics accounted for more than half the population growth in the U.S. according to the U.S. Census.

• Six out of 10 Hispanic homebuyers are millennials.

• The Hispanic purchasing power was $1.4 trillion in 2016—more than the entire country of Australia.

• Hispanic people account for 76.4% of labor growth.

In addition to these numbers, you can see a graph in the video above that shows the growth in owner-occupied units. You can see the Hispanic population of homeowners start to increase over the last decade or so now that growth has outpaced that of non-Hispanic homeowners.

Another graph in the video above shows the net homeownership change. It’s interesting to note that Hispanics had an additional 1.1 million homeownership changes from 2010 to 2016, while non-Hispanic homeownership changes went down by 2.2 million.

“Hispanic homeownership is at an all-time high.”

Some of these stats just absolutely blew me away. After reading into them more, it makes sense. As far as Hispanic attitudes toward homeownership are concerned, raising a family and wealth creation have proven to be the primary drivers. It appears that trend is likely to continue.

Before I go, I wanted to quickly remind you that I’m bringing in David Osborn, one of the authors of “Wealth Can’t Wait” on November 2nd. You’ll walk away with a free hardcover copy of David’s book. Learn more about the event here.



At RE/MAX Professionals, we have several events coming up, ourselves. For one, we offer two real estate classes, called Momentum, each week. Momentum is all about mastering the basics. To learn more about Momentum, click here.



If you have any questions about that or about real estate in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/+Videos/2017/September/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+Recent+Trends+in+Hispanic+Homeownership.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/+Videos/2017/September/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+Recent+Trends+in+Hispanic+Homeownership.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

It’s pretty amazing to see some of the home buying numbers in the Hispanic community. Here are a few that stick out to us.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

It’s pretty amazing to see some of the home buying numbers in the Hispanic community. Here are a few that stick out to us.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Master Your Craft?</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/how-can-you-master-your-craft.html</link>
        
          <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
          <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
          <category>Reviews and Referral System</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-22 13:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/+Videos/2017/August/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Can+You+Master+Your+Craft%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What does it take to master your craft? Today, I’ve got a few stories on this subject as well as a few opportunities you should know about that can help.

Join RE/MAX Professionals

Right now, my family and I are taking a trip up to Jackson Hole, Wyoming for the total solar eclipse. But today, I wanted to talk to you about something different—mastering your craft.

When it comes to mastering your craft, one story that comes to mind for me is that of my mentor: Howard Brinton. When it comes to becoming a surgeon, mastering your craft is an absolute necessity. Between college, med school, and practicing on cadavers, a lot of time and hard work goes into it.

But, there are many ways you can master your craft. When it comes to real estate, the 90 minutes it takes to get your license isn’t where the fine-tuning ends. In real estate, experience with real clients is the best way to master your craft.

In fact, experience is a great way to hone your skills in any endeavor. As a kid, Kurt Warner, who was just inducted into the NFL Hall of Fame, would practice every single day. He continued this through high school, college, and beyond. Even still, success doesn’t always come that simply.

Kurt was cut after being drafted by the Green Bay Packers. He didn’t make the team, but kept practicing anyway. After gaining even more experience through arena football and even playing in Europe, he was contacted by the St. Louis Rams. Then when he started playing with them, he took the team to the Super Bowl—and they won.

No matter what your passion is, it will take a lot of time to master it. As a real estate agent, you can master your craft by practicing scripts, listing presentations, and buyer presentations. If you want to be great at what you do, you’ve got to practice daily.

I want to help. If you’re looking to further yourself in your real estate career, I’d like to sit down with you and speak one-on-one about how you can master your craft.

For me, becoming skilled at what I do is something I’ve always strived for. As a child my hero was Bruce Lee. Seeing his statue was one of the reasons I took my recent trip to Hong Kong. Bruce Lee has been an inspiration to me, and many of the things he’s said still resonate with me, today. One quote of his in particular stands out: “I fear not the man who has practiced 10,000 kicks once, but I fear the man who has practiced one kick 10,000 times.”

“Experience with real clients is the best way to master your craft.”

This is true not just of martial arts, but of any skill. To become truly masterful over what you do, you must put in a lot of time. As a real estate professional, there are a lot of events out there designed to help you master your craft.

At RE/MAX Professionals, we have several events coming up, ourselves. For one, we offer two real estate classes, called Momentum, each week. Momentum is all about mastering the basics. To learn more about Momentum, click here.



We’re also excited to announce that we will be hosting a special guest speaker, David Osborn, on November 2nd, 2017. David is going to share his story with us. After college, he took a year off to backpack around the world. After coming back to help his mom with her real estate endeavors, David now owns one of the nation’s largest real estate firms.

Along with his story, David will also be speaking about his most recent book, “Wealth Can’t Wait.” On that note, we have exciting news. The first 200 people who sign up will receive a copy of David’s book on us. For more information about this event, click here. 



If you’ve got any questions you’d like me to answer, send it in. If we use your question in one of our videos, I’ll send you out a $50 gift certificate.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/+Videos/2017/August/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Can+You+Master+Your+Craft%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/+Videos/2017/August/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+How+Can+You+Master+Your+Craft%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

What does it take to master your craft? Today, I’ve got a few stories on this subject as well as a few opportunities you should know about that can help.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

What does it take to master your craft? Today, I’ve got a few stories on this subject as well as a few opportunities you should know about that can help.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Statistics About Real Estate in the Valley</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/statistics-about-real-estate-in-valley.html</link>
        
          <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
          <category>Lead Conversion</category>
        
          <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-12 14:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/+Videos/2017/July/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+Statistics+About+Real+Estate+in+the+Valley.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I have some interesting statistics about real estate agents in the Valley, and an opportunity for those Realtors who want to improve their numbers.

Join RE/MAX Professionals

There are almost 38,000 active licenses in the Valley today that are Realtors, plus additional non-Realtor licenses as well. There are over 4,200 real estate offices in the Valley.

One interesting statistic that stands out to me is that 15% of active agents have left the business after just one year. That’s about 5,700 agents who no longer have a license.

10% of agents, or about 3,800, are only in business for 24 to 36 months. After three years in the business, an additional 5% of the remaining agents leave. So once you’ve made it past four years in the business, you can expect to be doing pretty well.

“Once you’ve made it past four years, you can expect to be doing pretty well.”

Throughout 2016, the number of homes sold in the Valley was 88,713. Given the current number of agents that are active, that’s only 2.36 homes per agent! Our agents at RE/MAX Professionals sell 10 times that average. Some of our agents have sold over 100 homes in the last year.

So if you have any questions on how to become a better real estate agent, we offer free training to anyone interested. You don’t have to join our company, but we would love to see you come through. We’ve created a better business model that focuses on helping regular agents become legendary agents.

If you have any questions about our free training, please give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/+Videos/2017/July/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+Statistics+About+Real+Estate+in+the+Valley.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/+Videos/2017/July/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+Statistics+About+Real+Estate+in+the+Valley.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I have some interesting statistics about real estate agents in the Valley, and an opportunity for those Realtors who want to improve their numbers.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I have some interesting statistics about real estate agents in the Valley, and an opportunity for those Realtors who want to improve their numbers.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>7 Common Habits of Wealthy Individuals</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/7-common-habits-of-wealthy-individuals.html</link>
        
          <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
          <category>Transaction Management</category>
        
          <category>Reviews and Referral System</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-28 13:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Everyone’s life is a different journey. However, if you start forming these habits now, your journey will lead to wealth.

Join RE/MAX Professionals

Today’s topic is right out of the book “Wealth Can’t Wait” by David Osborn and Paul Morris. I know these gentlemen personally and was very excited to read their book. In it, I found a ton of helpful, useful information on creating wealth. One of the things that stuck out to me the most was the list of seven habits that create wealth.

1. Live by design. Think about how you want your life to be and create a plan to get there.

2. Make business decisions based on a solid foundation and solid fundamentals.

3. Stick with what you know and drill in deep. Our wealth should be built through our biggest competency.

4. Earn more by learning more. I probably go to more seminars than most Realtors, and I believe they have helped me immensely in my career. There’s always something new you can learn.

“My constant education has helped me immensely in my career.”

5. Break down your big goals into smaller ones and add accountability.

6. Spend less than you earn and invest the rest.

7. Let go of the small stuff. We need to think and act bigger than that.

This is just one of the many helpful passages I picked up by reading “Wealth Can’t Wait.” If you have any questions about the book, would like to discuss it further, or want to discuss your real estate career, give us a call or send us an email today. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Everyone’s life is a different journey. However, if you start forming these habits now, your journey will lead to wealth.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Everyone’s life is a different journey. However, if you start forming these habits now, your journey will lead to wealth.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Internet Companies That Are Interrupting the Market</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/3-internet-companies-that-are.html</link>
        
          <category>Lead Generation</category>
        
          <category>Lead Conversion</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-12 10:41:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Property acquisition companies have been around for a long time in our market, but we are just now starting to see more online-only companies. Today, I’ve listed three of the most popular.

Join RE/MAX Professionals

Today I wanted to talk to you about three companies based solely online that are interrupting our real estate market in the Phoenix metro area.

1. Open Door has been around for the last couple of years, and it’s a pretty fascinating company to say the least. I can tell you that they aren’t going away anytime soon. They have an extraordinary management team and are valued at $550 million. They have $110 million in cash equity to buy properties, and have in total $180 million to acquire properties and run this platform.

I’m currently representing a buyer who is looking to purchase a home through this site and it’s been an interesting experience. As far as I know, Phoenix was one of their first test markets, and they seem to be successful so far.

2. OfferPad is an online application that helps you sell your home quickly and efficiently. It was started by a local Realtor and a gentleman from Blackstone in 2005, and they have $260 million in debt acquisition money and $30 million in equity.

Due to one of the founder’s developed business models, this company is expanding to multiple cities at a faster rate than Open Door. They’ve captured a 2% market share in the Phoenix metro area.

3. Zillow is a well-known company that has seen a lot of controversy over their Zestimate feature. They also have an Instant Offer Program that is being tested in Las Vegas and Orlando. It’s set up for big investor pools to directly buy homes from homeowners.

“These companies have been around for a long time.”

There’s been some play to keep the agent involved in these transactions, but I’m sure that at some point those parties will work to find a way around paying a commission to the agent.

Both Open Door and OfferPad are buying houses and advertising their ease of use. They claim to take the pain out of selling your home, and their popularity speaks for itself. What’s interesting is that both those apps also charge a commission for acquisitions that sits between 6% and 10%, depending on the risk factor.

These types of companies have been around for a long time in the direct investor-to-homeowner market. We’ve seen their yellow signs at street lights that say “I’ll buy your house for cash,” or something similar. We’re just now seeing the online model move forward.

I’d love to have your opinion about these online real estate companies. Do you think they’re going to “Uber-ize” the market? Will there be less need for agents? Shoot me an email or leave a comment below with your thoughts.

If you have any other questions about this or any other real estate topics, give me a call. I’d be happy to help!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Property acquisition companies have been around for a long time in our market, but we are just now starting to see more online-only companies. Today, I’ve listed three of the most popular.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Property acquisition companies have been around for a long time in our market, but we are just now starting to see more online-only companies. Today, I’ve listed three of the most popular.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are You Practicing the Right Lead Response Strategies?</title>
        <link>https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com/are-you-practicing-right-lead-response.html</link>
        
          <category>Lead Conversion</category>
        
        <author>Nate Martinez</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-27 17:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+Prospecting+by+the+Numbers.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What are the best practices for prospecting? We’ve got a great study from MIT about this topic to share with you today.

Join RE/MAX Professionals

I’ve got some great information to share today that I recently came across. A study conducted by MIT and published in the Harvard Business Review examined a number of different factors relating to response times for lead management. They collected more than 15,000 Internet leads in a three-year period and reached out to more than 100,000 different people in order to find the best times for getting responses.

Although every day is a good day to make contact, the study found that you have the best odds of reaching someone on either a Wednesday or a Thursday. There was a 49% difference between calling on Thursday versus calling on Tuesday.

As for the best time to make contact, the best results were found within the 3:30 to 5:30 p.m. time period. The next best time to call would be between 8 p.m. and 9 a.m. The difference between calling at 1:00 p.m. versus calling at 4 p.m. is 164%.

“You have the best odds of converting leads within five minutes of capturing them.”

You’ve probably heard before that making contact with prospects is all about timeliness. In fact, you do have the greatest odds of converting leads within the first five minutes of capturing them. After that, the conversion percentage decreases by 10 times. You absolutely have to respond to these leads as soon as they come in. There is more than a 400% difference between responding within five minutes and responding within 10.

Another thing this study showed was that persistence is key. When making calls, the likelihood of conversion increases greatly after about the sixth call. Continuing to call and being persistent with your leads is another simple way to ensure the success of your real estate business.

If you have any other questions for me, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. If you’d just like to sit down and have a chat about your career, I’d be happy to help with that as well. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+Prospecting+by+the+Numbers.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="https://joinremaxprofessionalsaz.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Nate+Martinez/Recruiting/Phoenix+Real+Estate+Agent-+Prospecting+by+the+Numbers.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

What are the best practices for prospecting? We’ve got a great study from MIT about this topic to share with you today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Nate Martinez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

What are the best practices for prospecting? We’ve got a great study from MIT about this topic to share with you today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Valley of the Sun, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Nate Martinez</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Nate Martinez</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from RE/MAX Professionals - your professional Valley of the Sun Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
